<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ide on SeleniumHQ Browser Automation</title>
    <link>https://selenium.dev/tags/ide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ide on SeleniumHQ Browser Automation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://selenium.dev/tags/ide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Atoms have come to Selenium IDE</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/atoms-have-come-to-selenium-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/atoms-have-come-to-selenium-ide/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned in Simon&amp;#8217;s Going Atomic: Why? and Going Atomic: How, part of the merging of Selenium and WebDriver is to share common code between the two. And as of the 1.0.10 release of Selenium IDE, this merged code, &amp;#8216;atoms&amp;#8217; is now included.
Some early users of this release are noticing that this the atom that drives assertAttribute and verifyAttribute is causing their scripts to break. This post explains the &amp;#8216;why&amp;#8217; and suggests how to fix them as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.0 backend for running IDE test suite via the Se2 Firefox</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0-backend-for-running-ide-test-suite-via-the-se2-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0-backend-for-running-ide-test-suite-via-the-se2-firefox/</guid>
      <description>The GSoC 2010, it’s a great adventure.
I’m Raynatou, I come from Burkina and do my internship at SERLI. Like all interns in this company the topic of my internship focuses on advanced topics like the integration of WebDriver as backend for Selenium IDE. Selenium IDE is currently built upon Selenium Core for interacting with web pages. Selenium Core has several major limitations, including the inability to fire native events. To avoid these limitations and produce more robust tests, I am investigating Selenium IDE to using WebDriver in place of Selenium Core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium-IDE – Looking back and looking forward</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-looking-back-and-looking-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-looking-back-and-looking-forward/</guid>
      <description>Its been around six months and three releases since I took the reins of Selenium-IDE. The fundamental change in that time has been the adoption of a plugin model like the fine folks over that Firebug. (We&amp;#8217;re also self-hosting it which is big from a project internals perspective.)
Right now, you can add custom user-extensions and formatters, but in the very near future you will be able to add location strategies as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium IDE 1.0.7 – Now with Drag-and-Drop!</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-1-0-7-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-1-0-7-released/</guid>
      <description>So its a month later than planned, but Selenium IDE 1.0.7 is now available. The delay was due to some internal build changes and not code, but one of the code changes that is there more than makes up for the delay.
That&amp;#8217;s right, drag-and-drop has finally arrived to Se-IDE &amp;#8212; though credit lies with Jérémy Hérault for implementing it.
Oh, and if you are Swedish, there is now a localization for you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>