<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Selenium – workshops</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/tags/workshops/</link><description>Recent content in workshops on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/tags/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Let's meet at SeleniumConf, Once Again!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/lets-meet-in-person-at-seleniumconf-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/lets-meet-in-person-at-seleniumconf-2023/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This year is special, thanks to the decision to host an in-person conference after a long hiatus and several years of
virtual-only events. We&amp;rsquo;ve gone out of our way to reflect this feeling at the conference. We have engrossing keynotes,
well-researched talks, hands-on pre-conference workshops, hallway tracks, and whatnot!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="heres-a-quick-list-of-what-to-expect">Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list of what to expect!&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="whats-cooking-in-keynotes">What&amp;rsquo;s cooking in Keynotes?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have Diego Molina kicking things off with
&amp;lsquo;&lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#selenium-state-of-the-union">Selenium: State of the Union&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo; where he will talk about
all things Selenium, including the project, the code, and the community. Think of it as a journey through the times with
Selenium. A must-attend without any shred of doubt!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next up is Erika Chestnut&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#bigger-than-the-box">Bigger Than The Box&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo; where she
will focus on the idea of quality and whether it has been restricted to only a single step in the delivery process.
It is indeed a dialogue that needs to happen given that our lives revolve around quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On day 2, we have first-time SeleniumConf keynote speaker Mark Winteringham from the Ministry of Testing talking about
&amp;lsquo;&lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#what-exactly-do-you-do-in-test-automation">What Exactly Do You Do in Test Automation?&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;
Is it just about coding and frameworks or is there more to it? How should a test automation practitioner think about
their role? Think of this as learning from the ground up or in some cases, back to the basics!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="talks-talks-and-more-talks">Talks, talks, and more talks&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve cast our net far and wide this time around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just as a highlight, across the two days, we will cover a diverse range of topics from crawlers, identifying code
smells, blended testing, component testing, quality gates, quality metrics to track, testing with real robots, and
managing the test data nightmare, among others. Quite a list, huh? Trust me, this is just a sneak peek. You can check
out the entire list &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, we&amp;rsquo;ve got a session on how testing with
&lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#solving-unemployment-in-africa-with-testing-and-selenium">Selenium is solving unemployment in Africa&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The cherry on the cake is the Q&amp;amp;A with the Selenium Committer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#q-amp-a-with-the-selenium-committers-panel">Panel&lt;/a>
where you&amp;rsquo;ll get to pick the brains of the very people who&amp;rsquo;ve built Selenium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a way, we&amp;rsquo;ve truly tried our best to touch upon the technology, people, and process aspects of testing. We&amp;rsquo;d love to
have you over to catch these experts in action!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="getting-your-hands-dirty-with-tailored-workshops">Getting your hands dirty with tailored workshops&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Testing is all about exploring. How about exploring and diving into something new?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve got community leaders doing deep dives into Selenium, Appium 2.0, how to become a committer, state model-based
testing, and driving observability with Selenium Grid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We truly believe that nothing beats hearing it from the horse&amp;rsquo;s mouth.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-more">What&amp;rsquo;s more?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While there are some amazing keynotes, well-researched talks, and structured workshops, we really think the biggest
takeaway for any attendee is the people they&amp;rsquo;ll get to meet. Selenium has been a great example of how the community can
come together to build something that is greater than the sum of its parts. A conference like this brings together folks
from across the world, with different levels of experience, and puts them under a single roof.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What can be more beautiful than getting to interact with the very community that has built and grown Selenium?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are you waiting for? &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/register/">Register now&lt;/a>! We can&amp;rsquo;t wait to welcome you to Chicago!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>