<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Documentation for Selenium</title>
    <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Documentation for Selenium</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>2013-{year}</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Selenium project and tools</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/the_selenium_project_and_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/the_selenium_project_and_tools/</guid>
      <description>Selenium controls web browsers Selenium is many things but at its core, it is a toolset for web browser automation that uses the best techniques available to remotely control browser instances and emulate a user&amp;rsquo;s interaction with the browser.
It allows users to simulate common activities performed by end-users; entering text into fields, selecting drop-down values and checking boxes, and clicking links in documents. It also provides many other controls such as mouse movement, arbitrary JavaScript execution, and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On test automation</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/on_test_automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/on_test_automation/</guid>
      <description>First, start by asking yourself whether or not you really need to use a browser. Odds are that, at some point, if you are working on a complex web application, you will need to open a browser and actually test it.
Functional end-user tests such as Selenium tests are expensive to run, however. Furthermore, they typically require substantial infrastructure to be in place to be run effectively. It is a good rule to always ask yourself if what you want to test can be done using more lightweight test approaches such as unit tests or with a lower-level approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of testing</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/types_of_testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/types_of_testing/</guid>
      <description>Acceptance testing This type of testing is done to determine if a feature or system meets the customer expectations and requirements. This type of testing generally involves the customer&amp;rsquo;s cooperation or feedback, being a validation activity that answers the question:
 Are we building the right product?.
 For web applications, the automation of this testing can be done directly with Selenium by simulating user expected behaviour. This simulation could be done by record/playback or through the different supported languages as explained in this documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/about_this_documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/about_this_documentation/</guid>
      <description>These docs, like the code itself, are maintained 100% by volunteers within the Selenium community. Many have been using it since its inception, but many more have only been using it for a short while, and have given their time to help improve the onboarding experience for new users.
If there is an issue with the documentation, we want to know! The best way to communicate an issue is to visit https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>