<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hangout on Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/tags/hangout/</link><description>Recent content in Hangout on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 05:24:49 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/tags/hangout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Selenium Hangout 5 Recap</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2014/selenium-hangout-6-recap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2014/selenium-hangout-6-recap/</guid><description>01:35 – 9:45 W3C Update
Notes from most recent W3C Meeting
Highlights:
– changes to the get_attribute method call
– screenshots (changing to viewport only, eventually will support whole page)
– The WebDriver W3C working group has a GitHub repo now
– WebDriver will move from a “REST-ish” to a more “RESTful” interface
11:23 – 16:00 Selenium 3 Status Update
16:05 – 17:10 Marionette (FirefoxdDiver rewrite) testing help
Marionette Roadmap</description></item><item><title>Selenium Hangout 5 Recap</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2014/selenium-hangout-5-recap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2014/selenium-hangout-5-recap/</guid><description>0:00 – 01:10 Intro
1:11 – 13:00 WebDriver W3C Spec &amp;amp; Selenium 3 Update
Progress on the spec, still a work in progress No user facing changes to the Selenium API as a result Trying to pair the spec and Selenium 3 together If all goes well, the spec and Selenium 3 could drop during Selenium Conf (fingers crossed) 13:01 – 24:10 Selenium Conf 2014 Update
Check out the new and shiny conference site Dates posted (e.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Hangout 4 Recap</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2014/selenium-hangout-4-recap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2014/selenium-hangout-4-recap/</guid><description>Here’s a recap from the latest Selenium Hangout panel discussion. To submit questions for future hangouts, you can message us on Twitter (@seleniumhangout) or e-mail us (questions@seleniumhangout.com).
Panel
David Burns (@AutomatedTester)
Kevin Menard (@nirvdrum)
Dave Haeffner (@TourDeDave)
Timeline
1:30-16:51: How to handle screenshots across different drivers
tl;dr driver specific issues due to a lacking standard and missing API
This is getting addressed in World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) spec which is under development E-mail use-cases you would like to see in the spec to automatedtester@mozilla.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Hangout 3 Recap</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/selenium-hangout-3-recap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/selenium-hangout-3-recap/</guid><description>Here is a recap of our most recent Selenium Hangout where we answered a grab bag of questions ranging from how to use Selenium within your existing workflow down to nitty-gritty details around performance and deprecated functions.
Be sure to tune into our Twitter feed to find out details about our next Hangout.
And if your question didn’t get answered, we encourage you to hop on IRC and ask it there.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Hangout 2 Recap</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/selenium-hangout-2-recap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/selenium-hangout-2-recap/</guid><description>This is a recap from the most recent Selenium Hangout (a.k.a. The World’s Best Selenium Meetup). For info on future meetups, follow them on Twitter.
Thanks to all who attended and tuned into the last Selenium Hangout where we talked about Selenium 3! Below is a write-up of the meetup, the video, and relevant links we mentioned. And to access all meetup videos you can go here.
Panel
David Burns (@AutomatedTester)</description></item></channel></rss>