<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conference on Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/categories/conference/</link><description>Recent content in Conference on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:36:32 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/categories/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Announcing SeleniumConf &amp; AppiumConf 2025</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/seleniumconf-appiumconf-valencia-2025/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/seleniumconf-appiumconf-valencia-2025/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to announce that SeleniumConf &amp;amp; AppiumConf is returning for 2025, bringing together browser and mobile automation enthusiasts from around the world. This must-attend event will take place from March 26-28, 2025, in the vibrant city of Valencia, Spain!
This year, the conference will gather over 400 browser and mobile automation professionals, including developers, testers, quality managers, test architects, and others, to explore the latest trends in browser and mobile automation, including cutting-edge topics like AI in automation, game testing, accessibility automation, and much more.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Open Space Conference Oct 28th</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-open-space-conference/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-open-space-conference/</guid><description>In less than two weeks, Selenium project is holding space for free and online community meetup, the inaugural Selenium Open Space Conference. Open space conferences are ones where everyone is a speaker, and we co-create our agenda for conversations, questions or answers, workshops, sharing and learning.
We start our 24 hour event at time of 19 years from the tracked Selenium release announcement. We split the day into four segments to facilitate the global community.</description></item><item><title>Let's meet at SeleniumConf, Once Again!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/lets-meet-in-person-at-seleniumconf-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/lets-meet-in-person-at-seleniumconf-2023/</guid><description>This year is special, thanks to the decision to host an in-person conference after a long hiatus and several years of virtual-only events. We&amp;rsquo;ve gone out of our way to reflect this feeling at the conference. We have engrossing keynotes, well-researched talks, hands-on pre-conference workshops, hallway tracks, and whatnot!
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list of what to expect! What&amp;rsquo;s cooking in Keynotes? We have Diego Molina kicking things off with &amp;lsquo;Selenium: State of the Union&amp;rsquo; where he will talk about all things Selenium, including the project, the code, and the community.</description></item><item><title>SeleniumConf Chicago 2023 Speakers Announced</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/seleniumconf-chicago-2023-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/seleniumconf-chicago-2023-update/</guid><description>As many of you know, the Selenium Conference returns to an in-person event next March 28-30, 2023 in Chicago, IL. The Program Chairs &amp;amp; Committee, as well as the Extended Program Review Committee, have been hard at work putting together an outstanding lineup of speakers and workshops, and we&amp;rsquo;re close to releasing the full agenda and a completely re-branded conference website - stay tuned! In the meantime, we wanted you to be among the first to know who will be presenting, announce a new, additional pre-conference workshop, and provide you with some important updates.</description></item><item><title>SeleniumConf Virtual 2020 Recap</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/selenium-conf-2020-recap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/selenium-conf-2020-recap/</guid><description>This year the Selenium Conference was held virtually, and despite that, the conference was again that exciting place where the Selenium community meets every year to share and learn about the most popular browser automation tool in the world. The conference offered talks about improved testing practices, new tools to simplify the setup of automated tests, the future of Selenium, and lots of learnings from speakers who shared their use cases and practical advice for how they use Selenium at work.</description></item><item><title>SeleniumConf London 2019 Videos and Pictures</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2019/seleniumconf-london-2019/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2019/seleniumconf-london-2019/</guid><description>Check out all the SeleniumConf London 2019 videos and photos!
You can find all the videos here, and all the pictures here.
If you cannot wait to get started, feel free to watch below Simon&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;State of the Union&amp;rdquo; keynote!</description></item><item><title>Fall Selenium Conf, Save the Date &amp; Call for Speakers!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/fall-selenium-conf-save-the-date/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/fall-selenium-conf-save-the-date/</guid><description>We’re excited to announce that we’ve finally determined where and when Selenium Conf will be happening this Fall.
Our initial goal was to bring the event to a new country, but for a number of reasons that proved more challenging than we’d hoped. But in 2012 we had the 2nd annual Selenium Conf in London, and we’re pleased to be bringing it back there this year!
The conference will be held at The Mermaid in downtown London on November 14-16:</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf India 2016 Update</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-conf-india-2016-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-conf-india-2016-update/</guid><description>Selenium Conf India is happening this June 24-26 in Bangalore, India.
Tickets, call for speakers, and sponsorship slots are now available!
http://2016.seleniumconf.in/</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf India — Save The Date!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-india-save-the-date/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-india-save-the-date/</guid><description>In our last update we mentioned there will be 2 Selenium Confs in 2016 — one in India, another somewhere else (TBD).
Well, we are pleased to announce the official dates and location for Selenium Conf India!
When: June 24th &amp;amp; 25th, 2016
Where: Bangalore, India (at The Chancery Pavilion Hotel)
Mark you calendars! We’ll have more details as they become available (e.g., call for speakers, ticket sales, etc.). To get the latest updates, be sure to sign up for the Selenium Conf mailing list.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf 2016</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2016/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2016/</guid><description>Interested in learning what’s in store for Se Conf 2016? Then be sure to read this write-up from the Conference Organizers.
Also, if you want to receive email notifications about the conference (e.g., when and where it will be, call for speakers, ticket sales, etc.) then go here and complete the sign-up form.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf 2015 Update</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2015-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2015-update/</guid><description>Selenium 2015 is just around the corner (September 8-10). Since our last post we have:
confirmed Keynote speakers finalized workshop presenters selected the talks for the conference You can see keynote &amp;amp; workshop info here, and the selected talks here.
If you still need a ticket, the last block of tickets are on sale NOW.
If you want to attend the conference then register ASAP. Tickets will go quick and once they’re gone, they’re gone.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf 2015 Details</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2015-details/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2015-details/</guid><description>The Selenium Conf 2015 website is live!
You can now:
– purchase tickets (while supplies last)
– find out venue information
– submit a talk
– learn more about our talk selection process (tl;dr it is a blind review process to encourage diversity)
What are you waiting for? Go to the conference website already!</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf 2015 – Save The Date</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2015-save-the-date/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2015-save-the-date/</guid><description>Selenium Conf is coming to Portland, Oregon this year!
It will be happening on September 8, 9, and 10. Mark your calendars.
Stay tuned for details!</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium Conf ’14: Bangalore, India</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2014/announcing-selenium-conf-14-bangalore-india/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2014/announcing-selenium-conf-14-bangalore-india/</guid><description>It makes me enormously happy and proud to announce that the Selenium Conference 2014 will be held in Bangalore on the 4-6 September. I’m looking forward to seeing you there!
One of the plans we’ve had from the very beginning for SeConf was that it was going to be a conference for the community of people who make Selenium such a fun project to work on. One way to do this was to host the conference where the largest groups of people using Selenium are found.</description></item><item><title>Curious to know how we picked speakers for the 2013 SeConf? Read on…</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/curious-to-know-how-we-picked-speakers-for-the-2013-seconf-read-on/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/curious-to-know-how-we-picked-speakers-for-the-2013-seconf-read-on/</guid><description>This is a guest post by Marcus Merrell, one of the organizers of the 2013 Selenium Conference.
Selenium/Webdriver has kept my family fed since 2007. Since I’ve never committed a line of code to this magical project, I thought the least I could do was spend a few hours helping put SeConf 2013 together. When they asked for a volunteer to put the speaker program together, I was thrilled to step forward!</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf 2013: Call for Papers and Early Bird Tickets</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/selenium-conf-2013-call-for-papers-and-early-bird-tickets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/selenium-conf-2013-call-for-papers-and-early-bird-tickets/</guid><description>This year’s Selenium Conference is slated for June 10 – 12 in beautiful Boston, Massachusetts. The conference will be held at the Renaissance Boston Waterfront Hotel. Similar to last year, this year’s conference will kick off with a full day of Selenium Workshops, followed by a two day, two track conference. If you’ve always dreamed of speaking at a Selenium Conference there’s still time to submit a talk to us at http://www.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf: Community</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-community/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-community/</guid><description>In this series of blog posts we’ve introduced one of the keynotes and talked about some of the great presentations you’ll see at Selenium Conf ’12, but so far we’ve missed the most important aspect of the entire event: you.
For me, one of the highlights of any conference is the chance to meet other members of the community, make new friends and talk about all things interesting (and perhaps even tangentially related to the conference!</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf: Speakers</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-speakers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-speakers/</guid><description>I may be biased, but I think Selenium Conf ’12 is going to be great. There are talks aimed at every level of Selenium user. We’ve got experience reports, so you can learn from the trials and tribulations of others. There are talks about using Selenium in unusual ways, such as performance testing, or automated security testing, so you can see new ideas and approaches.
There are technical talks, such as the one Jim Evans is giving on lessons learned from developing the IE driver, so you can learn a little bit more about how Selenium works and Luke Daley’s talk about Geb is bound to be fun.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf Keynotes: Liz Keogh</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-keynotes-liz-keogh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-keynotes-liz-keogh/</guid><description>The tickets for Selenium Conf ’12 are still on sale for about another week, so there’s still time for you to buy your tickets. In case you’ve not already gone to the conference site to see the great line up, this week we’ll be letting you know what to expect!
I’m really pleased to announce that Liz Keogh, who is a core member of the Behaviour Driven Development (BDD) community and is one of the stalwarts of the London Agile community, as well as a haiku poet, is going to be one of our keynotes!</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conference 2012</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conference-2012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conference-2012/</guid><description>Good news, everybody! Selenium Conf ’12 is getting closer! We recently selected the speakers for the conference, and it’s going to be a great mix of talks, spanning the full range of subjects from the very practical to the deeply technical. I’m promised that there will be robots.
Selenium Conf isn’t just about the planned talks, it’s also about the community. On the final day, there will be an unconference, so if there’s something you feel passionately about and feel the world should know, now’s your chance.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium Conf ’12</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/announcing-selenium-conf-12/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/announcing-selenium-conf-12/</guid><description>The community around Selenium is the thing that really makes the Selenium project special. Last year, we held the first official Selenium Conference in San Francisco, and it was both great fun and a huge success. It is therefore with great pleasure that we are announcing Selenium Conf ’12! It’ll be taking place in London from the 16th to the 18th April, and we’re really looking forward to seeing you all there!</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf is coming… get your proposals in!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-conf-is-coming-get-your-proposals-in/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-conf-is-coming-get-your-proposals-in/</guid><description>It has been mentioned at and hinted upon a couple times in the Smattering posts, but nothing has ‘officially’ been mentioned here, so it is time we fix that.
The first Selenium Conf is a go!
The logistics are set and we’re starting to sort out the program. Here is what you need to know. Right. Now.
When – Monday, April 4 – Wednesday, April 6 Where – Marines Memorial Club and Hotel Why – Its about darn time… This is a community driven event, though our friends at Sauce Labs are doing a lot of the leg work on the facilities (and food!</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conference Survey</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-conference-survey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-conference-survey/</guid><description>Great news! Thanks to the initiative of our friends at Sauce Labs, we’re finally ready to host the first-ever Selenium Conference. We’re still working out a lot of the details, but so far we’ve decided this first conference will be sometime in April and hosted in San Francisco.
In order to figure out the rest of the details, we’re looking for feedback from the Selenium user community. Please take a moment to fill out the following survey.</description></item><item><title>Selenium at Agile 2010</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-at-agile-2010/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-at-agile-2010/</guid><description>The Selenium project does not have an ‘official’ presence here at Agile as it is seen as a ‘test after’ tool rather than ‘test first’ — even though it provides the magic of the ‘test first’ frameworks… But there is a small, unofficial contingent of recognizable faces around that can help people out and some sessions on it.
Sessions
Why your selenium tests are so dang brittle, and what to do about it – Wednesday, August 11 – 3:30 – 5:00</description></item></channel></rss>