<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Status on Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/tags/status/</link><description>Recent content in Status on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 05:24:49 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/tags/status/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Announcing Selenium 4</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/announcing-selenium-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/announcing-selenium-4/</guid><description>It’s with very great pleasure that we are announcing the release of Selenium 4. This is available for Java, .Net, Python, Ruby, and Javascript. You can download it from your favourite package manager or right from GitHub!
If you’re already a Selenium user, this update should be as easy as just changing your dependency from 3.x to 4.0.0. We’ve worked hard to ensure that this is a “drop-in” upgrade, having focused on keeping the public APIs as stable as possible.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4 Release Candidate 2</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-rc-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-rc-2/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve listeneed and responded to the feedback from the first release candidate of Selenium 4, and we&amp;rsquo;re now happy to announce the second release candidate of Selenium 4. This is shipping for .Net, Java, Python, Ruby, and Javascript, and it&amp;rsquo;s available from all the popular package managers. Go! Try it out!
Unless we encounter a very serious issue or bug, this is likely to be the last release before we push Selenium 4.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4 Release Candidate</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-rc-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-rc-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the first release candidate of Selenium 4. We&amp;rsquo;re shipping this for .Net, Java, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript, so if you&amp;rsquo;re using any of those languages, go and grab it from your package manager of choice!
This release is the result of a lot of work by the Selenium team project, but most importantly, all the Selenium community who tried our beta releases, and gave us great and valuable feedback.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4 Beta 1 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-beta-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-beta-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of the first beta of Selenium 4. We&amp;rsquo;re shipping this for Java, .Net, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript, so if you&amp;rsquo;re using any of those languages, go and grab it from your package manager of choice!
This has been the culmination of a lot of work by so many people, not only the project TLC, but also of literally hundreds of people: 205 since we released Selenium 3.</description></item><item><title>The Current Status of Selenium 1 and Selenium 2</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/the-current-status-of-selenium-1-and-selenium-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/the-current-status-of-selenium-1-and-selenium-2/</guid><description>In the beginning there was Se1, and it was good. But it could have been better — in ways that WebDriver was starting to be good at. Thus the brilliant idea was hatched to merge the two projects.
And then the confusion began. Let’s see if I can start to address some of it via a ficticious conversation that consolidates the Se-user list and #selenium irc channel.
There are a couple annoying bugs in Se-RC 1.</description></item></channel></rss>