<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kubernetes on Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/tags/kubernetes/</link><description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 15:24:21 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Multi-Arch Images via Docker Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/multi-arch-images-via-docker-selenium/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/multi-arch-images-via-docker-selenium/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the landing of Multi-Arch Images for Selenium Grid Server on the Selenium Docker Hub registry!
Motivation For experimental Docker container images that are able to run on platforms such as the Apple M-series or Raspberry Pi, the community-driven repository initiative hosted at SeleniumHQ-Community/docker-seleniarm. These images are built for separate architectures: linux/arm64 (aarch64), linux/arm/v7 (armhf), and linux/amd64 and published on Seleniarm Docker Hub registry.
In order to bring more awareness to the existence of the Multi-Arch Docker container images, provide more insight and transparency on how the container images are built, as well as overcome challenges in building and maintaining them.</description></item><item><title>Scaling a Kubernetes Selenium Grid with KEDA</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/scaling-grid-with-keda/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/scaling-grid-with-keda/</guid><description>The Issue If you have any experience with Selenium Grid and Kubernetes you will probably run into an issue with scaling. Kubernetes (K8S) works wonders for scaling up and down applications based on their CPU and Memory usage, but it is not so straightforward when it comes down to applications like Selenium Grid.
The issue is described quite well in this blog post. But in short, the Horizontal Pod AutoScaler (HPA) that is built into Kubernetes checks (by default) for resource consumption to determine if a deployment needs to be scaled up or down.</description></item></channel></rss>