<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Firefox on Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/tags/firefox/</link><description>Recent content in Firefox on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 15:32:53 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/tags/firefox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Novelties in Selenium Manager 0.4.15</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/novelties_in_selenium_manager_0.4.15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/novelties_in_selenium_manager_0.4.15/</guid><description>Support for Firefox ESR Selenium Manager 0.4.15 includes support for Firefox Extended Support Release (ESR). This way, Firefox ESR can be automatically managed with Selenium using the label esr in the browser version. Bindings languages set this browser version (like other accepted labels for browser versions, such as stable, beta, dev, canary, and nightly) using a browser option called browserVersion.
Support for Edge WebView2 Selenium Manager 0.4.15 allows automated driver management for Microsoft Edge WebView2.</description></item><item><title>What's new in Selenium Manager 0.4.12, shipped with Selenium 4.12.0</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/whats_new_in_selenium_manager_0.4.12_shipped_with_selenium_4.12.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/whats_new_in_selenium_manager_0.4.12_shipped_with_selenium_4.12.0/</guid><description>A new release of Selenium Manager is out. For this release, we made a relevant decision concerning the Selenium Manager versioning format. From now on, Selenium Manager will follow the same version as Selenium. Nevertheless, since Selenium Manager is still in beta, its major version is 0. Thus, Selenium 4.12.0 is shipped with Selenium Manager 0.4.12.
First, we made a substantial effort to stabilize the already available features on Selenium Manager.</description></item><item><title>Dev and Beta Channel Browsers via Docker Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/dev-and-beta-channel-browsers-via-docker-selenium/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/dev-and-beta-channel-browsers-via-docker-selenium/</guid><description>The Docker Selenium browser Beta and Dev channel releases are now regularly published to Docker Hub and updated every two days. This enables testers and developers to test their applications on pre-release versions of Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, and Microsoft Edge before their official releases, using container tools, such as Docker. This empowers teams to stay ahead of the curve and catch potential showstoppers in their CI environment before those issues have an impact on their users.</description></item></channel></rss>