<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/tags/selenium/</link><description>Recent content on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 09:28:08 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/tags/selenium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sauce Labs: A New Milestone with Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/saucelabs-selenium-partnership/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/saucelabs-selenium-partnership/</guid><description>Selenium has witnessed an exceptional year filled with expansion and progress. The rising popularity of Selenium&amp;rsquo;s Python Bindings is prominently showcased through the engaging discussions at the Selenium Conference and on LinkedIn. Concurrently, the Java bindings have reached a significant landmark, surpassing 100 million downloads. In addition to this, the community has managed to garner over 2.5 million active Selenium users monthly.
We could not have achieved Selenium&amp;rsquo;s 20th anniversary without the collective efforts of numerous volunteers and the invaluable assistance of a company like Sauce Labs.</description></item><item><title>Celebrating a Milestone: BrowserStack Becomes Selenium's Development Partner</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/browserstack-selenium-partnership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/browserstack-selenium-partnership/</guid><description>It has been a great year for the Selenium community as it continues to grow. The popularity of Selenium’s Python Bindings is evident from the discussions at the Selenium Conference and on LinkedIn, while the Java bindings have impressively surpassed 100 million downloads.
This project, having reached 20 years old this year, would not be possible without the amazing contributions from our volunteer contributors and the Open Source Program Offices of companies like BrowserStack that allow us to work on this project as part of our day jobs.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.21 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-21-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-21-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.21.0 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v123, v124, and v125 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Selenium has at least 2.4M active users in the last 30 days. 100k more than last month! India and United States are the top countries with the most users.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.20 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-20-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-20-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.20.0 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v122, v123, and v124 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Selenium has at least 2.3M active users in the last 30 days. 500k more than last month! Java and JavaScript keep adding more WebDriver BiDi features.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.19 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-19-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-19-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.19.0 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v121, v122, and v123 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Thanks to Selenium Manager&amp;rsquo;s records usage, we know Selenium has at least 1.8M active users in the last 30 days! Java and JavaScript keep adding more WebDriver BiDi features.</description></item><item><title>Update imports to use BiDi Java</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/bidi-java-breaking-change/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/bidi-java-breaking-change/</guid><description>What part of the code base is impacted? Selenium WebDriver BiDi APIs in Java bindings are impacted.
What is impacted by the breaking change? The WebDriver BiDi APIs stay as they are, so you can continue to use them. However, the import statements need to be updated.
What is the breaking change? The import statements need to be updated when using the BiDi APIs.
Before Selenium 4.19: Java import org.openqa.selenium.bidi.LogInspector; import org.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.18 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-18-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-18-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.18.0 and 4.18.1 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v120, v121, and v122 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Selenium Manager records usage has been decreased to reduce impact on users. Chrome headless changed the name of the browser to reflect that it is not actually chrome; Selenium now handles this seamlessly, but you should still switch to --headless=new (see: Headless is going away) Noteworthy changes per language Java Enabling Grid to use self-signed certificate for debugging Added explicit target locator events to the listener support classes in WebDriverListener.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.17 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-17-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-17-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.17.0 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v119, v120, and v121 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Selenium Manager records usage set environment variable SE_AVOID_STATS to &amp;quot;true&amp;quot; to avoid sending information. Chrome headless changed the name of the browser to reflect that it is not actually chrome; Selenium now handles this seamlessly, but you should still switch to --headless=new (see: Headless is going away) Noteworthy changes per language Java Remove deprecated event listener classes; update to EventFiringDecorator and WebDriverListener classes Allow disabling Grid UI Deprecated FirefoxBinary class and legacy Error Codes Deprecated HTML5 features for offline storage, location, and network connection No longer accepting session requests with desiredCapabilities keyword See all changes JavaScript Remove deprecated headless methods and associated references Implemented remote file downloading See all changes .</description></item><item><title>Selenium Vs … blog posts</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-vs-blog-posts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-vs-blog-posts/</guid><description>The easiest way to clickbait a blog post about automated testing is to compare Selenium against another tool in the space with a catchy title especially when it talks down about the incumbent.
Unfortunately, this can lead to muddying the waters of which features are available in any of the products out there especially when we compare apples to apples.
Selenium has always been a great tool for browser automation. Fortunately for the project, it has become the tool of choice for testing web applications for nearly 2 decades.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.16 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-16-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-16-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.16.0 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, and Selenium 4.16.1 for .NET, Java and the Grid. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v118, v119, and v120 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Users may now opt in to Selenium Manager by specifying a browserVersion that is different from what is found on the System All bindings now log Selenium information Noteworthy changes per language Java Improve Grid usage of Selenium Manager by always allowing browser version of &amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; Implement CDP script pinning for Chrome-based browsers Allow reusing devtools instance with JDK 11 client Moved org.</description></item><item><title>Novelties in Selenium Manager 0.4.15</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/novelties_in_selenium_manager_0.4.15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/novelties_in_selenium_manager_0.4.15/</guid><description>Support for Firefox ESR Selenium Manager 0.4.15 includes support for Firefox Extended Support Release (ESR). This way, Firefox ESR can be automatically managed with Selenium using the label esr in the browser version. Bindings languages set this browser version (like other accepted labels for browser versions, such as stable, beta, dev, canary, and nightly) using a browser option called browserVersion.
Support for Edge WebView2 Selenium Manager 0.4.15 allows automated driver management for Microsoft Edge WebView2.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.15 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-15-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-15-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.15.0 for Java, Javascript, Ruby, .NET and the Grid; 4.15.2 for Python. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v117, v118, and v119 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Implemented Remote File Downloads Selenium Manager supports webview2, Firefox ESR and Driver and Browser Mirrors Noteworthy changes per language Java Numerous BiDi implementations Remove CDP version dependencies in the server Selenium Manager now gets copied to cache directory instead of being used from temp directory See all changes JavaScript Replaced calls to console.</description></item><item><title>Status of Selenium Manager in October 2023</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/status_of_selenium_manager_in_october_2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/status_of_selenium_manager_in_october_2023/</guid><description>Selenium Manager continues its development plan. As usual, in the latest releases, i.e., 0.4.13 and 0.4.14 (shipped with Selenium 4.13 and 4.14, respectively), we have fixed the problems reported so far. In these releases, the issues were related to the extraction of the Firefox binary from the self-extracting archive (SFX) in Windows and the advanced configuration through the configuration file (se-config.toml) and environment variables (e.g., SE_BROWSER). Moreover, these recent releases include new features, as explained below.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.13 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-13-0-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-13-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.13.0 for Java, Python, Javascript and the Grid; and 4.13.1 for .NET and Ruby. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v115, v116, and v117 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Reminder: this is the last version of Selenium with Java 8 support. Please upgrade to at least Java 11. The location of Selenium Manager can be set manually in all bindings with SE_MANAGER_PATH environment variable.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.14 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-14-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-14-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.14.0 for Java, Python, Javascript, Ruby, .NET and the Grid. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v116, v117, and v118 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) If you are using Java, this release requires Java 11! (see post on Java 8 support) Selenium supports automatic downloading and management of the Microsoft Edge browser Relevant improvements per language Java Removed support for Async HTTP Client, the default is now the default Java library Allow setting SSL context in client config for HttpClient Several logging message improvements See all changes JavaScript See all changes .</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.12.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-12-0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-12-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.12.0 for Java, .NET, Ruby, Python, and Javascript as well as the Grid. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v114, v115, and v116 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Quite a few fixes for Selenium Manager, and now with Firefox browser management! Read about all the new Selenium Manager features .</description></item><item><title>What's new in Selenium Manager 0.4.12, shipped with Selenium 4.12.0</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/whats_new_in_selenium_manager_0.4.12_shipped_with_selenium_4.12.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/whats_new_in_selenium_manager_0.4.12_shipped_with_selenium_4.12.0/</guid><description>A new release of Selenium Manager is out. For this release, we made a relevant decision concerning the Selenium Manager versioning format. From now on, Selenium Manager will follow the same version as Selenium. Nevertheless, since Selenium Manager is still in beta, its major version is 0. Thus, Selenium 4.12.0 is shipped with Selenium Manager 0.4.12.
First, we made a substantial effort to stabilize the already available features on Selenium Manager.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.11.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-11-0-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-11-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.11.0 for Java, .NET, Ruby, Python, and Javascript as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v113, v114, and v115 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Support for Chrome for Testing (CfT) through Selenium Manager. Read more at the new Selenium Manager features blog post.</description></item><item><title>What's new in Selenium Manager with Selenium 4.11.0</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/whats-new-in-selenium-manager-with-selenium-4.11.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/whats-new-in-selenium-manager-with-selenium-4.11.0/</guid><description>As of version 4.6.0, all releases of Selenium (Java, JavaScript, Python, Ruby, and .Net) are shipped with Selenium Manager. Selenium Manager is a binary tool (implemented in Rust) that provides automated driver management for Selenium. Selenium Manager is still in beta, although it is becoming a relevant component of Selenium.
So far, the main feature of Selenium Manager is called automated driver management. I use the term management for this feature (and not just download) since this process is broader and implies different steps:</description></item><item><title>Building Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/building-selenium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/building-selenium/</guid><description>One of the things that we knew from the very beginning of the Selenium project was that people like to code in more than one language. Some people love a bit of JS, others Ruby, and still others prefer C# or Java.
To complicate matters, there’s plenty of pieces we want to share between the language bindings you’ll be using. Examples include the “atoms” (re-usable pieces of javascript that perform common functions – such as “isDisplayed” or “getAttribute” – that we want to work the same way no matter which language you prefer to write tests in), things like our CDP support, which uses shared files that describe all the available functions we can call, and the new Selenium Manager, which is written in Rust, but we bundle with each of the language bindings.</description></item><item><title>Java 8 support in Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/java-8-support/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/java-8-support/</guid><description>“If it ain’t broke, don’t fix it” is a saying you may have heard, but sometimes it’s necessary to move on from our old favorites. That’s why we’re announcing that Selenium will stop supporting Java 8 on September 30, 2023. This applies for both the Java bindings and the Selenium Grid.
Selenium has long supported Java 8, but as technology evolves, so must we. One of the primary reasons for this change is that Java 8 reached the end of active support over a year ago.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.10.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-10-0-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-10-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.10.0 for Java, .NET, Ruby, Python, and Javascript as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v112, v113, and v114 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Selenium Manager supports proxy usage by using the proxy information set in the browser options. Adding support for webview2 in Edge for Java, JavaScript, and Ruby Error messages across bindings now include links to the Selenium documentation.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.9.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-9-0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-9-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.9.0 for Java, .NET, Ruby, Python, and Javascript as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v110, v111, and v112 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Maven BOM for the Java bindings. Remote file downloads are now possible through Selenium Grid. First steps taken to phase out CDP in Firefox and replace it with the BiDi implementation.</description></item><item><title>Headless is Going Away!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/headless-is-going-away/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/headless-is-going-away/</guid><description>Headless is an execution mode for Firefox and Chromium based browsers. It allows users to run automated scripts in headless mode, meaning that the browser window wouldn’t be visible. In most of Selenium&amp;rsquo;s bindings there is a convenience method to set this execution mode while setting the browser options. However, Selenium 4.8.0 will be deprecated this method and now users need to set it through arguments when setting the browser options.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.8.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-8-0-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-8-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.8.0 for Java, .NET, Ruby, Python, and Javascript as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v107, v108, and v109 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Large JS executions have the name as a comment to help understand what payload being sent to/from server/driver.</description></item><item><title>Year End Review 2022</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/end-of-year-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/end-of-year-review/</guid><description>It was an amazing year here at the Selenium project, and we wanted to remind you of some of the great things we accomplished.
In terms of releases, we continued to build on top of Selenium 4 which was launched in October 2021. This year we published v4.2, v4.3, v4.4, v4.5, v4.6, and v4.7. These releases included improvements, bug fixes, removal of deprecated functionality, improved error handling, updates of the underlying libraries, support for the latest Chrome DevTools versions to keep you in sync with new browser releases, but also new features.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.7.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-7-0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-7-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.7.0 for Java, .NET, and Javascript as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver; for Ruby use 4.7.1, and Python 4.7.2. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v106, v107, and v108 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Selenium Manager now supports IE Driver &amp;amp; has improved error logging. Using Edge in IE Mode no longer requires ignoring zoom levels.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Selenium Manager</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/introducing-selenium-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/introducing-selenium-manager/</guid><description>Most people&amp;rsquo;s first experience with Selenium ends up with an error message like this one:
java.lang.IllegalStateException: The path to the driver executable must be set by the webdriver.chrome.driver system property; for more information, see https://chromedriver.chromium.org/. The latest version can be downloaded from https://chromedriver.chromium.org/downloads Then they have to search the web for instructions on what to do with the drivers they download.
Selenium: now with batteries included! The Selenium project wants to improve the user experience, and one of the first steps is to help all users to simplify how they set up their environment.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.6.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-6-0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-6-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.6.0 for Java, .NET, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript bindings as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Adding support for CDP released in Chrome v105, v106, and v107, while v104 was removed Initial implementation of Selenium Manager across bindings Improvements to the new Java HTTP 11 client and important Grid fixes.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.5.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-5-0-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-5-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.5.0 for Java, .NET, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript bindings as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver. Links to everything can be found on our Downloads Page.
Highlights Adding support for CDP released in Chrome v105 and v106, while v102 and v103 were removed Updates to Select functionality Improved experience for Firefox Add-ons IE driver automatically uses Edge in IE Mode if IE is not present Java 11 HTTP Client supported for Java users running Java versions 11+ Various language specific bug fixes; see the full list of changes in the Changelogs.</description></item><item><title>Using Java 11+ HTTP Client in Selenium 4.5.0 and beyond</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/using-java11-httpclient/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/using-java11-httpclient/</guid><description>Current HTTP client used in Selenium Selenium uses an HTTP client and associated WebSocket client for multiple purposes
To send commands to the WebDriver To send commands from the Selenium client library to the Grid For various Grid components to communicate with each other depending on the Grid mode To create ChromeDevTools protocol and BiDi protocol sessions Currently, Selenium uses AsyncHttpClient. AsyncHttpClient is an open-source library built on top of Netty.</description></item><item><title>Scaling a Kubernetes Selenium Grid with KEDA</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/scaling-grid-with-keda/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/scaling-grid-with-keda/</guid><description>The Issue If you have any experience with Selenium Grid and Kubernetes you will probably run into an issue with scaling. Kubernetes (K8S) works wonders for scaling up and down applications based on their CPU and Memory usage, but it is not so straightforward when it comes down to applications like Selenium Grid.
The issue is described quite well in this blog post. But in short, the Horizontal Pod AutoScaler (HPA) that is built into Kubernetes checks (by default) for resource consumption to determine if a deployment needs to be scaled up or down.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.4.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-4-0-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-4-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.4.0. We&amp;rsquo;re shipping this for Java, .Net, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript, so if you&amp;rsquo;re using any of those languages, go and grab it from your package manager of choice!
Some of the main highlights are:
Adding support for CDP released in Chrome v104, while v101 was removed Virtual authenticator feature was completed across languages. All language bindings will throw an error when w3c: false is set in ChromeOptions Improved health checks and requests with non W3C locators for Relay Nodes in Grid Check the complete changelog and download the artifacts at the Selenium 4.</description></item><item><title>Test Automation Summit Berlin</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/test-automation-summit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/test-automation-summit/</guid><description>Have you ever wanted to contribute to an open source testing project, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out where to start? If so, fill out this form to apply for an invitation to join the Open Source Test Automation Summit on August 26 in Berlin, sponsored by Selenium and hosted by Sauce Labs. You can review the list of available projects below and select the one that you&amp;rsquo;d like to contribute to. We&amp;rsquo;ll be in touch soon if you are selected to join us.</description></item><item><title>Improving &amp; refining our Docs translations</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/docs-translations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/docs-translations/</guid><description>A while ago, we started to make the Selenium documentation available in more languages. This, in an effort to offer a more inclusive environment for Selenium users who do not have English as their mother tongue.
This effort grew organically, and we got many pull requests adding content for different languages. Over time, some translations got to a very good state, and others didn&amp;rsquo;t get much attention. This brought the situation where 9 different languages are available in the documentation, but only a few add value to the readers.</description></item><item><title>A Tour of 4: New Commands</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/a-tour-of-4-new-commands/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/a-tour-of-4-new-commands/</guid><description>Before we ship Selenium 4, I thought it would be nice to introduce some of the new features in-depth. Of course, all of the features we&amp;rsquo;re covering are in the main WebDriver documentation, so if you&amp;rsquo;re not one for reading blog posts, then feel free to dive in there!
You may well be familiar with how to start a Selenium server: you just do something like java -jar selenium-server-4.0.0.jar standalone and away you go!</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium 4</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/announcing-selenium-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/announcing-selenium-4/</guid><description>It’s with very great pleasure that we are announcing the release of Selenium 4. This is available for Java, .Net, Python, Ruby, and Javascript. You can download it from your favourite package manager or right from GitHub!
If you’re already a Selenium user, this update should be as easy as just changing your dependency from 3.x to 4.0.0. We’ve worked hard to ensure that this is a “drop-in” upgrade, having focused on keeping the public APIs as stable as possible.</description></item><item><title>A Tour of 4: Authentication</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/a-tour-of-4-authentication/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/a-tour-of-4-authentication/</guid><description>Before we ship Selenium 4, I thought it would be nice to introduce some of the new features in-depth. Of course, all of the features we&amp;rsquo;re covering are in the main WebDriver documentation, so if you&amp;rsquo;re not one for reading blog posts, then feel free to dive in there!
The first thing I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce you to is Selenium 4&amp;rsquo;s new-found ability to authenticate to websites. We&amp;rsquo;ve always been able to handle &amp;ldquo;form-based&amp;rdquo; authentication, where a login page has some INPUT elements that you need to enter the user name and password, but handling sites that use basic or digest authentication has always been harder.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4 Release Candidate 2</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-rc-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-rc-2/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve listeneed and responded to the feedback from the first release candidate of Selenium 4, and we&amp;rsquo;re now happy to announce the second release candidate of Selenium 4. This is shipping for .Net, Java, Python, Ruby, and Javascript, and it&amp;rsquo;s available from all the popular package managers. Go! Try it out!
Unless we encounter a very serious issue or bug, this is likely to be the last release before we push Selenium 4.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4 Release Candidate</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-rc-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-rc-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the first release candidate of Selenium 4. We&amp;rsquo;re shipping this for .Net, Java, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript, so if you&amp;rsquo;re using any of those languages, go and grab it from your package manager of choice!
This release is the result of a lot of work by the Selenium team project, but most importantly, all the Selenium community who tried our beta releases, and gave us great and valuable feedback.</description></item><item><title>All Selenium downloads are now available on GitHub releases</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/downloads-now-on-github-releases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/downloads-now-on-github-releases/</guid><description>We announced on a previous entry our decision to move all binaries from Google Storage to GitHub releases. Today, we would like to announce that this work has been completed and all binaries are also available to be downloaded in each one of the releases we have done in GitHub.
In addition to that, all links on our downloads page have been updated, as well as all references to Google Storage in the Selenium code base.</description></item><item><title>Selenium downloads will move to GitHub releases</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/downloads-moving-to-github-releases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/downloads-moving-to-github-releases/</guid><description>Thanks to Google, Google Storage has been the central place where we have been able to upload all binaries created for each Selenium release, and the place where the Selenium community can download them from. To do so, all people needed to do was visit our downloads page, find the release, and download from there!
The Selenium project hosts its source code on GitHub, and people who are familiar with GitHub know that they can go to the &amp;ldquo;release&amp;rdquo; page there to find any downloads for each release of a project.</description></item><item><title>The Selenium website has a new look!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/new-look-for-selenium-site/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/new-look-for-selenium-site/</guid><description>We have been working hard during the last few weeks redoing our website. Today, we are very happy to share it with the community and we are hoping to get as much feedback as possible!
We did a major revamp to our website two years ago. However, this revamp had some &amp;ldquo;technical debt&amp;rdquo; in it&amp;hellip;
We&amp;#39;re happy to announce that we have (finally!) refreshed our site. Head on over to https://t.</description></item><item><title>IRC channels are moving to Libera.chat</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/moving-to-libera-chat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/moving-to-libera-chat/</guid><description>Yesterday, 19 May 2021, all the staff of Freenode, the IRC network, collectively resigned as staff because of what they felt was a hostile takeover.
Freenode has always been seen as the home of Free and Open Software, so it was natural that you could find us on the #selenium channel there. To maintain this openness, and inclusivity, we are moving our IRC Channel over to Libera.chat. It is has been created by the team that previously maintained Freenode.</description></item><item><title>Observability in Selenium 4</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-observability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-observability/</guid><description>Diagnosing problems when the Selenium server isn&amp;rsquo;t working has never been easy. With Selenium 4, we have integrated OpenTelemetry to help you troubleshoot issues, optimize performance, and provide visibility into the system. By making the Selenium server observable, we are putting more power into your hands.
Need for Observability Selenium server enables distributed testing. Instead of running the browsers for tests locally, the tests use a remote browser driver that points to a server.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4 Beta 1 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-beta-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-beta-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of the first beta of Selenium 4. We&amp;rsquo;re shipping this for Java, .Net, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript, so if you&amp;rsquo;re using any of those languages, go and grab it from your package manager of choice!
This has been the culmination of a lot of work by so many people, not only the project TLC, but also of literally hundreds of people: 205 since we released Selenium 3.</description></item><item><title>New Tricks in Selenium 4</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-the-new-selenium-grid/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-the-new-selenium-grid/</guid><description>In the fourth and final post in his series, Simon Stewart continues talking about what&amp;rsquo;s coming in Selenium 4 and reviews what&amp;rsquo;s new in the Selenium Grid.
We’ve covered a lot of ground in the past few blog posts, including how to contribute to the project, and some details of what you can expect as a Selenium user. But there’s more to Selenium than just the APIs you use to write your tests, and one of the big features we’ve not covered yet is the refreshed Selenium Grid: a mechanism that allows you to distribute your tests across a fleet of machines.</description></item><item><title>New Tricks in Selenium 4</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-new-tricks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-new-tricks/</guid><description>In the third post in his series, Simon Stewart continues talking about what&amp;rsquo;s coming in Selenium 4 and reviews some of the tricks in the new release.
In my last posts, we talked about how to contribute to Selenium, and why we’re bumping the version number to 4. That’s enough preamble! Today, we’ll cover some details about the new tricks and capabilities that Selenium 4 offers.
Finding Elements, and Relative Locators You know, finding elements on a page can be really difficult.</description></item><item><title>What’s Coming in Selenium 4: Why The Major Version Bump?</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-why-the-major-version-bump/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-why-the-major-version-bump/</guid><description>In the second post in this series, Simon Stewart continues talking about what&amp;rsquo;s coming in Selenium 4 and why this release has a major version bump.
In my last post, I shared a bit about how the Selenium project works overall. Now, let’s start talking about Selenium 4 and what’s coming. One thing I think I should clear up is &amp;ldquo;why the major version number bump?&amp;rdquo;
Sometimes I joke that the major reason for the version number bump is that while the digits of Pi are infinite, when we went from 3.</description></item><item><title>What’s Coming in Selenium 4: How Can I Contribute?</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-how-can-i-contribute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-how-can-i-contribute/</guid><description>In this new blog series all about the upcoming release of Selenium 4, Simon Stewart will cover how the Selenium project works, who is involved, how you can get involved, and a sneak peek at what’s new in Selenium 4.
As the lead of the Selenium project, I wanted to kick off a new blog series leading up to the release of Selenium 4. During this series, I’ll talk all about how the Selenium project works, who is involved, how you—yes, you!</description></item><item><title>SeleniumConf Virtual 2020 Recap</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/selenium-conf-2020-recap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/selenium-conf-2020-recap/</guid><description>This year the Selenium Conference was held virtually, and despite that, the conference was again that exciting place where the Selenium community meets every year to share and learn about the most popular browser automation tool in the world. The conference offered talks about improved testing practices, new tools to simplify the setup of automated tests, the future of Selenium, and lots of learnings from speakers who shared their use cases and practical advice for how they use Selenium at work.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.0 Alpha 6 is out!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/selenium-4-alpha-6-is-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/selenium-4-alpha-6-is-out/</guid><description>We are very pleased to announce the release of Selenium 4.0 Alpha 6.
All the information can be seen in different tweets from the project contributors, here they are all in one place:
Happy Friday! I&amp;#39;ve just pushed Selenium 4.0a6 for Java. There&amp;#39;s a lot of nice changes:
* Full remoting of the CDP protocol across the Grid
* The skeleton of our GraphQL support
* Better configuration options, especially for Nodes, via TOML</description></item><item><title>SeleniumConf London 2019 Videos and Pictures</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2019/seleniumconf-london-2019/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2019/seleniumconf-london-2019/</guid><description>Check out all the SeleniumConf London 2019 videos and photos!
You can find all the videos here, and all the pictures here.
If you cannot wait to get started, feel free to watch below Simon&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;State of the Union&amp;rdquo; keynote!</description></item><item><title>Selenium IDE Is Dead, Long Live Selenium IDE!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2018/long-live-selenium-ide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2018/long-live-selenium-ide/</guid><description>In August of 2017 Simon shared the bleak, hard news that as of Firefox 55 Selenium IDE would no longer work. Selenium IDE (or as we’ll refer to it from here on out – the Legacy IDE) was, and is, dead.
Since then quite a lot has happened with the IDE. We have a new version of it which we are referring to as… Selenium IDE!
It is currently in “alpha” and available for use in both Chrome and Firefox.</description></item><item><title>Firefox 55 and Selenium IDE</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2017/firefox-55-and-selenium-ide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2017/firefox-55-and-selenium-ide/</guid><description>The bad news: from Firefox 55 onwards, Selenium IDE will no longer work.
The reasons for this are complex, but boil down to two main causes:
Browsers are complicated pieces of software that are constantly evolving. Mozilla has been working hard to make Firefox faster and more stable, while still retaining the flexibility and ease of extension that we’ve come to know and love. As part of that process, Firefox is switching extensions from the original “XPI” format, to a newer, more widely adopted “Web Extension” mechanism.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 3.0: Out Now!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-0-out-now/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-0-out-now/</guid><description>We are very pleased to announce the release of Selenium 3.0. If you’ve been waiting for a stable release since 2.53.1, now’s your chance to update. And if you do, here is what you’ll find:
As we’ve said before, for users of the WebDriver APIs this is a drop-in replacement. You’ll find that modern browsers, such as Chrome and Edge will continue to work just as before, and we’ve taken the opportunity to fix some bugs and improve stability.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 3 is Coming</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-is-coming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-is-coming/</guid><description>Selenium 3 is coming! As I write this, we think that “beta 4” will be the last beta before the official 3.0 release. I’m here to tell you about what’s changed, and what impact this will have on your testing.
TL;DR: WebDriver users will just find bug fixes and a drop-in replacement for 2.x. Selenium Grid users will also find bug fixes and a simple update. The WebDriver APIs are now the only APIs actively supported by the Selenium project.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium 3.0-beta1</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/announcing-selenium-3-0-beta1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/announcing-selenium-3-0-beta1/</guid><description>At SeleniumConf in 2013, we announced that a new major version of Selenium would be released “by Christmas”. Fortunately, we never said which Christmas, as it has taken us a while to make all the changes we wanted to make! We’re excited to announce the release of the first beta — Selenium 3.0.0-beta1.
We’d love you to try it out on your projects, and provide us with feedback on where the rough edges are before we ship the 3.</description></item><item><title>Fall Selenium Conf, Save the Date &amp; Call for Speakers!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/fall-selenium-conf-save-the-date/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/fall-selenium-conf-save-the-date/</guid><description>We’re excited to announce that we’ve finally determined where and when Selenium Conf will be happening this Fall.
Our initial goal was to bring the event to a new country, but for a number of reasons that proved more challenging than we’d hoped. But in 2012 we had the 2nd annual Selenium Conf in London, and we’re pleased to be bringing it back there this year!
The conference will be held at The Mermaid in downtown London on November 14-16:</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf India 2016 Update</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-conf-india-2016-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-conf-india-2016-update/</guid><description>Selenium Conf India is happening this June 24-26 in Bangalore, India.
Tickets, call for speakers, and sponsorship slots are now available!
http://2016.seleniumconf.in/</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf India — Save The Date!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-india-save-the-date/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-india-save-the-date/</guid><description>In our last update we mentioned there will be 2 Selenium Confs in 2016 — one in India, another somewhere else (TBD).
Well, we are pleased to announce the official dates and location for Selenium Conf India!
When: June 24th &amp;amp; 25th, 2016
Where: Bangalore, India (at The Chancery Pavilion Hotel)
Mark you calendars! We’ll have more details as they become available (e.g., call for speakers, ticket sales, etc.). To get the latest updates, be sure to sign up for the Selenium Conf mailing list.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf 2016</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2016/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2016/</guid><description>Interested in learning what’s in store for Se Conf 2016? Then be sure to read this write-up from the Conference Organizers.
Also, if you want to receive email notifications about the conference (e.g., when and where it will be, call for speakers, ticket sales, etc.) then go here and complete the sign-up form.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf 2015 Update</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2015-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2015-update/</guid><description>Selenium 2015 is just around the corner (September 8-10). Since our last post we have:
confirmed Keynote speakers finalized workshop presenters selected the talks for the conference You can see keynote &amp;amp; workshop info here, and the selected talks here.
If you still need a ticket, the last block of tickets are on sale NOW.
If you want to attend the conference then register ASAP. Tickets will go quick and once they’re gone, they’re gone.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf 2015 Details</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2015-details/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2015-details/</guid><description>The Selenium Conf 2015 website is live!
You can now:
– purchase tickets (while supplies last)
– find out venue information
– submit a talk
– learn more about our talk selection process (tl;dr it is a blind review process to encourage diversity)
What are you waiting for? Go to the conference website already!</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf 2015 – Save The Date</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2015-save-the-date/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/selenium-conf-2015-save-the-date/</guid><description>Selenium Conf is coming to Portland, Oregon this year!
It will be happening on September 8, 9, and 10. Mark your calendars.
Stay tuned for details!</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium Conf ’14: Bangalore, India</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2014/announcing-selenium-conf-14-bangalore-india/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2014/announcing-selenium-conf-14-bangalore-india/</guid><description>It makes me enormously happy and proud to announce that the Selenium Conference 2014 will be held in Bangalore on the 4-6 September. I’m looking forward to seeing you there!
One of the plans we’ve had from the very beginning for SeConf was that it was going to be a conference for the community of people who make Selenium such a fun project to work on. One way to do this was to host the conference where the largest groups of people using Selenium are found.</description></item><item><title>Android and iOS Support</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/android-and-ios-support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/android-and-ios-support/</guid><description>TL;DR: We’re retiring Selenium’s own AndroidDriver and iPhoneDriver in favour of any of Selendroid, iosdriver and Appium. If you’re using one of Selenium’s own mobile drivers, please evaluate one of these alternatives.
The longer version:
In 2007, Steve Jobs announced the iPhone and changed the mobile Web from a curiosity to something the mainstream wanted and used. Current trends suggest that mobile Web usage will surpass desktop usage in the not too distant future.</description></item><item><title>Mobile WebDriver</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/mobile-webdriver/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/mobile-webdriver/</guid><description>Although the WebDriver APIs started life as just a mechanism for automating web browsers, over the past few years it has been extended to also work on mobile devices. Projects such as Appium, iosdriver, and Selendroid have all shown that this approach works, and works well. On the Web, if you start using Selenium WebDriver with one browser (Firefox, for example), it’s easy to switch out the browser for another one (such as Internet Explorer or Chrome).</description></item><item><title>The Road to Selenium 3</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/the-road-to-selenium-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/the-road-to-selenium-3/</guid><description>Selenium 2 was released in July 2011. It’s now two years old, and what a couple of years it’s been! The WebDriver APIs, which were the major addition in Selenium 2, are now the basis for a W3C standard, and there are implementations written and supported by Google, Mozilla and Opera. There have been 34 releases, with official support for Java, C#, Python, Ruby and Javascript, and the community has stepped in to provide bindings for Perl, PHP and others.</description></item><item><title>Curious to know how we picked speakers for the 2013 SeConf? Read on…</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/curious-to-know-how-we-picked-speakers-for-the-2013-seconf-read-on/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/curious-to-know-how-we-picked-speakers-for-the-2013-seconf-read-on/</guid><description>This is a guest post by Marcus Merrell, one of the organizers of the 2013 Selenium Conference.
Selenium/Webdriver has kept my family fed since 2007. Since I’ve never committed a line of code to this magical project, I thought the least I could do was spend a few hours helping put SeConf 2013 together. When they asked for a volunteer to put the speaker program together, I was thrilled to step forward!</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf 2013: Call for Papers and Early Bird Tickets</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/selenium-conf-2013-call-for-papers-and-early-bird-tickets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/selenium-conf-2013-call-for-papers-and-early-bird-tickets/</guid><description>This year’s Selenium Conference is slated for June 10 – 12 in beautiful Boston, Massachusetts. The conference will be held at the Renaissance Boston Waterfront Hotel. Similar to last year, this year’s conference will kick off with a full day of Selenium Workshops, followed by a two day, two track conference. If you’ve always dreamed of speaking at a Selenium Conference there’s still time to submit a talk to us at http://www.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium 2.26: the “It’s Really Real” Release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-26/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-26/</guid><description>It’s been a long time since we announced a new Selenium release on this blog, as we moved to a model of quicker releases, but we’ve been working on 2.26 for far longer than normal — it’s out! Download it now! — so I thought it best to let you know. We’re aiming to head back to faster releases, so hopefully you won’t see another blog post about the release for a while (though I’m sure they’ll appear in the “Smatterings of Selenium” posts)</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium 2.22</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-22/</guid><description>It’s been a while since the last Selenium release, but I’m happy to announce that Selenium 2.22 is now available for download. This is a big release for us and features two major changes.
The first is that Selenium 2.22 is the first version that requires Java 6 in order to run. This has been the case for the Selenium Server for some time, but this is the first time the client code has required Java 6.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf: Community</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-community/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-community/</guid><description>In this series of blog posts we’ve introduced one of the keynotes and talked about some of the great presentations you’ll see at Selenium Conf ’12, but so far we’ve missed the most important aspect of the entire event: you.
For me, one of the highlights of any conference is the chance to meet other members of the community, make new friends and talk about all things interesting (and perhaps even tangentially related to the conference!</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf: Speakers</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-speakers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-speakers/</guid><description>I may be biased, but I think Selenium Conf ’12 is going to be great. There are talks aimed at every level of Selenium user. We’ve got experience reports, so you can learn from the trials and tribulations of others. There are talks about using Selenium in unusual ways, such as performance testing, or automated security testing, so you can see new ideas and approaches.
There are technical talks, such as the one Jim Evans is giving on lessons learned from developing the IE driver, so you can learn a little bit more about how Selenium works and Luke Daley’s talk about Geb is bound to be fun.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf Keynotes: Liz Keogh</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-keynotes-liz-keogh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-keynotes-liz-keogh/</guid><description>The tickets for Selenium Conf ’12 are still on sale for about another week, so there’s still time for you to buy your tickets. In case you’ve not already gone to the conference site to see the great line up, this week we’ll be letting you know what to expect!
I’m really pleased to announce that Liz Keogh, who is a core member of the Behaviour Driven Development (BDD) community and is one of the stalwarts of the London Agile community, as well as a haiku poet, is going to be one of our keynotes!</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conference 2012</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conference-2012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conference-2012/</guid><description>Good news, everybody! Selenium Conf ’12 is getting closer! We recently selected the speakers for the conference, and it’s going to be a great mix of talks, spanning the full range of subjects from the very practical to the deeply technical. I’m promised that there will be robots.
Selenium Conf isn’t just about the planned talks, it’s also about the community. On the final day, there will be an unconference, so if there’s something you feel passionately about and feel the world should know, now’s your chance.</description></item><item><title>Support for Ancient Browsers</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/support-for-ancient-browsers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/support-for-ancient-browsers/</guid><description>The first code checked into the Selenium project’s public repository was in November, 2004. We’re now in 2012. In the intervening years there have been many browsers released. The last browser we officially stopped supporting was Firefox 2.0, and it’s time to review the list of browsers again.
We periodically review the list of supported browsers as the more changes there are between the oldest version of a browser that we support and the most recent, the harder it is for us to add new features and maintain those that already exist.</description></item><item><title>A Note About the Cybervillains SSL Certificate</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-note-about-the-cybervillains-ssl-certificate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-note-about-the-cybervillains-ssl-certificate/</guid><description>If you&amp;#8217;re using Selenium RC to test websites hosted on a secure site (accessed using a URL starting with HTTPS), we strongly recommend that you upgrade to Selenium 2.19. This is because the Cybervillains certificate in previous versions will expire soon, and has been replaced in 2.19 with an updated one.
Our thanks to Patrick Lightbody, Ivan De Marino and Mark Watson and Neustar for taking providing the new certificate and the patch!</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium 2.19: the Prancing Unicorn release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-19-the-prancing-unicorn-release/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-19-the-prancing-unicorn-release/</guid><description>You might be pleased to hear that Selenium 2.19 has been released (download it from here!). There’s one big user facing changing that we’d like to tell you about: the webdriver-backed selenium can now be used in supported languages.
By providing this capability, it’s possible to migrate from RC to the WebDriver APIs without rewriting all your tests in one fell swoop (which must be a Good Thing, right?) An example of how to use it in Python would be:</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.16 Released: Welcome to 2012!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-2-16-released-welcome-to-2012/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-2-16-released-welcome-to-2012/</guid><description>It’s been a while since we last blogged about a Selenium release. Since the release of 2.0, we’ve been attempting to give you a fresh and shiny Selenium release every week (though, in reality, we’re managing to get you one every 10 days on average). This allows you to pick the version that’s most suitable for you and your teams, but provides a route for quick feedback on how we’re doing.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium Conf ’12</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/announcing-selenium-conf-12/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/announcing-selenium-conf-12/</guid><description>The community around Selenium is the thing that really makes the Selenium project special. Last year, we held the first official Selenium Conference in San Francisco, and it was both great fun and a huge success. It is therefore with great pleasure that we are announcing Selenium Conf ’12! It’ll be taking place in London from the 16th to the 18th April, and we’re really looking forward to seeing you all there!</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.9 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-9-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-9-released/</guid><description>We’re pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.9. As well as improving the stability of Grid under high loads, we’ve added an experimental (and temporary!) feature that allows the Firefox driver to use a different mechanism for determining when a page is loaded. This is designed to handle the case where the driver appears to hang, as it’s waiting for all incoming requests to complete before continuing. How to enable this mode is listed in the changelog.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.8 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-8-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-8-released/</guid><description>In keeping with our (roughly) weekly releases, Selenium 2.8 was released today (and on Maven too), with a *huge* list of bug-fixes! As well as improved stability, if you’re using the Java API, this release adds the ability to upload files to a RemoteWebDriver server (see RemoteWebDriver.setFileDetector (http://selenium.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/docs/api/java/org/openqa/selenium/remote/RemoteWebDriver.html#setFileDetector(org.openqa.selenium.remote.FileDetector))).
Particular thanks have to go out to our two newest committers, Alexei Barancev and Ajay Kemparaj, for the copious bug-fixes they’ve contributed!</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.6 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-6-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-6-released/</guid><description>If you’ve been watching this blog carefully you’ll have noticed that the last release announcement we made was for 2.3, so it may come as a surprise that we’re announcing that 2.6 has been released (even on Maven!). Don’t worry: 2.4 and 2.5 were released on time and without muss or fuss. 2.6, on the other hand has been almost three weeks brewing.
Selenium 2.6 introduces a raft of improvements and stability fixes.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.3 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-3-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-3-released/</guid><description>Continuing our new tradition of weekly releases, we’re very pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.3. The release notes for this version are pretty slim:
Better detection of clickable areas in Firefox. Merge of Google-contributed code into the underlying javascript libraries used by the drivers. We’ve also fixed bugs, one of which was being a nuisance for users of IBM’s JRE. The complete changelog can be found in the zipped downloads or in our source tree (http://selenium.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.2 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-2-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-2-released/</guid><description>The feedback from the last release was heard loud and clear: little and often it is!
We’re proud to announce the release of Selenium 2.2. What’s new this time? For many users, this is simply a bug fix release as there are no new major features. One thing you might appreciate is better exceptions (http://selenium.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/docs/api/java/org/openqa/selenium/IllegalLocatorException.html) being thrown when xpath searches return something other than a web element when using the WebDriver APIs, and we’re continuing to tweak the emulation of user events.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.1 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-1-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-1-released/</guid><description>Now that Selenium 2 has been released, one of the goals of the project is to provide regular updates to our users and the community. The aim is for these updates to be small and manageable, incrementally addressing issues and problems raised by you. Selenium 2.1, which is launched today, marks the first of these regular, small releases.
Selenium 2.1 is largely focused on improving Grid with a host of minor improvements including better tracking of “orphaned” browser instances.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0: Out Now!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0/</guid><description>We are very, very pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.0. If you’ve been waiting for a stable release since 1.0.3, now’s the chance to update. And if you do, what will you find?
For users of Selenium 1, this is a drop-in replacement. You’ll find support for modern browsers such as Firefox 5 and IE 9, as well as a wealth of bug fixes and stability improvements. That’s one reason to update, but what other reasons are there?</description></item><item><title>Selenium IDE 1.0.12 – now with Firefox 5 support</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-ide-1-0-12-firefox-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-ide-1-0-12-firefox-5/</guid><description>Last week we quietly released Selenium IDE 1.0.12 on the website. It has Firefox 5 support along with other improvements. See the release notes and unofficial announcement. Download it here or ask Firefox to check for plugins updates.
And for those who did not download 1.0.11 (it was not pushed through the update system) you will want to read about the formatter change that landed.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0rc3: The “Next One’s The Big One” Release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc3-the-next-ones-the-big-one-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc3-the-next-ones-the-big-one-release/</guid><description>When we pushed the 2.0rc1 live, we really hoped that the next release would be 2.0 final. We very quickly got some feedback that encouraged us to push a 2.0rc2. Now, after just under three weeks, we’re launching a third and final release candidate. You can download it from the Selenium HQ site or directly from Google Code.
We think we’ve addressed many of the common issues, added some polish and added a host of bug fixes and minor changes, and we hope to hear your feedback!</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0rc2: The Better Working Release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc2-the-better-working-release/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc2-the-better-working-release/</guid><description>You win some and you lose some. We’d been really pleased to get Selenium 2.0rc1 out, so we were pretty disappointed to hear that some of you were running into problems with the Java version of the IE driver not launching IE sometimes. That’s definitely not good, so we fixed the problems and have released Selenium 2.0rc2. It’s the same as rc1, but with fewer problems 🙂
We’re still very keen to hear your feedback!</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0rc1: The Grid Release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc1-the-grid-release/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc1-the-grid-release/</guid><description>We’re very happy to announce the first Release Candidate for Selenium 2, available for Java, C#, Ruby and Python. The API has been stabilised and the functionality needed for the final 2.0 release is mostly in. We’re going to be working hard to get there as soon as possible, but now’s the perfect time to test the waters and provide us with any feedback you may have! Grab the downloads from the site!</description></item><item><title>Selenium IDE 1.0.11 – Now with Firefox 4 Support!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-ide-1-0-11-now-with-firefox-4-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-ide-1-0-11-now-with-firefox-4-support/</guid><description>We know that you have been waiting eagerly for this release and you have to wait no more. Selenium IDE 1.0.11 is now here and you can get it from the seleniumhq download site. The update will also be pushed to you automatically over the next couple days.
Other things of note around this release
•Release Notes
•Where to log bugs
•Welcome Selenium IDE 1.0.11 (with Firefox 4 support)</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0b3: The Next Gen Browser Release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0b3-the-next-gen-browser-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0b3-the-next-gen-browser-release/</guid><description>It’s been about 5 weeks since the release of beta 2, so we’re very pleased to announce that Selenium 2.0b3 has just been released simultaneously for Java, .Net, Ruby and Python. You can download it from Selenium HQ or from the Google Code site. This release focused on providing excellent support for the next generation of browsers, particularly IE 9 and Firefox 4, and we think you’ll like what you’ll find.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0b2 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0b2-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0b2-released/</guid><description>We’ve just released Selenium 2.0b2. If you’re the impatient sort who loves to have the latest and greatest, head over to the download site and get it while it’s hot. If you’re a Python user, then all you need to do is a simple “pip install -U selenium”. Ruby users can, as ever, simply run “gem install selenium-webdriver”. Maven users need to wait just a little bit longer: we’re going to be checking the release in ASAP.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Joins the Software Freedom Conservancy</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-joins-the-software-freedom-conservancy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-joins-the-software-freedom-conservancy/</guid><description>It doesn’t seem that long ago that we announced on the mailing list that the Selenium project planned to join the Software Freedom Conservancy. I’m very pleased to announce that as of Friday, 21st January, our application was approved. We’re now under the aegis of the SFC.
From most people’s perspective, this won’t make much difference: you’ll still be able to view the documentation and download the latest versions of Selenium from Selenium HQ.</description></item><item><title>2.0b1 and Maven</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/2-0b1-and-maven/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/2-0b1-and-maven/</guid><description>If you’re using Maven and the 2.0b1 release of Selenium, you may be running into some problems getting maven to pick up your tests. The underlying problem is that selenium contains support classes for both JUnit and TestNG. The solution is to add this to your pom.xml
&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.seleniumhq.selenium&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;selenium&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;2.0b1&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;exclusions&amp;gt; &amp;lt;exclusion&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.testng&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;testng&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/exclusion&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/exclusions&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf is coming… get your proposals in!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-conf-is-coming-get-your-proposals-in/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-conf-is-coming-get-your-proposals-in/</guid><description>It has been mentioned at and hinted upon a couple times in the Smattering posts, but nothing has ‘officially’ been mentioned here, so it is time we fix that.
The first Selenium Conf is a go!
The logistics are set and we’re starting to sort out the program. Here is what you need to know. Right. Now.
When – Monday, April 4 – Wednesday, April 6 Where – Marines Memorial Club and Hotel Why – Its about darn time… This is a community driven event, though our friends at Sauce Labs are doing a lot of the leg work on the facilities (and food!</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0 beta 1 Release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0-beta-1-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0-beta-1-release/</guid><description>We recently released the first of the betas for Selenium 2. It’s available for Java, C# and Ruby. If you’ve been holding off trying Selenium 2 because of the alpha label, then the biggest improvement you’ll see is with the new WebDriver APIs, but there’s a lot more!
A promise of relatively stable APIs For Firefox only right now, an API for dealing with alerts, prompts and confirms (http://selenium.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/docs/api/java/org/openqa/selenium/WebDriver.TargetLocator.html#alert()). A brand new IE driver.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conference Survey</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-conference-survey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-conference-survey/</guid><description>Great news! Thanks to the initiative of our friends at Sauce Labs, we’re finally ready to host the first-ever Selenium Conference. We’re still working out a lot of the details, but so far we’ve decided this first conference will be sometime in April and hosted in San Francisco.
In order to figure out the rest of the details, we’re looking for feedback from the Selenium user community. Please take a moment to fill out the following survey.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0a6 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a6-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a6-released/</guid><description>We are extremely pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.0a6! Head over to the downloads page to get it while it’s hot, or wait just a little bit longer for it to appear in a maven repo near you. The .Net version will also be updated soon too, and the python and ruby libraries have been having smaller, more frequent releases all this time.
You’ll be pleased to hear that the Selenium 1.</description></item><item><title>Going Atomic: How</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/going-atomic-how/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/going-atomic-how/</guid><description>This is the second of my technical posts. Again, if you’re interested in the internal workings of Selenium 2, then please skip straight to something else. If you’re interested in how and why we made some of the technical decisions on the project, keep reading….
We left our intrepid heroes in a tight spot: they’d decided to write a shared library of code, to be used by the various webdriver implementations and selenium core, but the requirements for doing this seemed to be at odds with it actually happening.</description></item><item><title>Going Atomic: Why?</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/going-atomic-why/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/going-atomic-why/</guid><description>This is the first in a series of technical posts by me about the internals of Selenium WebDriver. If you’re not interested in technical nitty-gritty, then feel free to step away now.
Still here? Excellent.
Let’s take a step back to just before the Selenium and WebDriver projects merged. There were, very obviously, two separate codebases. Looking closer and with a slightly different perspective, there were more than this. We used the test suites for webdriver to define the behaviour for multiple, largely independent, driver codebases.</description></item><item><title>How to use Selenium 2 with Maven</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/how-to-use-selenium-2-with-maven/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/how-to-use-selenium-2-with-maven/</guid><description>There are several ways to use Selenium 2:
If you don’t have Selenium 1.x legacy code, you might want to directly use on of the new WebDriver implemenations like ChromeDriver, HtmlUnitDriver, FirefoxDriver, or InternetExplorerDriver which provide a nice, small and easy to learn API. If you have Selenium 1.x legacy code, you can still use the well known DefaultSelenium class or the new WebDriverBackedSelenium, which extends DefaultSelenium but uses one of the WebDriver implementations internally.</description></item><item><title>The Current Status of Selenium 1 and Selenium 2</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/the-current-status-of-selenium-1-and-selenium-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/the-current-status-of-selenium-1-and-selenium-2/</guid><description>In the beginning there was Se1, and it was good. But it could have been better — in ways that WebDriver was starting to be good at. Thus the brilliant idea was hatched to merge the two projects.
And then the confusion began. Let’s see if I can start to address some of it via a ficticious conversation that consolidates the Se-user list and #selenium irc channel.
There are a couple annoying bugs in Se-RC 1.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0a5 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a5-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a5-released/</guid><description>I’m pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.0a5, available for immediate download. This release brings a host of changes under the hood, and represents the efforts of many contributors. Highlights include:
New interfaces (http://selenium.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/docs/api/java/org/openqa/selenium/html5/package-frame.html) for dealing with HTML 5 elements. An API for implicit waits (http://selenium.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/docs/api/java/org/openqa/selenium/WebDriver.Timeouts.html): quietly waiting until an element is present before continuing with a test. You can use them like this: driver.manage().timeouts().implicitlyWait(15, TimeUnit.SECONDS) A revamped Firefox driver.</description></item><item><title>Selenium IDE – Looking back and looking forward</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-looking-back-and-looking-forward/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-looking-back-and-looking-forward/</guid><description>Its been around six months and three releases since I took the reins of Selenium-IDE. The fundamental change in that time has been the adoption of a plugin model like the fine folks over that Firebug. (We’re also self-hosting it which is big from a project internals perspective.)
Right now, you can add custom user-extensions and formatters, but in the very near future you will be able to add location strategies as well.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Grid 1.0.8 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-8-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-8-released/</guid><description>We’re pleased to announce the release of Selenium Grid 1.0.8. This release fixes multithreaded issues with the Selenium Grid hub that appeared randomly under heavy load. If you’ve ever seen a log message about HttpClient being accessed by multiple threads, you definitely want to upgrade. Even if you haven’t, this release is highly recommended for all.
You can download it now or view the changelog. The list of changes is:</description></item><item><title>Selenium IDE 1.0.7 – Now with Drag-and-Drop!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-1-0-7-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-1-0-7-released/</guid><description>So its a month later than planned, but Selenium IDE 1.0.7 is now available. The delay was due to some internal build changes and not code, but one of the code changes that is there more than makes up for the delay.
That’s right, drag-and-drop has finally arrived to Se-IDE — though credit lies with Jérémy Hérault for implementing it.
Oh, and if you are Swedish, there is now a localization for you.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Grid 1.0.7 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-7-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-7-released/</guid><description>Following up on the Selenium Grid 1.0.6 release, which was mostly a bug fix release, we’re pleased to announce the release of Selenium Grid 1.0.7. This is another bug fix release that focuses primarily on how Selenium Grid handles browser sessions.
You can download it now or view the changelog. The list of changes are:
Hub now instructs remote controls to shutdown a session if the hub is going to remove it due to being idle for too long Added ability to specify timeout period when waiting for remote controls to become available.</description></item><item><title>The Future of Selenium Grid</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/the-future-of-selenium-grid/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/the-future-of-selenium-grid/</guid><description>As you likely know by now, after years of stewardship Philippe has stepped down as maintainer of Selenium Grid and has named me the new maintainer. In this post, I hope to address the most immediate questions about what this means for the future of Selenium Grid.
Background I realize many of you may not know who I am. I’ve been using Selenium in some capacity for close to five years now.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0a3 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a3-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a3-released/</guid><description>Selenium 2.0a3 has been released and can be downloaded from the Selenium project site. This is a major update to 2.0 and all users are encouraged to update. The new features include:
An improved remote protocol. Updating the version of HtmlUnit used to 2.7. Improved support for simulating user interactions with the browser via native events on Linux. Better support for Firefox 3.6. Bug fixes The .Net, Python and Ruby bindings will be updated soon, as will the maven artefacts.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Grid 1.0.6 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-6-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-6-released/</guid><description>Following up on the Selenium Grid 1.0.5 release, which added self-healing features to ease grid management, we’re pleased to announce the release of Selenium Grid 1.0.6. This is a bug fix release for 1.0.5 with some minor new additions.
You can download it now or view the changelog. The summary of changes are:
Fixed some concurrent modification issues that may have resulted in NullPointerExceptions Fixed issue with shutting down workers with Rakefile Added PID file support for hub and worker started via Rakefile, making it easier to use a process monitor such as monit In case you missed the announcement, Philippe is no longer maintaining Selenium Grid.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 1.0.3 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-1-0-3-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-1-0-3-released/</guid><description>Hot off the heals of 1.0.2, we’re releasing Selenium Remote Control 1.0.3. You can download it now (http://selenium.googlecode.com/files/selenium-remote-control-1.0.3.zip).
There is no functional difference between this version and 1.0.2, other than it is packaged up a little nicer and we’ve clarified the relationship between selenium-server and the client drivers. That is: we are not releasing new client drivers with future 1.x releases. The reason is that we locked down the API in version 1.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 1.0.2 Released: Firefox 3.6 and Snow Leopard Support</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-1-0-2-release-firefox-3-6-and-snow-leopard-support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-1-0-2-release-firefox-3-6-and-snow-leopard-support/</guid><description>Today we’re happy to announce that Selenium Remote Control 1.0.2 has been released. While most of our efforts are on Selenium 2.0, we understand that there are millions of Selenium users that still need the 1.x line supported. That’s why we’ve said from the start that our goal is make 2.x 100% backwards compatible with 1.x. And that’s why we’re releasing a new version of Selenium RC today.
Download it here (http://selenium.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the official Selenium blog!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/welcome-to-the-official-selenium-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/welcome-to-the-official-selenium-blog/</guid><description>Since we moved away from Clearspace for our forums, it’s time we also did the same for our blogging platform. As such, the new location for the official Selenium blog will now be:
http://seleniumhq.wordpress.com
We hope to be much better about posting news, tips, and tricks here going forward.</description></item></channel></rss>