<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Legacy on Documentation Selenium</title>
    <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/fr/legacy_docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Legacy on Documentation Selenium</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>2013-{year}</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/fr/legacy_docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 1 (Selenium RC)</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/fr/legacy_docs/selenium_rc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/fr/legacy_docs/selenium_rc/</guid>
      <description>Page being translated from English to French. Do you speak French? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
 Introduction Selenium RC was the main Selenium project for a long time, before the WebDriver/Selenium merge brought up Selenium 2, a more powerful tool. It is worth to highlight that Selenium 1 is not supported anymore.
How Selenium RC Works First, we will describe how the components of Selenium RC operate and the role each plays in running your test scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from RC to WebDriver</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/fr/legacy_docs/migrating_from_rc_to_webdriver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/fr/legacy_docs/migrating_from_rc_to_webdriver/</guid>
      <description>Comment migrer vers Selenium WebDriver Une question fréquente lors de l&amp;rsquo;adoption de Selenium 2 est la bonne chose à faire lors de l&amp;rsquo;ajout de nouveaux tests à un ensemble de tests existant? Utilisateurs nouveaux dans le Le framework peut commencer par utiliser les nouvelles API WebDriver pour écrire leurs tests. Mais qu&amp;rsquo;en est-il des utilisateurs qui ont déjà des suites de tests existants? Ce guide est conçu pour montrer comment migrer vos tests existants vers les nouvelles API, permettant à tous les nouveaux tests d&#39;être écrits en utilisant les nouvelles fonctionnalités offertes par WebDriver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Runner HTML</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/fr/legacy_docs/html-runner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/fr/legacy_docs/html-runner/</guid>
      <description>Selenium HTML-runner permet d&amp;rsquo;exécuter des Test Suites depuis la ligne de commande. Les Tests Suites sont des exports HTML depuis Selenium IDE ou autre outil compatible.
Informations générales  Les combinaisons de version de geckodriver / firefox / selenium-html-runner sont importantes. Il doit y avoir une matrice de compatibilité quelque part. selenium-html-runner exécute seulement des Test Suites (et non pas des Test Case, comme un export de Monitis Transaction Monitor). Assurez-vous de vous y conformer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legacy Selenium IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/fr/legacy_docs/selenium_ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/fr/legacy_docs/selenium_ide/</guid>
      <description>Page being translated from English to French. Do you speak French? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
 Introduction The Selenium-IDE (Integrated Development Environment) is the tool you use to develop your Selenium test cases. It’s an easy-to-use Firefox plug-in and is generally the most efficient way to develop test cases. It also contains a context menu that allows you to first select a UI element from the browser’s currently displayed page and then select from a list of Selenium commands with parameters pre-defined according to the context of the selected UI element.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>