<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Selenium Browser Automation Project on Documentation for Selenium</title>
    <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Selenium Browser Automation Project on Documentation for Selenium</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>2013-{year}</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Browsers</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/getting_started_with_webdriver/browsers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/getting_started_with_webdriver/browsers/</guid>
      <description>Consumer browsers The Selenium framework officially supports the following browsers:
   Browser Maintainer Versions Supported     Chrome Chromium All versions   Firefox Mozilla 54 and newer   Internet Explorer Selenium 6 and newer   Opera Opera Chromium / Presto 10.5 and newer   Safari Apple 10 and newer    Specialized browsers There is also a set of specialized browsers out there typically used in development environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Captchas</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/captchas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/captchas/</guid>
      <description>CAPTCHA, short for Completely Automated Public Turing test to tell Computers and Humans Apart, is explicitly designed to prevent automation, so do not try! There are two primary strategies to get around CAPTCHA checks:
 Disable CAPTCHAs in your test environment Add a hook to allow tests to bypass the CAPTCHA  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright and attributions</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/front_matter/copyright_and_attributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/front_matter/copyright_and_attributions/</guid>
      <description>The Documentation of Selenium Copyright &amp;copy; 2013-2020 , Software Freedom Conservancy.
Every effort has been made to make this documentation as complete and as accurate as possible, but no warranty or fitness is implied. The information provided is on an “as-is” basis. The authors and the publisher shall have neither liability nor responsibility to any person or entity with respect to any loss or damages arising from the information contained in this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Selenium libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/selenium_installation/installing_selenium_libraries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/selenium_installation/installing_selenium_libraries/</guid>
      <description>First you need to install the Selenium bindings for your automation project. The installation process for libraries depends on the language you choose to use.
Java Installation of Selenium libraries for Java can be done using Maven. Add the selenium-java dependency in your project pom.xml:
&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.seleniumhq.selenium&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;selenium-java&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;3.X&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; The selenium-java dependency supports running your automation project with all Selenium supported browsers. If you want to run tests only in a specific browser, you can add the dependency for that browser in your pom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page object models</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/page_object_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/page_object_models/</guid>
      <description>Page Object is a Design Pattern which has become popular in test automation for enhancing test maintenance and reducing code duplication. A page object is an object-oriented class that serves as an interface to a page of your AUT. The tests then use the methods of this page object class whenever they need to interact with the UI of that page. The benefit is that if the UI changes for the page, the tests themselves don’t need to change, only the code within the page object needs to change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purposes and main functionalities</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/purposes_and_main_functionalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/purposes_and_main_functionalities/</guid>
      <description> Central entry point for all tests Management and control of the nodes / environment where the browsers run Scaling Running tests in parallel Cross platform testing Load balancing  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick tour</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/getting_started/quick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/getting_started/quick/</guid>
      <description>Selenium is not just one tool or API but it composes many tools.
WebDriver If you are beginning with desktop website or mobile website test automation, then you are going to be using WebDriver APIs. WebDriver uses browser automation APIs provided by browser vendors to control browser and run tests. This is as if a real user is operating the browser. Since WebDriver does not require its API to be compiled with application code, it is not intrusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote WebDriver server</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/remote_webdriver/remote_webdriver_server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/remote_webdriver/remote_webdriver_server/</guid>
      <description>The server will always run on the machine with the browser you want to test. The server can be used either from the command line or through code configuration.
Starting the server from the command line Once you have downloaded selenium-server-standalone-{VERSION}.jar, place it on the computer with the browser you want to test. Then, from the directory with the jar, run the following:
java -jar selenium-server-standalone-{VERSION}.jar Considerations for running the server The caller is expected to terminate each session properly, calling either Selenium#stop() or WebDriver#quit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 1 (Selenium RC)</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/legacy_docs/selenium_rc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/legacy_docs/selenium_rc/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Selenium RC was the main Selenium project for a long time, before the WebDriver/Selenium merge brought up Selenium 2, a more powerful tool. It is worth to highlight that Selenium 1 is not supported anymore.
How Selenium RC Works First, we will describe how the components of Selenium RC operate and the role each plays in running your test scripts.
RC Components Selenium RC components are:
 The Selenium Server which launches and kills browsers, interprets and runs the Selenese commands passed from the test program, and acts as an HTTP proxy, intercepting and verifying HTTP messages passed between the browser and the AUT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shared capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/driver_idiosyncrasies/shared_capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/driver_idiosyncrasies/shared_capabilities/</guid>
      <description>In-order to create a new session by Selenium WebDriver, local end should provide the basic capabilities to remote end. The remote end uses the same set of capabilities to create a session and describes the current session features.
WebDriver provides capabilities that each remote end will/should support the implementation. Following are the capabilities that WebDriver supports:
browserName: This capability is used to set the browserName for a given session. If the specified browser is not installed at the remote end, the session creation will fail</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Selenium project and tools</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/the_selenium_project_and_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/the_selenium_project_and_tools/</guid>
      <description>Selenium controls web browsers Selenium is many things but at its core, it is a toolset for web browser automation that uses the best techniques available to remotely control browser instances and emulate a user&amp;rsquo;s interaction with the browser.
It allows users to simulate common activities performed by end-users; entering text into fields, selecting drop-down values and checking boxes, and clicking links in documents. It also provides many other controls such as mouse movement, arbitrary JavaScript execution, and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the components</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/understanding_the_components/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/understanding_the_components/</guid>
      <description>Building a test suite using WebDriver will require you to understand and effectively use a number of different components. As with everything in software, different people use different terms for the same idea. Below is a breakdown of how terms are used in this description.
Terminology  API: Application Programming Interface. This is the set of &amp;ldquo;commands&amp;rdquo; you use to manipulate WebDriver. Library: A code module which contains the APIs and the code necessary to implement them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Components of a Grid</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/components_of_a_grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/components_of_a_grid/</guid>
      <description>Hub  Intermediary and manager Accepts requests to run tests Takes instructions from client and executes them remotely on the nodes Manages threads  A Hub is a central point where all your tests are sent. Each Selenium Grid consists of exactly one hub. The hub needs to be reachable from the respective clients (i.e. CI server, Developer machine etc.) The hub will connect one or more nodes that tests will be delegated to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domain specific language</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/domain_specific_language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/domain_specific_language/</guid>
      <description>A domain specific language (DSL) is a system which provides the user with an expressive means of solving a problem. It allows a user to interact with the system on their terms – not just programmer-speak.
Your users, in general, do not care how your site looks. They do not care about the decoration, animations, or graphics. They want to use your system to push their new employees through the process with minimal difficulty; they want to book travel to Alaska; they want to configure and buy unicorns at a discount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driver requirements</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/driver_requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/driver_requirements/</guid>
      <description>Through WebDriver, Selenium supports all major browsers on the market such as Chrom(ium), Firefox, Internet Explorer, Opera, and Safari. Where possible, WebDriver drives the browser using the browser&amp;rsquo;s built-in support for automation, although not all browsers have official support for remote control.
WebDriver&amp;rsquo;s aim is to emulate a real user&amp;rsquo;s interaction with the browser as closely as possible. This is possible at varying levels in different browsers. For more details on the different driver idiosyncracies, please see Driver Idiosyncracies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driver specific capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/driver_idiosyncrasies/driver_specific_capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/driver_idiosyncrasies/driver_specific_capabilities/</guid>
      <description>Firefox Define Capabilities using FirefoxOptions FirefoxOptions is the new way to define capabilities for the Firefox browser and should generally be used in preference to DesiredCapabilities.
Java Python C# Ruby JavaScript Kotlin FirefoxOptions options = new FirefoxOptions(); options.addPreference(&amp;#34;network.proxy.type&amp;#34;, 0); driver = new RemoteWebDriver(options);   from selenium.webdriver.firefox.options import Options options = Options() options.headless = True driver = webdriver.Firefox(options=options)   var options = new FirefoxOptions(); options.Proxy.Kind = ProxyKind.Direct; var driver = new FirefoxDriver(options);   require &amp;#39;selenium-webdriver&amp;#39; opts = Selenium::WebDriver::Firefox::Options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File downloads</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/file_downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/file_downloads/</guid>
      <description>Whilst it is possible to start a download by clicking a link with a browser under Selenium&amp;rsquo;s control, the API does not expose download progress, making it less than ideal for testing downloaded files. This is because downloading files is not considered an important aspect of emulating user interaction with the web platform. Instead, find the link using Selenium (and any required cookies) and pass it to a HTTP request library like libcurl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing WebDriver binaries</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/selenium_installation/installing_webdriver_binaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/selenium_installation/installing_webdriver_binaries/</guid>
      <description>To execute your project and control the browser you need to have browser-specific WebDriver binaries installed.
Download the WebDriver binary supported by your browser and place it in the System PATH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from RC to WebDriver</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/legacy_docs/migrating_from_rc_to_webdriver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/legacy_docs/migrating_from_rc_to_webdriver/</guid>
      <description>How to Migrate to Selenium WebDriver A common question when adopting Selenium 2 is what&amp;rsquo;s the correct thing to do when adding new tests to an existing set of tests? Users who are new to the framework can begin by using the new WebDriver APIs for writing their tests. But what of users who already have suites of existing tests? This guide is designed to demonstrate how to migrate your existing tests to the new APIs, allowing all new tests to be written using the new features offered by WebDriver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On test automation</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/on_test_automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/on_test_automation/</guid>
      <description>First, start by asking yourself whether or not you really need to use a browser. Odds are that, at some point, if you are working on a complex web application, you will need to open a browser and actually test it.
Functional end-user tests such as Selenium tests are expensive to run, however. Furthermore, they typically require substantial infrastructure to be in place to be run effectively. It is a good rule to always ask yourself if what you want to test can be done using more lightweight test approaches such as unit tests or with a lower-level approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote WebDriver client</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/remote_webdriver/remote_webdriver_client/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/remote_webdriver/remote_webdriver_client/</guid>
      <description>To run a remote WebDriver client, we first need to connect to the RemoteWebDriver. We do this by pointing the URL to the address of the server running our tests. In order to customize our configuration, we set desired capabilities. Below is an example of instantiating a remote WebDriver object pointing to our remote web server, www.example.com, running our tests on Firefox.
Java Python C# Ruby JavaScript Kotlin FirefoxOptions firefoxOptions = new FirefoxOptions(); WebDriver driver = new RemoteWebDriver(new URL(&amp;#34;http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third party drivers and plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/getting_started_with_webdriver/third_party_drivers_and_plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/getting_started_with_webdriver/third_party_drivers_and_plugins/</guid>
      <description>Selenium can be extended through the use of plugins. Here are a number of plugins created and maintained by third parties. For more information on how to create your own plugin or have it listed, consult the docs.
Please note that these plugins are not supported, maintained, hosted, or endorsed by the Selenium project. In addition, be advised that the plugins listed below are not necessarily licensed under the Apache License v.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typographical conventions</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/front_matter/typographical_conventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/front_matter/typographical_conventions/</guid>
      <description>Capitalisation of titles One should avoid title capitalisation, such as A Very Fine Heading, and instead go for A very fine heading. Gratutious capitalisation, or title case, often show a misunderstanding of – or a disregard for – orthographic conventions. We prefer what is known as sentence case, with a single initial capital to start headers.
Line length When editing the documentation’s source, which is written in plain HTML, limit your line lengths to around 72 characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with colours</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/support_packages/working_with_colours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/support_packages/working_with_colours/</guid>
      <description>You will occasionally want to validate the colour of something as part of your tests; the problem is that colour definitions on the web are not constant. Would it not be nice if there was an easy way to compare a HEX representation of a colour with a RGB representation of a colour, or a RGBA representation of a colour with a HSLA representation of a colour?
Worry not. There is a solution: the Color class!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser manipulation</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/browser_manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/browser_manipulation/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Ruby is not installed by default on Windows. Download the latest version and run the installer. You can leave all settings at default values, except at the Installation Destination and Optional Tasks screen check where you need to check the Add Ruby executables to your PATH checkbox. To drive any browser, you have to install selenium-webdriver Ruby gem. To install it, open command prompt and type this:
gem install selenium-webdriver Or, if you use Bundler, add this line to your application&amp;rsquo;s Gemfile:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating application state</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/generating_application_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/generating_application_state/</guid>
      <description>Selenium should not be used to prepare a test case. All repetitive actions and preparations for a test case, should be done through other methods. For example, most web UIs have authentication (e.g. a login form). Eliminating logging in via web browser before every test will improve both the speed and stability of the test. A method should be created to gain access to the AUT* (e.g. using an API to login and set a cookie).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML runner</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/legacy_docs/html-runner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/legacy_docs/html-runner/</guid>
      <description>Selenium HTML-runner allows you to run Test Suites from a command line. Test Suites are HTML exports from Selenium IDE or campatible tools.
Common information  Combination of releases of geckodriver / firefox / selenium-html-runner matters. There might be a software compatibility matrix somewhere. selenium-html-runner runs only Test Suite (not Test Case - for example an export from Monitis Transaction Monitor). Be sure you comply with this. For Linux users with no DISPLAY - you need to start html-runner with Virtual display (search for xvfb)  Example Linux environment Install / download following software packages:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP response codes</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/http_response_codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/http_response_codes/</guid>
      <description>For some browser configurations in Selenium RC, Selenium acted as a proxy between the browser and the site being automated. This meant that all browser traffic passed through Selenium could be captured or manipulated. The captureNetworkTraffic() method purported to capture all of the network traffic between the browser and the site being automated, including HTTP response codes.
Selenium WebDriver is a completely different approach to browser automation, preferring to act more like a user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Standalone server</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/selenium_installation/installing_standalone_server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/selenium_installation/installing_standalone_server/</guid>
      <description>If you plan to use Grid then you should download the selenium-server-standalone JAR file. All the components are available via selenium-server. The standalone JAR contains everything, including the remote Selenium server and the client-side bindings. This means that if you use the selenium-server-standalone jar in your project, you do not have to add selenium-java or a browser specific jar.
&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.seleniumhq.selenium&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;selenium-server&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;3.X&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locating elements</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/getting_started_with_webdriver/locating_elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/getting_started_with_webdriver/locating_elements/</guid>
      <description>Locating one element One of the most fundamental techniques to learn when using WebDriver is how to find elements on the page. WebDriver offers a number of built-in selector types, amongst them finding an element by its ID attribute:
Java Python C# Ruby JavaScript Kotlin WebElement cheese = driver.findElement(By.id(&amp;#34;cheese&amp;#34;));   driver.find_element(By.ID, &amp;#34;cheese&amp;#34;)   IWebElement element = driver.FindElement(By.Id(&amp;#34;cheese&amp;#34;));   cheese = driver.find_element(id: &amp;#39;cheese&amp;#39;)   const cheese = driver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up your own Grid</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/setting_up_your_own_grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/setting_up_your_own_grid/</guid>
      <description>To use Selenium Grid, you need to maintain your own infrastructure for the nodes. As this can be a cumbersome and time intense effort, many organizations use IaaS providers such as Amazon EC2 and Google Compute to provide this infrastructure.
Other options include using providers such as Sauce Labs or Testing Bot who provide a Selenium Grid as a service in the cloud. It is certainly possible to also run nodes on your own hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of testing</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/types_of_testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/types_of_testing/</guid>
      <description>Acceptance testing This type of testing is done to determine if a feature or system meets the customer expectations and requirements. This type of testing generally involves the customer&amp;rsquo;s cooperation or feedback, being a validation activity that answers the question:
 Are we building the right product?.
 For web applications, the automation of this testing can be done directly with Selenium by simulating user expected behaviour. This simulation could be done by record/playback or through the different supported languages as explained in this documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with select elements</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/support_packages/working_with_select_elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/support_packages/working_with_select_elements/</guid>
      <description>Select elements can require quite a bit of boiler plate code to automate. To reduce this, and make your tests cleaner, there is a Select class in the Selenium support package. To use it, you will need the following import statement:
Java Python C# Ruby JavaScript Kotlin import org.openqa.selenium.support.ui.Select;   from selenium.webdriver.support.select import Select   using OpenQA.Selenium.Support.UI   include Selenium::WebDriver::Support   // We don&amp;#39;t have a JavaScript code sample yet - Help us out and raise a PR    import org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/about_this_documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/introduction/about_this_documentation/</guid>
      <description>These docs, like the code itself, are maintained 100% by volunteers within the Selenium community. Many have been using it since its inception, but many more have only been using it for a short while, and have given their time to help improve the onboarding experience for new users.
If there is an issue with the documentation, we want to know! The best way to communicate an issue is to visit https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gmail, email and Facebook logins</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/gmail_email_and_facebook_logins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/gmail_email_and_facebook_logins/</guid>
      <description>For multiple reasons, logging into sites like Gmail and Facebook using WebDriver is not recommended. Aside from being against the usage terms for these sites (where you risk having the account shut down), it is slow and unreliable.
The ideal practice is to use the APIs that email providers offer, or in the case of Facebook the developer tools service which exposes an API for creating test accounts, friends and so forth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legacy Selenium IDE</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/legacy_docs/selenium_ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/legacy_docs/selenium_ide/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Selenium-IDE (Integrated Development Environment) is the tool you use to develop your Selenium test cases. It’s an easy-to-use Firefox plug-in and is generally the most efficient way to develop test cases. It also contains a context menu that allows you to first select a UI element from the browser’s currently displayed page and then select from a list of Selenium commands with parameters pre-defined according to the context of the selected UI element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mock external services</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/mock_external_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/mock_external_services/</guid>
      <description>Eliminating the dependencies on external services will greatly improve the speed and stability of your tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mouse actions in detail</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/support_packages/mouse_and_keyboard_actions_in_detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/support_packages/mouse_and_keyboard_actions_in_detail/</guid>
      <description>Mouse represents a mouse event. Mouse actions are performed by using low-level interface which allows us to provide virtualized device input action to the web browser.
clickAndHold It will move to the element and clicks (without releasing) in the middle of the given element.
Java Python C# Ruby JavaScript Kotlin import org.openqa.selenium.By; import org.openqa.selenium.WebDriver; import org.openqa.selenium.WebElement; import org.openqa.selenium.chrome.ChromeDriver; import org.openqa.selenium.interactions.Actions; public class clickAndHold { public static void main(String[] args) { WebDriver driver = new ChromeDriver(); try { // Navigate to Url  driver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performing actions on the AUT*</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/getting_started_with_webdriver/performing_actions_on_the_aut/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/getting_started_with_webdriver/performing_actions_on_the_aut/</guid>
      <description>You can set an element&amp;rsquo;s text using the sendKeys method as follows:
Java Python C# Ruby JavaScript Kotlin String name = &amp;#34;Charles&amp;#34;; driver.findElement(By.name(&amp;#34;name&amp;#34;)).sendKeys(name);   name = &amp;#34;Charles&amp;#34; driver.find_element(By.NAME, &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;).send_keys(name)   string name = &amp;#34;Charles&amp;#34;; driver.FindElement(By.Name(&amp;#34;name&amp;#34;)).SendKeys(name);   name = &amp;#34;Charles&amp;#34; driver.find_element(name: &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;).send_keys(name)   const name = &amp;#34;Charles&amp;#34;; await driver.findElement(By.name(&amp;#39;name&amp;#39;)).sendKeys(name);   val name = &amp;#34;Charles&amp;#34; driver.findElement(By.name(&amp;#34;name&amp;#34;)).sendKeys(name)     Some web applications use JavaScript libraries to add drag-and-drop functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waits</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/waits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/waits/</guid>
      <description>WebDriver can generally be said to have a blocking API. Because it is an out-of-process library that instructs the browser what to do, and because the web platform has an intrinsically asynchronous nature, WebDriver does not track the active, real-time state of the DOM. This comes with some challenges that we will discuss here.
From experience, most intermittent issues that arise from use of Selenium and WebDriver are connected to race conditions that occur between the browser and the user&amp;rsquo;s instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When to use Grid</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/when_to_use_grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/when_to_use_grid/</guid>
      <description>Generally speaking, there’s two reasons why you might want to use Grid.
 To run your tests against multiple browsers, multiple versions of browser, and browsers running on different operating systems. To reduce the time it takes for the test suite to complete a test pass.  Grid is used to speed up the execution of a test pass by using multiple machines to run tests in parallel. For example, if you have a suite of 100 tests, but you set up Grid to support 4 different machines (VMs or separate physical machines) to run those tests, your test suite will complete in (roughly) one-fourth the time as it would if you ran your tests sequentially on a single machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved reporting</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/improved_reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/improved_reporting/</guid>
      <description>Selenium is not designed to report on the status of test cases run. Taking advantage of the built-in reporting capabilities of unit test frameworks is a good start. Most unit test frameworks have reports that can generate xUnit or HTML formatted reports. xUnit reports are popular for importing results to a Continuous Integration (CI) server like Jenkins, Travis, Bamboo, etc. Here are some links for more information regarding report outputs for several languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support classes</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/support_classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/support_classes/</guid>
      <description>WebDriver support classes are provided to simplify maintaining your code. They provide a nice abstraction to make modeling HTML element(s) as domain objects easier, also providing helper methods to make using such objects easy to reason about. We will learn about:
 Locator Strategies Events LoadableComponent ThreadGuard etc.  Let&amp;rsquo;s Start:
ThreadGuard  This class is only available in the Java Binding
 ThreadGuard checks that a driver is called only from the same thread that created it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test dependency</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/test_dependency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/test_dependency/</guid>
      <description>A common idea and misconception about automated testing is regarding a specific test order. Your tests should be able to run in any order, and not rely on other tests to complete in order to be successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid sharing state</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/avoid_sharing_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/avoid_sharing_state/</guid>
      <description>Although mentioned in several places it is worth mentioning again. Ensure tests are isolated from one another.
  Do not share test data. Imagine several tests that each query the database for valid orders before picking one to perform an action on. Should two tests pick up the same order you are likely to get unexpected behaviour.
  Clean up stale data in the application that might be picked up by another test e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript alerts, prompts and confirmations</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/js_alerts_prompts_and_confirmations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/js_alerts_prompts_and_confirmations/</guid>
      <description>WebDriver provides an API for working with the three types of native popup messages offered by JavaScript. These popups are styled by the browser and offer limited customisation.
Alerts The simplest of these is referred to as an alert, which shows a custom message, and a single button which dismisses the alert, labelled in most browsers as OK. It can also be dismissed in most browsers by pressing the close button, but this will always do the same thing as the OK button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance testing</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/performance_testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/performance_testing/</guid>
      <description>Performance testing using Selenium and WebDriver is generally not advised. Not because it is incapable, but because it is not optimised for the job and you are unlikely to get good results.
It may seem ideal to performance test in the context of the user but a suite of WebDriver tests are subjected to many points of external and internal fragility which are beyond your control; for example browser startup speed, speed of HTTP servers, response of third party servers that host JavaScript or CSS, and the instrumentation penalty of the WebDriver implementation itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with cookies</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/support_packages/working_with_cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/support_packages/working_with_cookies/</guid>
      <description>A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent from a website and stored in your computer. Cookies are mostly used to recognise the user and load the stored information.
WebDriver API provides a way to interact with cookies with built-in methods:
Add Cookie It is used to add a cookie to the current browsing context. Add Cookie only accepts a set of defined serializable JSON object. Here is the link to the list of accepted JSON key values</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Http proxies</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/http_proxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/http_proxies/</guid>
      <description>A proxy server acts as an intermediary for requests between a client and a server. In simple, the traffic flows through the proxy server on its way to the address you requested and back.
A proxy server for automation scripts with Selenium could be helpful for:
 Capture network traffic Mock backend calls made by the website Access the required website under complex network topologies or strict corporate restrictions/policies.  If you are in a corporate environment, and a browser fails to connect to a URL, this is most likely because the environment needs a proxy to be accessed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link spidering</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/link_spidering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/worst_practices/link_spidering/</guid>
      <description>Using WebDriver to spider through links is not a recommended practice. Not because it cannot be done, but because WebDriver is definitely not the most ideal tool for this. WebDriver needs time to start up, and can take several seconds, up to a minute depending on how your test is written, just to get to the page and traverse through the DOM.
Instead of using WebDriver for this, you could save a ton of time by executing a curl command, or using a library such as BeautifulSoup since these methods do not rely on creating a browser and navigating to a page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test independency</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/test_independency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/test_independency/</guid>
      <description>Write each test as its own unit. Write the tests in a way that will not be reliant on other tests to complete:
Let us say there is a content management system with which you can create some custom content which then appears on your website as a module after publishing, and it may take some time to sync between the CMS and the application.
A wrong way of testing your module is that the content is created and published in one test, and then checking the module in another test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consider using a fluent API</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/consider_using_a_fluent_api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/consider_using_a_fluent_api/</guid>
      <description>Martin Fowler coined the term &amp;ldquo;Fluent API&amp;rdquo;. Selenium already implements something like this in their FluentWait class, which is meant as an alternative to the standard Waitclass. You could enable the Fluent API design pattern in your page object and then query the Google search page with a code snippet like this one:
driver.get( &amp;#34;http://www.google.com/webhp?hl=en&amp;amp;amp;tab=ww&amp;#34; ); GoogleSearchPage gsp = new GoogleSearchPage(); gsp.withFluent().setSearchString().clickSearchButton(); The Google page object class with this fluent behavior might look like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page loading strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/page_loading_strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/page_loading_strategy/</guid>
      <description>Defines the current session&amp;rsquo;s page loading strategy. By default, when Selenium WebDriver loads a page, it follows the normal pageLoadStrategy. It is always recommended to stop downloading additional resources (like images, css, js) when the page loading takes lot of time.
The document.readyState property of a document describes the loading state of the current document. By default, WebDriver will hold off on responding to a driver.get() (or) driver.navigate().to() call until the document ready state is complete</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh browser per test</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/fresh_browser_per_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/guidelines_and_recommendations/fresh_browser_per_test/</guid>
      <description>Start each test from a clean known state. Ideally, spin up a new virtual machine for each test. If spinning up a new virtual machine is not practical, at least start a new WebDriver for each test. For Firefox, start a WebDriver with your known profile.
FirefoxProfile profile = new FirefoxProfile(new File(&amp;#34;pathToFirefoxProfile&amp;#34;)); WebDriver driver = new FirefoxDriver(profile); </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web element</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/web_element/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/web_element/</guid>
      <description>WebElement represents a DOM element. WebElements can be found by searching from the document root using a WebDriver instance, or by searching under another WebElement.
WebDriver API provides built-in methods to find the WebElements which are based on different properties like ID, Name, Class, XPath, CSS Selectors, link Text, etc.
Find Element It is used to find an element and returns a first matching single WebElement reference, that can be used for future element actions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrome Devtools</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/support_packages/chrome_devtools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/support_packages/chrome_devtools/</guid>
      <description>Selenium 4 alpha versions have much awaited native support for Chrome Dev Protocol through &amp;ldquo;DevTools&amp;rdquo; interface. This helps us getting Chrome Development properties such as Application Cache, Fetch, Network, Performance, Profiler, Resource Timing, Security and Target CDP domains etc.
Chrome DevTools is a set of web developer tools built directly into the Google Chrome browser. DevTools can help you edit pages on-the-fly and diagnose problems quickly, which ultimately helps you build better websites, faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/webdriver/keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Keyboard represents a KeyBoard event. KeyBoard actions are performed by using low-level interface which allows us to provide virtualized device input to the web browser.
sendKeys The sendKeys types a key sequence in DOM element even if modifier key sequence is encountered. Here are the list of possible keystrokes that WebDriver Supports.
Java Python C# Ruby JavaScript Kotlin import org.openqa.selenium.By;import org.openqa.selenium.Keys;import org.openqa.selenium.WebDriver;import org.openqa.selenium.firefox.FirefoxDriver;public class HelloSelenium {public static void main(String[] args) {WebDriver driver = new FirefoxDriver();try {// Navigate to Url driver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to the Selenium Site &amp; Documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/contributing/</guid>
      <description>Selenium is a big software project, its site and documentation are key to understanding how things work and learning effective ways to exploit its potential.
This project contains both Selenium&amp;rsquo;s site and documentation. This is an ongoing effort (not targeted at any specific release) to provide updated information on how to use Selenium effectively, how to get involved and how to contribute to Selenium.
Contributions toward the site and docs follow the process described in the below section about contributions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>