<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introducción on Documentación de Selenium</title>
    <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introducción on Documentación de Selenium</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>2013-{year}</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Selenium project and tools</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/introduction/the_selenium_project_and_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/introduction/the_selenium_project_and_tools/</guid>
      <description>Page being translated from English to Spanish. Do you speak Spanish? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
 Selenium controls web browsers Selenium is many things but at its core, it is a toolset for web browser automation that uses the best techniques available to remotely control browser instances and emulate a user&amp;rsquo;s interaction with the browser.
It allows users to simulate common activities performed by end-users; entering text into fields, selecting drop-down values and checking boxes, and clicking links in documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On test automation</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/introduction/on_test_automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/introduction/on_test_automation/</guid>
      <description>Page being translated from English to Spanish. Do you speak Spanish? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
 First, start by asking yourself whether or not you really need to use a browser. Odds are that, at some point, if you are working on a complex web application, you will need to open a browser and actually test it.
Functional end-user tests such as Selenium tests are expensive to run, however.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of testing</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/introduction/types_of_testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/introduction/types_of_testing/</guid>
      <description>Page being translated from English to Spanish. Do you speak Spanish? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
 Acceptance testing This type of test is done to determine if a product&amp;rsquo;s feature matches its requirements. This generally involves the customer&amp;rsquo;s feedback or specification.
For web applications, the automation of this testing can be done directly with Selenium by simulating user expected behaviour. This simulation could be done by record/playback or through the different supported languages as explained in this documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acerca de esta documentación</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/introduction/about_this_documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/introduction/about_this_documentation/</guid>
      <description>Estos documentos, como el código en sí, son mantenidos al 100% por voluntarios dentro de la comunidad de Selenium. Muchos lo han estado usando desde su inicio, pero muchos más lo han estado usando desde hace poco y han dado su tiempo para ayudar a mejorar la experiencia de iniciación para los nuevos usuarios.
Si hay un problema con la documentación, ¡queremos saberlo! La mejor manera de comunicar un problema es visitar https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>