<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Grid 4 on Documentation for Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/grid_4/</link><description>Recent content in Grid 4 on Documentation for Selenium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>2013-{year}</copyright><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/grid_4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Components</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/grid_4/components_of_a_grid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/grid_4/components_of_a_grid/</guid><description>Router The Router takes care of forwarding the request to the correct component.
It is the entry point of the Grid, all external requests will be received by it. The Router behaves differently depending on the request. If it is a new session request, the Router will forward it to the New Session Queuer, which will add it to the New Session Queue. The New Session Queuer will trigger an event through the Event Bus.</description></item><item><title>Setting up your own</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/grid_4/setting_up_your_own_grid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/grid_4/setting_up_your_own_grid/</guid><description>Different Modes of Grid setup in Selenium 4: Standalone Hub and Node Distributed Docker Standalone Mode: The new Selenium Server Jar contains everything you&amp;rsquo;d need to run a grid. It is also the easiest mode to spin up a Selenium Grid. By default the server will be listening on http://localhost:4444, and that&amp;rsquo;s the URL you should point your RemoteWebDriver tests. The server will detect the available drivers that it can use from the System PATH</description></item><item><title>GraphQL querying support</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/grid_4/graphql_support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/grid_4/graphql_support/</guid><description>GraphQL is a query language for APIs and a runtime for fulfilling those queries with your existing data. It gives users the power to ask for exactly what they need and nothing more.
Enums Enums represent possible sets of values for a field.
For example, the Node object has a field called status. The state is an enum (specifically, of type Status) because it may be UP , DRAINING or UNAVAILABLE.</description></item><item><title>Grid endpoints</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/grid_4/grid_endpoints/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/en/grid/grid_4/grid_endpoints/</guid><description>Grid Grid Status Grid status provides the current state of the Grid. It consists of details about every registered Node. For every Node, the status includes information regarding Node availability, sessions, and slots.
cURL GET &amp;#39;http://localhost:4444/status&amp;#39; In the Standalone mode, the Grid URL is the Standalone server address.
In the Hub-Node mode, the Grid URL is the Hub server address.
In the fully distributed mode, the Grid URL is the Router server address.</description></item></channel></rss>