<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Worst practices on Selenium 文档</title>
    <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Worst practices on Selenium 文档</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>2013-{year}</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>验证码</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/captchas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/captchas/</guid>
      <description>验证码 (CAPTCHA), 是 全自动区分计算机和人类的图灵测试 (Completely Automated Public Turing test to tell Computers and Humans Apart) 的简称, 是被明确地设计用于阻止自动化的, 所以不要尝试!
规避验证码的检查, 主要有两个策略:
 在测试环境中禁用验证码 添加钩子以允许测试绕过验证码  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>文件下载</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/file_downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/file_downloads/</guid>
      <description>虽然可以通过在Selenium的控制下单击浏览器的链接来开始下载, 但是API并不会暴露下载进度, 因此这是一种不理想的测试下载文件的方式. 因为下载文件并非模拟用户与Web平台交互的重要方面. 取而代之的是, 应使用Selenium(以及任何必要的cookie)查找链接, 并将其传递给例如libcurl这样的HTTP请求库.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP response codes</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/http_response_codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/http_response_codes/</guid>
      <description>页面需要从英语翻译为简体中文。 您熟悉英语与简体中文吗？帮助我们翻译它，通过 pull requests 给我们！
 For some browser configurations in Selenium RC, Selenium acted as a proxy between the browser and the site being automated. This meant that all browser traffic passed through Selenium could be captured or manipulated. The captureNetworkTraffic() method purported to capture all of the network traffic between the browser and the site being automated, including HTTP response codes.
Selenium WebDriver is a completely different approach to browser automation, preferring to act more like a user and this is represented in the way you write tests with WebDriver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gmail, email and Facebook logins</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/gmail_email_and_facebook_logins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/gmail_email_and_facebook_logins/</guid>
      <description>页面需要从英语翻译为简体中文。 您熟悉英语与简体中文吗？帮助我们翻译它，通过 pull requests 给我们！
 For multiple reasons, logging into sites like Gmail and Facebook using WebDriver is not recommended. Aside from being against the usage terms for these sites (where you risk having the account shut down), it is slow and unreliable.
The ideal practice is to use the APIs that email providers offer, or in the case of Facebook the developer tools service which exposes an API for creating test accounts, friends and so forth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>测试依赖</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/test_dependency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/test_dependency/</guid>
      <description>关于自动化测试的一个常见想法和误解是关于特定的测试顺序. 您的测试应该能够以任何顺序运行，而不是依赖于完成其他测试才能成功.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance testing</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/performance_testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/performance_testing/</guid>
      <description>页面需要从英语翻译为简体中文。 您熟悉英语与简体中文吗？帮助我们翻译它，通过 pull requests 给我们！
 Performance testing using Selenium and WebDriver is generally not advised. Not because it is incapable but because it is not optimised for the job and you are unlikely to get good results.
It may seem ideal to performance test in the context of the user but a suite of WebDriver tests are subjected to many points of external and internal fragility which are beyond your control; for example browser startup speed, speed of HTTP servers, response of third party servers that host JavaScript or CSS, and the instrumentation penalty of the WebDriver implementation itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link spidering</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/link_spidering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/zh-cn/worst_practices/link_spidering/</guid>
      <description>页面需要从英语翻译为简体中文。 您熟悉英语与简体中文吗？帮助我们翻译它，通过 pull requests 给我们！
 Using WebDriver to spider through links is not a recommended practice not because it cannot be done, but because it’s definitely not the most ideal tool. WebDriver needs time to start up, and can take several seconds up to a minute depending on how your test is written, just to get to the page and traverse through the DOM.
Instead of using WebDriver for this, you could save a ton of time by executing a curl command, or using a library such as BeautifulSoup since these methods don’t rely on creating a browser and navigating to a page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>