<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pacotes de suporte on Documentação do Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/support_packages/</link><description>Recent content in Pacotes de suporte on Documentação do Selenium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>2013-{year}</copyright><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/support_packages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Trabalhando com cores</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/support_packages/working_with_colours/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/support_packages/working_with_colours/</guid><description>Ocasionalmente, você desejará validar a cor de algo como parte de seus testes; o problema é que as definições de cores na web não são constantes. Não seria bom se houvesse uma maneira fácil de comparar uma representação HEX de uma cor com uma representação RGB de uma cor, ou uma representação RGBA de uma cor com uma representação HSLA de uma cor?
Não se preocupe. Existe uma solução: a classe Color!</description></item><item><title>Trabalhando com elementos select</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/support_packages/working_with_select_elements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/support_packages/working_with_select_elements/</guid><description>Page being translated from English to Brazilian Portuguese. Do you speak Brazilian Portuguese? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
Select elements can require quite a bit of boiler plate code to automate. To reduce this, and make your tests cleaner, there is a Select class in the Selenium support package. To use it, you will need the following import statement:
Java Python C# Ruby JavaScript Kotlin import org.</description></item><item><title>Ações do mouse em detalhe</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/support_packages/mouse_and_keyboard_actions_in_detail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/support_packages/mouse_and_keyboard_actions_in_detail/</guid><description>Page being translated from English to Brazilian Portuguese. Do you speak Brazilian Portuguese? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
Mouse represents a mouse event. Mouse actions are performed by using low-level interface which allows us to provide virtualized device input action to the web browser.
clickAndHold It will move to the element and clicks (without releasing) in the middle of the given element.
Java Python C# Ruby JavaScript Kotlin import org.</description></item><item><title>Trabalhando com cookies</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/support_packages/working_with_cookies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/support_packages/working_with_cookies/</guid><description>Page being translated from English to Brazilian Portuguese. Do you speak Brazilian Portuguese? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent from a website and stored in your computer. Cookies are mostly used to recognise the user and load the stored information.
WebDriver API provides a way to interact with cookies with built-in methods:
Add Cookie It is used to add a cookie to the current browsing context.</description></item><item><title>Chrome Devtools</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/support_packages/chrome_devtools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/support_packages/chrome_devtools/</guid><description>As versões alfa do Selenium 4 têm aguardado suporte nativo para o protocolo Chrome DevTools por meio da interface &amp;ldquo;DevTools&amp;rdquo;. Isso nos ajuda a obter propriedades de desenvolvimento do Chrome, como cache de aplicativo, busca, rede, desempenho, criador de perfil, tempo de recurso, segurança e domínios de CDP de destino, etc.
Chrome DevTools é um conjunto de ferramentas de desenvolvedor da web integradas diretamente no navegador Google Chrome. DevTools pode ajudá-lo a editar páginas dinamicamente e diagnosticar problemas rapidamente, o que, em última análise, ajuda a criar sites melhores e mais rápidos.</description></item></channel></rss>