<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Selenium – conference</title><link>/tags/conference/</link><description>Recent content in conference on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Selenium at Agile 2010</title><link>/blog/2010/selenium-at-agile-2010/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2010/selenium-at-agile-2010/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Selenium project does not have an ‘official’ presence here at &lt;a href="http://agile2010.agilealliance.org">Agile&lt;/a> as it is seen as a ‘test after’ tool rather than ‘test first’ — even though it provides the magic of the ‘test first’ frameworks… But there is a small, unofficial contingent of recognizable faces around that can help people out and some sessions on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sessions&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Why your selenium tests are so dang brittle, and what to do about it&lt;/em> – Wednesday, August 11 – 3:30 – 5:00&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are writing automated through-the-GUI tests for a web application, you are in danger of creating tests that are more expensive to maintain than they are worth. With well-factored Selenium RC tests running in Junit or TestNG, you can keep your abstraction layers or “Lingos” — small bounded bits of slang for discrete parts of the object model — separate, thereby reducing the maintenance costs of your tests, and improving your sanity. Prerequisites include experience with Java or C#, and ideally some *basic* OOD familiarity (inheritance, composition, encapsulation, polymorphism).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Selenium Open Jam&lt;/em> – Tuesday, August 10 – 11 – 12&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bring your questions or problems or complaints. We’ll try to ease / solve them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>People&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Dawn Cannan&lt;/em> – author of &lt;a href="http://www.passionatetester.com/">Confessions of a Passionate Tester&lt;/a> and maintainer of the .NET version of &lt;a href="http://github.com/marisaseal/selenesse">Selenesse&lt;/a> which is a bridge between Selenium and Fitnesse.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Adam Goucher (me)&lt;/em> – maintainer of Selenium IDE and Selenium focused consultant&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Jason Huggins&lt;/em> – creator of Selenium and co-founder of &lt;a href="http://saucelabs.com">Sauce Labs&lt;/a> (Selenium in the cloud)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Patrick Wilson-Welsh&lt;/em> – Agile coach and Selenium power user&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you are not succeeding with Selenium, come track down one of us. We might redirect you somewhere else, but eventually we’ll get you sorted out.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>