<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Selenium – conference</title><link>/tags/conference/</link><description>Recent content in conference on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Let's meet at SeleniumConf, Once Again!</title><link>/blog/2023/lets-meet-in-person-at-seleniumconf-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/lets-meet-in-person-at-seleniumconf-2023/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This year is special, thanks to the decision to host an in-person conference after a long hiatus and several years of
virtual-only events. We&amp;rsquo;ve gone out of our way to reflect this feeling at the conference. We have engrossing keynotes,
well-researched talks, hands-on pre-conference workshops, hallway tracks, and whatnot!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="heres-a-quick-list-of-what-to-expect">Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list of what to expect!&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="whats-cooking-in-keynotes">What&amp;rsquo;s cooking in Keynotes?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have Diego Molina kicking things off with
&amp;lsquo;&lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#selenium-state-of-the-union">Selenium: State of the Union&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo; where he will talk about
all things Selenium, including the project, the code, and the community. Think of it as a journey through the times with
Selenium. A must-attend without any shred of doubt!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next up is Erika Chestnut&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#bigger-than-the-box">Bigger Than The Box&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo; where she
will focus on the idea of quality and whether it has been restricted to only a single step in the delivery process.
It is indeed a dialogue that needs to happen given that our lives revolve around quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On day 2, we have first-time SeleniumConf keynote speaker Mark Winteringham from the Ministry of Testing talking about
&amp;lsquo;&lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#what-exactly-do-you-do-in-test-automation">What Exactly Do You Do in Test Automation?&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;
Is it just about coding and frameworks or is there more to it? How should a test automation practitioner think about
their role? Think of this as learning from the ground up or in some cases, back to the basics!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="talks-talks-and-more-talks">Talks, talks, and more talks&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve cast our net far and wide this time around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just as a highlight, across the two days, we will cover a diverse range of topics from crawlers, identifying code
smells, blended testing, component testing, quality gates, quality metrics to track, testing with real robots, and
managing the test data nightmare, among others. Quite a list, huh? Trust me, this is just a sneak peek. You can check
out the entire list &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, we&amp;rsquo;ve got a session on how testing with
&lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#solving-unemployment-in-africa-with-testing-and-selenium">Selenium is solving unemployment in Africa&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The cherry on the cake is the Q&amp;amp;A with the Selenium Committer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#q-amp-a-with-the-selenium-committers-panel">Panel&lt;/a>
where you&amp;rsquo;ll get to pick the brains of the very people who&amp;rsquo;ve built Selenium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a way, we&amp;rsquo;ve truly tried our best to touch upon the technology, people, and process aspects of testing. We&amp;rsquo;d love to
have you over to catch these experts in action!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="getting-your-hands-dirty-with-tailored-workshops">Getting your hands dirty with tailored workshops&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Testing is all about exploring. How about exploring and diving into something new?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve got community leaders doing deep dives into Selenium, Appium 2.0, how to become a committer, state model-based
testing, and driving observability with Selenium Grid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We truly believe that nothing beats hearing it from the horse&amp;rsquo;s mouth.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-more">What&amp;rsquo;s more?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While there are some amazing keynotes, well-researched talks, and structured workshops, we really think the biggest
takeaway for any attendee is the people they&amp;rsquo;ll get to meet. Selenium has been a great example of how the community can
come together to build something that is greater than the sum of its parts. A conference like this brings together folks
from across the world, with different levels of experience, and puts them under a single roof.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What can be more beautiful than getting to interact with the very community that has built and grown Selenium?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are you waiting for? &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/register/">Register now&lt;/a>! We can&amp;rsquo;t wait to welcome you to Chicago!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: SeleniumConf Chicago 2023 Speakers Announced</title><link>/blog/2022/seleniumconf-chicago-2023-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/seleniumconf-chicago-2023-update/</guid><description>
&lt;p>As many of you know, the &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com">Selenium Conference&lt;/a> returns to an in-person event next March 28-30, 2023 in Chicago, IL. The Program Chairs &amp;amp; Committee, as well as the Extended Program Review Committee, have been hard at work putting together an outstanding lineup of speakers and workshops, and we&amp;rsquo;re close to releasing the full agenda and a completely re-branded conference website - stay tuned! In the meantime, we wanted you to be among the first to know who will be presenting, announce a new, additional pre-conference workshop, and provide you with some important updates. Here we go!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="keynote-sessions">Keynote Sessions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There will be four plenary keynote presentations across the 2-day conference. Selenium Core Committer &lt;strong>Diego Molina&lt;/strong> will open the conference on Wednesday with the &amp;ldquo;Selenium: State of the Union&amp;rdquo; presentation, followed by Quality &amp;amp; Leadership Coach &lt;strong>Erika Chestnut&lt;/strong> presenting &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#bigger-than-the-box">&amp;ldquo;Bigger Than The Box&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>, where she shares how she has crossed the aisles to elevate and expand the role quality in the organizations that she has worked for. Day 2 kicks off with &lt;strong>Mark Winteringham&lt;/strong>, Ministry of Testing OpsBoss, presenting &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#what-exactly-do-you-do-in-test-automation">&amp;ldquo;What Exactly Do You Do In Test Automation&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>. The final keynote session will be a &lt;strong>Q&amp;amp;A with the Selenium Committers&lt;/strong> panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="confirmed-track-session-presenters">Confirmed Track Session Presenters&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Following the opening keynote presentations, there will be two separate track sessions running in parallel. Here are the confirmed speakers to date and the presentations they will be giving:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Anand Bagmar&lt;/strong>, Software Quality Evangelist, Essence of Testing - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#metrics-to-make-your-quality-practices-effective">Metrics to Make Your Quality Practices Effective&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Andrew Knight&lt;/strong>, Developer Advocate, Applitools - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#managing-the-test-data-nightmare">Managing the Test Data Nightmare&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Benjamin Bischoff&lt;/strong>, Test Automation Engineer, Trivago N.V. - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#identifying-code-smells">Identifying Code Smells&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Bijoya Chatterjee&lt;/strong>, Director, Software QE, Sony Playstation - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#using-a-proxy-to-create-a-full-stack-automation-suite">Using A Proxy To Create A Full Stack Automation Suite&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Boni García&lt;/strong>, Staff Software Engineer, Sauce Labs - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#selenium-manager-automated-driver-amp-browser-management-for-selenium-webdriver">Selenium Manager: Automated Driver &amp;amp; Browser Management for Selenium WebDriver&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Christian Bromann&lt;/strong>, WebdriverIO Project Lead | Software Engineer, Stateful - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#component-testing-with-webdriverio">Component Testing with WebdriverIO&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Corina-Adina Pip&lt;/strong>, QA Lead , Deloitte Digital - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#whats-new-and-good-in-selenium">What’s New and Good in Selenium&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>David Burns&lt;/strong>, Selenium Core Committer | Head of Open Source Program Office, BrowserStack - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#why-browser-engines-real-desktop-browsers-mobile-browsers">Why Browser Engines ≠ Real Desktop Browsers ≠ Mobile Browsers&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dmitriy Gumeniuk&lt;/strong>, Head of Testing Products, EPAM Systems - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#building-quality-gates-and-automated-decisions-in-cicd-pipelines-lessons-learned-with-200000-regressions">Building Quality Gates and Automated Decisions in CI/CD Pipelines. Lessons Learned with 200,000 Regressions.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Eric Frankenberger&lt;/strong>, DevOps Engineer, Genesys Telecommunications - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#deploying-a-large-selenium-grid-with-video-recording-and-autoscaling-when-docker-swarm-amp-kubernetes-are-not-an-option">Deploying a Large Selenium Grid with Video Recording and Autoscaling When Docker Swarm &amp;amp; Kubernetes Are Not an Option&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ibironke Yekinni&lt;/strong>, Sr. Quality Assurance Engineer, Testify Limited - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#solving-unemployment-in-africa-with-testing-and-selenium">Solving Unemployment in Africa with Testing and Selenium&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Jan Molak&lt;/strong>, SerenityJS Project Lead, SmartCode Ltd - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#creating-faster-and-more-reliable-web-tests-with-blended-testing">Creating Faster and More Reliable Web Tests with Blended Testing&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Jason Huggins&lt;/strong>, Jason Huggins, Creator of Selenium | Founder, Tapster - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#testing-with-real-robots-over-the-internet-what-could-go-wrong">Testing With Real Robots Over the Internet: What Could Go Wrong?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Josh Grant&lt;/strong>, Developer Advocate, Code Intelligence - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#selenium-in-the-clouds-using-cloud-service-providers-with-selenium-webdriver">Selenium in the Clouds: Using Cloud Service Providers with Selenium WebDriver&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Liza Ivanova&lt;/strong>, Principal Software Engineer, Salesforce - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#declarative-utam-page-objects">Declarative UTAM Page Objects&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Maksim Sadym&lt;/strong>, Software Engineer, Google - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#webdriver-bidi-selenium-why-and-how">WebDriver BiDi + Selenium. Why and How?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Michael Mintz&lt;/strong>, Creator of SeleniumBase | Director of Automation, iboss - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#python-selenium-fundamentals-to-frameworks-with-seleniumbase">Python Selenium: Fundamentals to Frameworks (with SeleniumBase)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Robin Gupta&lt;/strong>, Associate Vice President, Provar - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#do-you-use-selenium-only-for-test-automation">Do You Use Selenium Only for Test Automation?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Roger Abelenda&lt;/strong>, CTO, Abstracta - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#evolve-your-selenium-scripts-into-performance-scripts">Evolve Your Selenium Scripts Into Performance Scripts&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Shi Ling Tai&lt;/strong>, CEO, UI-licious - &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#untestable-its-just-pressing-a-button-how-hard-could-it-be">UNTestable: It&amp;rsquo;s Just Pressing a Button, How Hard Could it Be?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="new-workshop-added---state-model-based-testing-using-selenium">New Workshop Added - State Model-Based Testing Using Selenium&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re pleased to announce a new addition to the optional pre-conference workshop day, &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#state-model-based-testing-using-selenium">State Model-Based Testing Using Selenium&lt;/a>, led by &lt;strong>Ru Cindrea&lt;/strong>, Managing Partner and Senior Test Consultant, Altom Consulting &amp;amp; &lt;strong>Alex Rotaru&lt;/strong>, Co-owner, Altom Consulting. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet heard of State Model-Based Testing (SMBT) is a testing technique that allows testers to visualize their applications and to generate and automate test flows by using different models of the application under test, thus obtaining a large number of test scenarios. When certain paths of the application are changed, the benefit of using SMBT is that you will only have to modify the states and transitions that apply to that change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This workshop rounds out the core pre-conference workshop offerings, which include a &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#selenium-deep-dive">Selenium Deep Dive&lt;/a> session led by Selenium Project Core Committer, &lt;strong>Titus Fortner&lt;/strong>; &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#driving-observability-with-selenium-grid-4">Driving Observability with Selenium Grid 4&lt;/a>, led by &lt;strong>Manoj Kumar&lt;/strong>, VP, Developer Relations at LambdaTest and Selenium Project Leadership Committee member, and &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/agenda/#advanced-appium-20">Advanced Appium 2.0&lt;/a>, with &lt;strong>Srini Sekar&lt;/strong> &amp;amp; &lt;strong>Sai Krishna&lt;/strong>, Lead Consultants at Thoughtworks and long-time Appium workshop instructors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Workshops are one of the most popular offerings at any SeleniumConf and because class sizes are limited they invariably sell-out. Early Bird ticket sales have closed, but you can still find openings for any of these awesome day-long sessions. &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/register/">Register today&lt;/a> and make sure you get a seat at the Conference + Workshop session of your choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="wait-wait---where-is-the-fix-a-bug-become-a-committer-workshop">Wait, Wait - Where is the Fix a Bug, Become a Committer Workshop?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re a long-time follower of past Selenium Conferences, or just happened to attend the July, 2022 virtual SeleniumConf, you may be familiar with the long-standing workshop offering &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/workshops/#fix-a-bug-become-a-committer">&amp;ldquo;Fix a Bug, Become a Committer&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>. This workshop is a bit different in that the goal is to both enhance your own Selenium experience while offering the ability to contribute back to the project. With this, it&amp;rsquo;s not a learning session, per se, but more of a doing session, and we thought we&amp;rsquo;d take a different approach this time and make it available at no-charge (other than buying a conference ticket) to a limited number of applicants. If you are familiar with Selenium and want to extend your conference experience an extra day we encourage you to &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/3iJf81w1x66a2veg8">apply&lt;/a>. Scholarship applicants (more below) are also welcome to apply.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="announcing-the-seleniumconf-chicago-2023-scholarship-program">Announcing the SeleniumConf Chicago 2023 Scholarship Program&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The mission of the Selenium project is to educate the QA and developer communities about Selenium, the importance of quality assurance, and automated testing in general. Both the Selenium project and the SeleniumConf organizers very much want everyone to be able to attend the conference, but we know that not everyone’s personal or financial circumstances make this possible - so, we&amp;rsquo;re setting aside a number of free tickets, and covering travel expenses, as part of our SeleniumConf Chicago 2023 scholarship program.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The program aims to support individuals from underrepresented groups in tech and those facing economic or social hardship so they have access to SeConf content and networking opportunities. If you’re an aspiring software professional looking to use Selenium, or a current one without access to the funds to buy your ticket, you should apply. We will award tickets to people who can show that the knowledge gained will be useful for their ongoing career. The application form will be posted in January, 2023.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ready-to-go-but-your-manager-needs-more-convincing">Ready to Go, But Your Manager Needs More Convincing?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ve now seen the keynotes, the current roster of speakers, and the awesome hands-on workshop descriptions, but you still need more to convince your manager? Download this &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/selenium-conf-chicago-2023-convince-your-boss-template.docx">&amp;ldquo;Convince Your Boss&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> email template and tailor it to your specific rationale using the details you&amp;rsquo;ve gleaned from this post. We&amp;rsquo;d really like to see you next March in Chicago - so &lt;a href="https://seleniumconf.com/register/">register here&lt;/a>!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Selenium at Agile 2010</title><link>/blog/2010/selenium-at-agile-2010/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2010/selenium-at-agile-2010/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Selenium project does not have an ‘official’ presence here at &lt;a href="http://agile2010.agilealliance.org">Agile&lt;/a> as it is seen as a ‘test after’ tool rather than ‘test first’ — even though it provides the magic of the ‘test first’ frameworks… But there is a small, unofficial contingent of recognizable faces around that can help people out and some sessions on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sessions&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Why your selenium tests are so dang brittle, and what to do about it&lt;/em> – Wednesday, August 11 – 3:30 – 5:00&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are writing automated through-the-GUI tests for a web application, you are in danger of creating tests that are more expensive to maintain than they are worth. With well-factored Selenium RC tests running in Junit or TestNG, you can keep your abstraction layers or “Lingos” — small bounded bits of slang for discrete parts of the object model — separate, thereby reducing the maintenance costs of your tests, and improving your sanity. Prerequisites include experience with Java or C#, and ideally some *basic* OOD familiarity (inheritance, composition, encapsulation, polymorphism).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Selenium Open Jam&lt;/em> – Tuesday, August 10 – 11 – 12&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bring your questions or problems or complaints. We’ll try to ease / solve them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>People&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Dawn Cannan&lt;/em> – author of &lt;a href="http://www.passionatetester.com/">Confessions of a Passionate Tester&lt;/a> and maintainer of the .NET version of &lt;a href="http://github.com/marisaseal/selenesse">Selenesse&lt;/a> which is a bridge between Selenium and Fitnesse.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Adam Goucher (me)&lt;/em> – maintainer of Selenium IDE and Selenium focused consultant&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Jason Huggins&lt;/em> – creator of Selenium and co-founder of &lt;a href="http://saucelabs.com">Sauce Labs&lt;/a> (Selenium in the cloud)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Patrick Wilson-Welsh&lt;/em> – Agile coach and Selenium power user&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you are not succeeding with Selenium, come track down one of us. We might redirect you somewhere else, but eventually we’ll get you sorted out.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>