<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Edge on Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/tags/edge/</link><description>Recent content in Edge on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 15:32:53 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/tags/edge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Novelties in Selenium Manager 0.4.15</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/novelties_in_selenium_manager_0.4.15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/novelties_in_selenium_manager_0.4.15/</guid><description>Support for Firefox ESR Selenium Manager 0.4.15 includes support for Firefox Extended Support Release (ESR). This way, Firefox ESR can be automatically managed with Selenium using the label esr in the browser version. Bindings languages set this browser version (like other accepted labels for browser versions, such as stable, beta, dev, canary, and nightly) using a browser option called browserVersion.
Support for Edge WebView2 Selenium Manager 0.4.15 allows automated driver management for Microsoft Edge WebView2.</description></item><item><title>Status of Selenium Manager in October 2023</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/status_of_selenium_manager_in_october_2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/status_of_selenium_manager_in_october_2023/</guid><description>Selenium Manager continues its development plan. As usual, in the latest releases, i.e., 0.4.13 and 0.4.14 (shipped with Selenium 4.13 and 4.14, respectively), we have fixed the problems reported so far. In these releases, the issues were related to the extraction of the Firefox binary from the self-extracting archive (SFX) in Windows and the advanced configuration through the configuration file (se-config.toml) and environment variables (e.g., SE_BROWSER). Moreover, these recent releases include new features, as explained below.</description></item><item><title>Dev and Beta Channel Browsers via Docker Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/dev-and-beta-channel-browsers-via-docker-selenium/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/dev-and-beta-channel-browsers-via-docker-selenium/</guid><description>The Docker Selenium browser Beta and Dev channel releases are now regularly published to Docker Hub and updated every two days. This enables testers and developers to test their applications on pre-release versions of Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, and Microsoft Edge before their official releases, using container tools, such as Docker. This empowers teams to stay ahead of the curve and catch potential showstoppers in their CI environment before those issues have an impact on their users.</description></item></channel></rss>