<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stories on Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/tags/stories/</link><description>Recent content in Stories on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 21:55:08 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/tags/stories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to delete your master branch</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/how_to_delete_your_master_branch/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/how_to_delete_your_master_branch/</guid><description>At the Selenium project we practice trunk based development, in which trunk is the usual name of the default git branch of the repository. However, when the project was moved to GitHub, the repository followed the traditional use of master as a name for the default git branch.
With the intention of making the Selenium project an even more inclusive place where everyone is welcome, a decision was made to use trunk as the default git branch and, after the switch, delete the master branch.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0 backend for running IDE test suite via the Se2 Firefox</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0-backend-for-running-ide-test-suite-via-the-se2-firefox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0-backend-for-running-ide-test-suite-via-the-se2-firefox/</guid><description>The GSoC 2010, it’s a great adventure.
I’m Raynatou, I come from Burkina and do my internship at SERLI. Like all interns in this company the topic of my internship focuses on advanced topics like the integration of WebDriver as backend for Selenium IDE. Selenium IDE is currently built upon Selenium Core for interacting with web pages. Selenium Core has several major limitations, including the inability to fire native events. To avoid these limitations and produce more robust tests, I am investigating Selenium IDE to using WebDriver in place of Selenium Core.</description></item><item><title>GSoC 2010 – Remote Storage</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/gsoc-2010-remote-storage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/gsoc-2010-remote-storage/</guid><description>What’s new for Selenium this summer ? The GSoC of course !!!!
I’m Jérémy, a french engineer and I work at SERLI, a services company based in France.
I’m working on Selenium since a year and this summer I’m mentoring Aleksejs for the GSoC 2010. I’m helped by David Burns when I’m on vacation or offline. His experience is really useful to me, and David is involved on student supervising regularly.</description></item></channel></rss>