<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Edgedriver on Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/tags/edgedriver/</link><description>Recent content in Edgedriver on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 18:11:20 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/tags/edgedriver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing Selenium Manager</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/introducing-selenium-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/introducing-selenium-manager/</guid><description>Most people&amp;rsquo;s first experience with Selenium ends up with an error message like this one:
java.lang.IllegalStateException: The path to the driver executable must be set by the webdriver.chrome.driver system property; for more information, see https://chromedriver.chromium.org/. The latest version can be downloaded from https://chromedriver.chromium.org/downloads Then they have to search the web for instructions on what to do with the drivers they download.
Selenium: now with batteries included! The Selenium project wants to improve the user experience, and one of the first steps is to help all users to simplify how they set up their environment.</description></item><item><title>IE Mode in Edge supported by IEDriver</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/ie-edge-support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/ie-edge-support/</guid><description>With the retirement of Internet Explorer 11 (IE 11) later this year, the folks in Redmond have helped the Selenium project with getting IE Mode in Microsoft Edge working in IEDriver.
IE 11 is due to retire on 15 June 2022 for certain versions of Windows 10. After this date, the Selenium project recommends that you test your IE sites with IE Mode in Microsoft Edge. The Selenium Project will not remove support for IE 11 when it retires but we will not actively fix issues as we have done with previous versions of IE.</description></item></channel></rss>