<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Selenium – meetup</title><link>/tags/meetup/</link><description>Recent content in meetup on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: The World’s Best Selenium Meetup</title><link>/blog/2013/the-worlds-best-selenium-meetup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2013/the-worlds-best-selenium-meetup/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Note from Adam: This is a guest post from &lt;a href="https://github.com/tourdedave">Dave Haeffner&lt;/a> who, along with &lt;a href="http://www.theautomatedtester.co.uk/">David Burns&lt;/a> hatched this idea at SeConf2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="selenium-meetups-are-great-but">&lt;strong>Selenium Meetups are great, but…&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Have you ever wanted to attend a Selenium Meetup but there’s not one near you? Or maybe there is but something’s come up and you can’t make it out that night? Or maybe the meetup near you struggles to get good speakers and have a consistent schedule? [Note from Adam; like, say, the Toronto one…]&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="we-can-do-better">&lt;strong>We can do better&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Well, what if there were a way to attend a meetup regardless of location?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what if each meetup you attended was lined with core maintainers of the Selenium project?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if you missed it, what if the whole thing was recorded and available for you to review at your leisure?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, now you can.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-worlds-best-selenium-meetup">&lt;strong>The World’s Best Selenium Meetup&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Introducing Selenium Hangout — the world’s best and most accessible Selenium meetup. An entirely online meetup that leverages Google Hangouts and live streaming to YouTube. All meetups will be recorded and posted online afterwards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each meetup will contain a small panel of people from the Selenium Community (e.g. core committers, automation practitioners, etc.) and they will discuss various topics (TBD).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-attend">&lt;strong>How to attend&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Simply follow &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SeleniumHangout">the SeleniumHangout Twitter account&lt;/a> to find out more.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>