<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meetup on Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/tags/meetup/</link><description>Recent content in Meetup on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:36:32 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/tags/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Announcing SeleniumConf &amp; AppiumConf 2025</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/seleniumconf-appiumconf-valencia-2025/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/seleniumconf-appiumconf-valencia-2025/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to announce that SeleniumConf &amp;amp; AppiumConf is returning for 2025, bringing together browser and mobile automation enthusiasts from around the world. This must-attend event will take place from March 26-28, 2025, in the vibrant city of Valencia, Spain!
This year, the conference will gather over 400 browser and mobile automation professionals, including developers, testers, quality managers, test architects, and others, to explore the latest trends in browser and mobile automation, including cutting-edge topics like AI in automation, game testing, accessibility automation, and much more.</description></item><item><title>Let's meet at SeleniumConf, Once Again!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/lets-meet-in-person-at-seleniumconf-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/lets-meet-in-person-at-seleniumconf-2023/</guid><description>This year is special, thanks to the decision to host an in-person conference after a long hiatus and several years of virtual-only events. We&amp;rsquo;ve gone out of our way to reflect this feeling at the conference. We have engrossing keynotes, well-researched talks, hands-on pre-conference workshops, hallway tracks, and whatnot!
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list of what to expect! What&amp;rsquo;s cooking in Keynotes? We have Diego Molina kicking things off with &amp;lsquo;Selenium: State of the Union&amp;rsquo; where he will talk about all things Selenium, including the project, the code, and the community.</description></item><item><title>SeleniumConf Chicago 2023 Speakers Announced</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/seleniumconf-chicago-2023-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/seleniumconf-chicago-2023-update/</guid><description>As many of you know, the Selenium Conference returns to an in-person event next March 28-30, 2023 in Chicago, IL. The Program Chairs &amp;amp; Committee, as well as the Extended Program Review Committee, have been hard at work putting together an outstanding lineup of speakers and workshops, and we&amp;rsquo;re close to releasing the full agenda and a completely re-branded conference website - stay tuned! In the meantime, we wanted you to be among the first to know who will be presenting, announce a new, additional pre-conference workshop, and provide you with some important updates.</description></item><item><title>The World’s Best Selenium Meetup</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/the-worlds-best-selenium-meetup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/the-worlds-best-selenium-meetup/</guid><description>Note from Adam: This is a guest post from Dave Haeffner who, along with David Burns hatched this idea at SeConf2013.
Selenium Meetups are great, but… Have you ever wanted to attend a Selenium Meetup but there’s not one near you? Or maybe there is but something’s come up and you can’t make it out that night? Or maybe the meetup near you struggles to get good speakers and have a consistent schedule?</description></item></channel></rss>