<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Releases on Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/categories/releases/</link><description>Recent content in Releases on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 18:29:35 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/categories/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Selenium 4.25 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-25-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-25-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.25 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Selenium 4.25.0 introduces several important changes and improvements across multiple programming languages and build systems. Below are the key highlights from this release.
General Updates Chrome DevTools support is now: v129, v128, and v127 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions)</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.24 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-24-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-24-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.24.0 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Noteworthy changes per language Java BiDi Prompt/Alert Test Fix: Fixed prompt/alert related tests if BiDi is enabled. Execute Script API: Added execute script high-level API for BiDi. JSpecify Annotations: Added JSpecify annotations for WebDriver, WebElement, SearchContext, and other interfaces. Dom Mutation Handler Support: Added DOM mutation handler support for BiDi.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.23 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-23-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-23-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.23.0 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Noteworthy changes per language Java Add custom duration for Actions constructor (#14085). Set session-request-timeout as client readTimeout in RemoteNewSessionQueue. Add high-level BiDi logging APIs. See all changes JavaScript Add source type to BiDi log entry. Add high-level script pinning BiDi APIs. See all changes .</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.22 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-22-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-22-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.22.0 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Selenium has at least 2.6 active users in the last 30 days. 200k more than last month! All information we collect is publicly available. The numbers only represent users who have Selenium Manager enabled and are using Selenium v4.17 or greater.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.21 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-21-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-21-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.21.0 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v123, v124, and v125 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Selenium has at least 2.4M active users in the last 30 days. 100k more than last month! India and United States are the top countries with the most users.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.20 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-20-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-20-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.20.0 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v122, v123, and v124 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Selenium has at least 2.3M active users in the last 30 days. 500k more than last month! Java and JavaScript keep adding more WebDriver BiDi features.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.19 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-19-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-19-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.19.0 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v121, v122, and v123 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Thanks to Selenium Manager&amp;rsquo;s records usage, we know Selenium has at least 1.8M active users in the last 30 days! Java and JavaScript keep adding more WebDriver BiDi features.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.18 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-18-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-18-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.18.0 and 4.18.1 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v120, v121, and v122 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Selenium Manager records usage has been decreased to reduce impact on users. Chrome headless changed the name of the browser to reflect that it is not actually chrome; Selenium now handles this seamlessly, but you should still switch to --headless=new (see: Headless is going away) Noteworthy changes per language Java Enabling Grid to use self-signed certificate for debugging Added explicit target locator events to the listener support classes in WebDriverListener.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.17 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-17-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-4-17-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.17.0 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, .NET, Java and the Grid! Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v119, v120, and v121 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Selenium Manager records usage set environment variable SE_AVOID_STATS to &amp;quot;true&amp;quot; to avoid sending information. Chrome headless changed the name of the browser to reflect that it is not actually chrome; Selenium now handles this seamlessly, but you should still switch to --headless=new (see: Headless is going away) Noteworthy changes per language Java Remove deprecated event listener classes; update to EventFiringDecorator and WebDriverListener classes Allow disabling Grid UI Deprecated FirefoxBinary class and legacy Error Codes Deprecated HTML5 features for offline storage, location, and network connection No longer accepting session requests with desiredCapabilities keyword See all changes JavaScript Remove deprecated headless methods and associated references Implemented remote file downloading See all changes .</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.16 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-16-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-16-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.16.0 for Javascript, Ruby, Python, and Selenium 4.16.1 for .NET, Java and the Grid. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v118, v119, and v120 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Users may now opt in to Selenium Manager by specifying a browserVersion that is different from what is found on the System All bindings now log Selenium information Noteworthy changes per language Java Improve Grid usage of Selenium Manager by always allowing browser version of &amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; Implement CDP script pinning for Chrome-based browsers Allow reusing devtools instance with JDK 11 client Moved org.</description></item><item><title>Novelties in Selenium Manager 0.4.15</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/novelties_in_selenium_manager_0.4.15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/novelties_in_selenium_manager_0.4.15/</guid><description>Support for Firefox ESR Selenium Manager 0.4.15 includes support for Firefox Extended Support Release (ESR). This way, Firefox ESR can be automatically managed with Selenium using the label esr in the browser version. Bindings languages set this browser version (like other accepted labels for browser versions, such as stable, beta, dev, canary, and nightly) using a browser option called browserVersion.
Support for Edge WebView2 Selenium Manager 0.4.15 allows automated driver management for Microsoft Edge WebView2.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.15 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-15-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-15-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.15.0 for Java, Javascript, Ruby, .NET and the Grid; 4.15.2 for Python. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v117, v118, and v119 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Implemented Remote File Downloads Selenium Manager supports webview2, Firefox ESR and Driver and Browser Mirrors Noteworthy changes per language Java Numerous BiDi implementations Remove CDP version dependencies in the server Selenium Manager now gets copied to cache directory instead of being used from temp directory See all changes JavaScript Replaced calls to console.</description></item><item><title>Status of Selenium Manager in October 2023</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/status_of_selenium_manager_in_october_2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/status_of_selenium_manager_in_october_2023/</guid><description>Selenium Manager continues its development plan. As usual, in the latest releases, i.e., 0.4.13 and 0.4.14 (shipped with Selenium 4.13 and 4.14, respectively), we have fixed the problems reported so far. In these releases, the issues were related to the extraction of the Firefox binary from the self-extracting archive (SFX) in Windows and the advanced configuration through the configuration file (se-config.toml) and environment variables (e.g., SE_BROWSER). Moreover, these recent releases include new features, as explained below.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.13 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-13-0-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-13-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.13.0 for Java, Python, Javascript and the Grid; and 4.13.1 for .NET and Ruby. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v115, v116, and v117 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Reminder: this is the last version of Selenium with Java 8 support. Please upgrade to at least Java 11. The location of Selenium Manager can be set manually in all bindings with SE_MANAGER_PATH environment variable.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.14 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-14-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-14-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.14.0 for Java, Python, Javascript, Ruby, .NET and the Grid. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v116, v117, and v118 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) If you are using Java, this release requires Java 11! (see post on Java 8 support) Selenium supports automatic downloading and management of the Microsoft Edge browser Relevant improvements per language Java Removed support for Async HTTP Client, the default is now the default Java library Allow setting SSL context in client config for HttpClient Several logging message improvements See all changes JavaScript See all changes .</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.12.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-12-0-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-12-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.12.0 for Java, .NET, Ruby, Python, and Javascript as well as the Grid. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v114, v115, and v116 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Quite a few fixes for Selenium Manager, and now with Firefox browser management! Read about all the new Selenium Manager features .</description></item><item><title>What's new in Selenium Manager 0.4.12, shipped with Selenium 4.12.0</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/whats_new_in_selenium_manager_0.4.12_shipped_with_selenium_4.12.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/whats_new_in_selenium_manager_0.4.12_shipped_with_selenium_4.12.0/</guid><description>A new release of Selenium Manager is out. For this release, we made a relevant decision concerning the Selenium Manager versioning format. From now on, Selenium Manager will follow the same version as Selenium. Nevertheless, since Selenium Manager is still in beta, its major version is 0. Thus, Selenium 4.12.0 is shipped with Selenium Manager 0.4.12.
First, we made a substantial effort to stabilize the already available features on Selenium Manager.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.11.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-11-0-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-11-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.11.0 for Java, .NET, Ruby, Python, and Javascript as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v113, v114, and v115 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Support for Chrome for Testing (CfT) through Selenium Manager. Read more at the new Selenium Manager features blog post.</description></item><item><title>What's new in Selenium Manager with Selenium 4.11.0</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/whats-new-in-selenium-manager-with-selenium-4.11.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/whats-new-in-selenium-manager-with-selenium-4.11.0/</guid><description>As of version 4.6.0, all releases of Selenium (Java, JavaScript, Python, Ruby, and .Net) are shipped with Selenium Manager. Selenium Manager is a binary tool (implemented in Rust) that provides automated driver management for Selenium. Selenium Manager is still in beta, although it is becoming a relevant component of Selenium.
So far, the main feature of Selenium Manager is called automated driver management. I use the term management for this feature (and not just download) since this process is broader and implies different steps:</description></item><item><title>Building Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/building-selenium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/building-selenium/</guid><description>One of the things that we knew from the very beginning of the Selenium project was that people like to code in more than one language. Some people love a bit of JS, others Ruby, and still others prefer C# or Java.
To complicate matters, there’s plenty of pieces we want to share between the language bindings you’ll be using. Examples include the “atoms” (re-usable pieces of javascript that perform common functions – such as “isDisplayed” or “getAttribute” – that we want to work the same way no matter which language you prefer to write tests in), things like our CDP support, which uses shared files that describe all the available functions we can call, and the new Selenium Manager, which is written in Rust, but we bundle with each of the language bindings.</description></item><item><title>Java 8 support in Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/java-8-support/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/java-8-support/</guid><description>“If it ain’t broke, don’t fix it” is a saying you may have heard, but sometimes it’s necessary to move on from our old favorites. That’s why we’re announcing that Selenium will stop supporting Java 8 on September 30, 2023. This applies for both the Java bindings and the Selenium Grid.
Selenium has long supported Java 8, but as technology evolves, so must we. One of the primary reasons for this change is that Java 8 reached the end of active support over a year ago.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.10.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-10-0-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-10-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.10.0 for Java, .NET, Ruby, Python, and Javascript as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v112, v113, and v114 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Selenium Manager supports proxy usage by using the proxy information set in the browser options. Adding support for webview2 in Edge for Java, JavaScript, and Ruby Error messages across bindings now include links to the Selenium documentation.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.9.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-9-0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-9-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.9.0 for Java, .NET, Ruby, Python, and Javascript as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v110, v111, and v112 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Maven BOM for the Java bindings. Remote file downloads are now possible through Selenium Grid. First steps taken to phase out CDP in Firefox and replace it with the BiDi implementation.</description></item><item><title>Headless is Going Away!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/headless-is-going-away/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/headless-is-going-away/</guid><description>Headless is an execution mode for Firefox and Chromium based browsers. It allows users to run automated scripts in headless mode, meaning that the browser window wouldn’t be visible. In most of Selenium&amp;rsquo;s bindings there is a convenience method to set this execution mode while setting the browser options. However, Selenium 4.8.0 will be deprecated this method and now users need to set it through arguments when setting the browser options.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.8.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-8-0-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/selenium-4-8-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.8.0 for Java, .NET, Ruby, Python, and Javascript as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v107, v108, and v109 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Large JS executions have the name as a comment to help understand what payload being sent to/from server/driver.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.7.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-7-0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-7-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.7.0 for Java, .NET, and Javascript as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver; for Ruby use 4.7.1, and Python 4.7.2. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Chrome DevTools support is now: v106, v107, and v108 (Firefox still uses v85 for all versions) Selenium Manager now supports IE Driver &amp;amp; has improved error logging. Using Edge in IE Mode no longer requires ignoring zoom levels.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Selenium Manager</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/introducing-selenium-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/introducing-selenium-manager/</guid><description>Most people&amp;rsquo;s first experience with Selenium ends up with an error message like this one:
java.lang.IllegalStateException: The path to the driver executable must be set by the webdriver.chrome.driver system property; for more information, see https://chromedriver.chromium.org/. The latest version can be downloaded from https://chromedriver.chromium.org/downloads Then they have to search the web for instructions on what to do with the drivers they download.
Selenium: now with batteries included! The Selenium project wants to improve the user experience, and one of the first steps is to help all users to simplify how they set up their environment.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.6.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-6-0-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-6-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.6.0 for Java, .NET, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript bindings as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver. Links to everything can be found on our downloads page.
Highlights Adding support for CDP released in Chrome v105, v106, and v107, while v104 was removed Initial implementation of Selenium Manager across bindings Improvements to the new Java HTTP 11 client and important Grid fixes.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.5.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-5-0-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-5-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.5.0 for Java, .NET, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript bindings as well as the Grid and Internet Explorer Driver. Links to everything can be found on our Downloads Page.
Highlights Adding support for CDP released in Chrome v105 and v106, while v102 and v103 were removed Updates to Select functionality Improved experience for Firefox Add-ons IE driver automatically uses Edge in IE Mode if IE is not present Java 11 HTTP Client supported for Java users running Java versions 11+ Various language specific bug fixes; see the full list of changes in the Changelogs.</description></item><item><title>Using Java 11+ HTTP Client in Selenium 4.5.0 and beyond</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/using-java11-httpclient/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/using-java11-httpclient/</guid><description>Current HTTP client used in Selenium Selenium uses an HTTP client and associated WebSocket client for multiple purposes
To send commands to the WebDriver To send commands from the Selenium client library to the Grid For various Grid components to communicate with each other depending on the Grid mode To create ChromeDevTools protocol and BiDi protocol sessions Currently, Selenium uses AsyncHttpClient. AsyncHttpClient is an open-source library built on top of Netty.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.4.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-4-0-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/selenium-4-4-0-released/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of Selenium 4.4.0. We&amp;rsquo;re shipping this for Java, .Net, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript, so if you&amp;rsquo;re using any of those languages, go and grab it from your package manager of choice!
Some of the main highlights are:
Adding support for CDP released in Chrome v104, while v101 was removed Virtual authenticator feature was completed across languages. All language bindings will throw an error when w3c: false is set in ChromeOptions Improved health checks and requests with non W3C locators for Relay Nodes in Grid Check the complete changelog and download the artifacts at the Selenium 4.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4 Release Candidate</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-rc-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-rc-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the first release candidate of Selenium 4. We&amp;rsquo;re shipping this for .Net, Java, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript, so if you&amp;rsquo;re using any of those languages, go and grab it from your package manager of choice!
This release is the result of a lot of work by the Selenium team project, but most importantly, all the Selenium community who tried our beta releases, and gave us great and valuable feedback.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4 Beta 1 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-beta-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-beta-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of the first beta of Selenium 4. We&amp;rsquo;re shipping this for Java, .Net, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript, so if you&amp;rsquo;re using any of those languages, go and grab it from your package manager of choice!
This has been the culmination of a lot of work by so many people, not only the project TLC, but also of literally hundreds of people: 205 since we released Selenium 3.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.0 Alpha 6 is out!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/selenium-4-alpha-6-is-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/selenium-4-alpha-6-is-out/</guid><description>We are very pleased to announce the release of Selenium 4.0 Alpha 6.
All the information can be seen in different tweets from the project contributors, here they are all in one place:
Happy Friday! I&amp;#39;ve just pushed Selenium 4.0a6 for Java. There&amp;#39;s a lot of nice changes:
* Full remoting of the CDP protocol across the Grid
* The skeleton of our GraphQL support
* Better configuration options, especially for Nodes, via TOML</description></item><item><title>Selenium 3.0: Out Now!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-0-out-now/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-0-out-now/</guid><description>We are very pleased to announce the release of Selenium 3.0. If you’ve been waiting for a stable release since 2.53.1, now’s your chance to update. And if you do, here is what you’ll find:
As we’ve said before, for users of the WebDriver APIs this is a drop-in replacement. You’ll find that modern browsers, such as Chrome and Edge will continue to work just as before, and we’ve taken the opportunity to fix some bugs and improve stability.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 3 is Coming</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-is-coming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-is-coming/</guid><description>Selenium 3 is coming! As I write this, we think that “beta 4” will be the last beta before the official 3.0 release. I’m here to tell you about what’s changed, and what impact this will have on your testing.
TL;DR: WebDriver users will just find bug fixes and a drop-in replacement for 2.x. Selenium Grid users will also find bug fixes and a simple update. The WebDriver APIs are now the only APIs actively supported by the Selenium project.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium 3.0-beta1</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/announcing-selenium-3-0-beta1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/announcing-selenium-3-0-beta1/</guid><description>At SeleniumConf in 2013, we announced that a new major version of Selenium would be released “by Christmas”. Fortunately, we never said which Christmas, as it has taken us a while to make all the changes we wanted to make! We’re excited to announce the release of the first beta — Selenium 3.0.0-beta1.
We’d love you to try it out on your projects, and provide us with feedback on where the rough edges are before we ship the 3.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium 2.26: the “It’s Really Real” Release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-26/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-26/</guid><description>It’s been a long time since we announced a new Selenium release on this blog, as we moved to a model of quicker releases, but we’ve been working on 2.26 for far longer than normal — it’s out! Download it now! — so I thought it best to let you know. We’re aiming to head back to faster releases, so hopefully you won’t see another blog post about the release for a while (though I’m sure they’ll appear in the “Smatterings of Selenium” posts)</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium 2.22</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-22/</guid><description>It’s been a while since the last Selenium release, but I’m happy to announce that Selenium 2.22 is now available for download. This is a big release for us and features two major changes.
The first is that Selenium 2.22 is the first version that requires Java 6 in order to run. This has been the case for the Selenium Server for some time, but this is the first time the client code has required Java 6.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium 2.19: the Prancing Unicorn release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-19-the-prancing-unicorn-release/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-19-the-prancing-unicorn-release/</guid><description>You might be pleased to hear that Selenium 2.19 has been released (download it from here!). There’s one big user facing changing that we’d like to tell you about: the webdriver-backed selenium can now be used in supported languages.
By providing this capability, it’s possible to migrate from RC to the WebDriver APIs without rewriting all your tests in one fell swoop (which must be a Good Thing, right?) An example of how to use it in Python would be:</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.16 Released: Welcome to 2012!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-2-16-released-welcome-to-2012/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-2-16-released-welcome-to-2012/</guid><description>It’s been a while since we last blogged about a Selenium release. Since the release of 2.0, we’ve been attempting to give you a fresh and shiny Selenium release every week (though, in reality, we’re managing to get you one every 10 days on average). This allows you to pick the version that’s most suitable for you and your teams, but provides a route for quick feedback on how we’re doing.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.9 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-9-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-9-released/</guid><description>We’re pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.9. As well as improving the stability of Grid under high loads, we’ve added an experimental (and temporary!) feature that allows the Firefox driver to use a different mechanism for determining when a page is loaded. This is designed to handle the case where the driver appears to hang, as it’s waiting for all incoming requests to complete before continuing. How to enable this mode is listed in the changelog.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.8 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-8-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-8-released/</guid><description>In keeping with our (roughly) weekly releases, Selenium 2.8 was released today (and on Maven too), with a *huge* list of bug-fixes! As well as improved stability, if you’re using the Java API, this release adds the ability to upload files to a RemoteWebDriver server (see RemoteWebDriver.setFileDetector (http://selenium.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/docs/api/java/org/openqa/selenium/remote/RemoteWebDriver.html#setFileDetector(org.openqa.selenium.remote.FileDetector))).
Particular thanks have to go out to our two newest committers, Alexei Barancev and Ajay Kemparaj, for the copious bug-fixes they’ve contributed!</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.6 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-6-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-6-released/</guid><description>If you’ve been watching this blog carefully you’ll have noticed that the last release announcement we made was for 2.3, so it may come as a surprise that we’re announcing that 2.6 has been released (even on Maven!). Don’t worry: 2.4 and 2.5 were released on time and without muss or fuss. 2.6, on the other hand has been almost three weeks brewing.
Selenium 2.6 introduces a raft of improvements and stability fixes.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.3 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-3-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-3-released/</guid><description>Continuing our new tradition of weekly releases, we’re very pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.3. The release notes for this version are pretty slim:
Better detection of clickable areas in Firefox. Merge of Google-contributed code into the underlying javascript libraries used by the drivers. We’ve also fixed bugs, one of which was being a nuisance for users of IBM’s JRE. The complete changelog can be found in the zipped downloads or in our source tree (http://selenium.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.2 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-2-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-2-released/</guid><description>The feedback from the last release was heard loud and clear: little and often it is!
We’re proud to announce the release of Selenium 2.2. What’s new this time? For many users, this is simply a bug fix release as there are no new major features. One thing you might appreciate is better exceptions (http://selenium.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/docs/api/java/org/openqa/selenium/IllegalLocatorException.html) being thrown when xpath searches return something other than a web element when using the WebDriver APIs, and we’re continuing to tweak the emulation of user events.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.1 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-1-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-1-released/</guid><description>Now that Selenium 2 has been released, one of the goals of the project is to provide regular updates to our users and the community. The aim is for these updates to be small and manageable, incrementally addressing issues and problems raised by you. Selenium 2.1, which is launched today, marks the first of these regular, small releases.
Selenium 2.1 is largely focused on improving Grid with a host of minor improvements including better tracking of “orphaned” browser instances.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0: Out Now!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0/</guid><description>We are very, very pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.0. If you’ve been waiting for a stable release since 1.0.3, now’s the chance to update. And if you do, what will you find?
For users of Selenium 1, this is a drop-in replacement. You’ll find support for modern browsers such as Firefox 5 and IE 9, as well as a wealth of bug fixes and stability improvements. That’s one reason to update, but what other reasons are there?</description></item><item><title>New ChromeDriver</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/new-chromedriver/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/new-chromedriver/</guid><description>The ChromeDriver is composed of two major pieces. There are the client APIs, which you use in your tests, and there’s a server part, which the client APIs know how to start and run and which takes the form of an executable called “chromedriver”. The server piece is maintained by the Chromium team, and they’ve just released a new version, with support for Chrome 14 and with bug fixes. If you’re using Selenium 2.</description></item><item><title>Selenium IDE 1.0.12 – now with Firefox 5 support</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-ide-1-0-12-firefox-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-ide-1-0-12-firefox-5/</guid><description>Last week we quietly released Selenium IDE 1.0.12 on the website. It has Firefox 5 support along with other improvements. See the release notes and unofficial announcement. Download it here or ask Firefox to check for plugins updates.
And for those who did not download 1.0.11 (it was not pushed through the update system) you will want to read about the formatter change that landed.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0rc3: The “Next One’s The Big One” Release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc3-the-next-ones-the-big-one-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc3-the-next-ones-the-big-one-release/</guid><description>When we pushed the 2.0rc1 live, we really hoped that the next release would be 2.0 final. We very quickly got some feedback that encouraged us to push a 2.0rc2. Now, after just under three weeks, we’re launching a third and final release candidate. You can download it from the Selenium HQ site or directly from Google Code.
We think we’ve addressed many of the common issues, added some polish and added a host of bug fixes and minor changes, and we hope to hear your feedback!</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0rc2: The Better Working Release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc2-the-better-working-release/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc2-the-better-working-release/</guid><description>You win some and you lose some. We’d been really pleased to get Selenium 2.0rc1 out, so we were pretty disappointed to hear that some of you were running into problems with the Java version of the IE driver not launching IE sometimes. That’s definitely not good, so we fixed the problems and have released Selenium 2.0rc2. It’s the same as rc1, but with fewer problems 🙂
We’re still very keen to hear your feedback!</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0rc1: The Grid Release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc1-the-grid-release/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc1-the-grid-release/</guid><description>We’re very happy to announce the first Release Candidate for Selenium 2, available for Java, C#, Ruby and Python. The API has been stabilised and the functionality needed for the final 2.0 release is mostly in. We’re going to be working hard to get there as soon as possible, but now’s the perfect time to test the waters and provide us with any feedback you may have! Grab the downloads from the site!</description></item><item><title>Selenium IDE 1.0.11 – Now with Firefox 4 Support!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-ide-1-0-11-now-with-firefox-4-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-ide-1-0-11-now-with-firefox-4-support/</guid><description>We know that you have been waiting eagerly for this release and you have to wait no more. Selenium IDE 1.0.11 is now here and you can get it from the seleniumhq download site. The update will also be pushed to you automatically over the next couple days.
Other things of note around this release
•Release Notes
•Where to log bugs
•Welcome Selenium IDE 1.0.11 (with Firefox 4 support)</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0b3: The Next Gen Browser Release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0b3-the-next-gen-browser-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0b3-the-next-gen-browser-release/</guid><description>It’s been about 5 weeks since the release of beta 2, so we’re very pleased to announce that Selenium 2.0b3 has just been released simultaneously for Java, .Net, Ruby and Python. You can download it from Selenium HQ or from the Google Code site. This release focused on providing excellent support for the next generation of browsers, particularly IE 9 and Firefox 4, and we think you’ll like what you’ll find.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0b2 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0b2-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0b2-released/</guid><description>We’ve just released Selenium 2.0b2. If you’re the impatient sort who loves to have the latest and greatest, head over to the download site and get it while it’s hot. If you’re a Python user, then all you need to do is a simple “pip install -U selenium”. Ruby users can, as ever, simply run “gem install selenium-webdriver”. Maven users need to wait just a little bit longer: we’re going to be checking the release in ASAP.</description></item><item><title>OperaDriver Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/operadriver_released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/operadriver_released/</guid><description>I think the word that I’m looking for is “wow”. Perhaps “Wow!” would express the concept a little more clearly. Perhaps “WOW!” would be even clearer. Yes, definitely. “WOW!” is a good way of describing this.
Before Christmas, Opera Software announced a pre-release of OperaWatir, an implementation of the Watir 2 API. What you may not know is that Watir 2 rests on the same WebDriver core as Selenium 2. Today, Opera made the source of the OperaDriver available on github: https://github.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0 beta 1 Release</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0-beta-1-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0-beta-1-release/</guid><description>We recently released the first of the betas for Selenium 2. It’s available for Java, C# and Ruby. If you’ve been holding off trying Selenium 2 because of the alpha label, then the biggest improvement you’ll see is with the new WebDriver APIs, but there’s a lot more!
A promise of relatively stable APIs For Firefox only right now, an API for dealing with alerts, prompts and confirms (http://selenium.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/docs/api/java/org/openqa/selenium/WebDriver.TargetLocator.html#alert()). A brand new IE driver.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0a6 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a6-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a6-released/</guid><description>We are extremely pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.0a6! Head over to the downloads page to get it while it’s hot, or wait just a little bit longer for it to appear in a maven repo near you. The .Net version will also be updated soon too, and the python and ruby libraries have been having smaller, more frequent releases all this time.
You’ll be pleased to hear that the Selenium 1.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0a5 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a5-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a5-released/</guid><description>I’m pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.0a5, available for immediate download. This release brings a host of changes under the hood, and represents the efforts of many contributors. Highlights include:
New interfaces (http://selenium.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/docs/api/java/org/openqa/selenium/html5/package-frame.html) for dealing with HTML 5 elements. An API for implicit waits (http://selenium.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/docs/api/java/org/openqa/selenium/WebDriver.Timeouts.html): quietly waiting until an element is present before continuing with a test. You can use them like this: driver.manage().timeouts().implicitlyWait(15, TimeUnit.SECONDS) A revamped Firefox driver.</description></item><item><title>Selenium IDE – Looking back and looking forward</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-looking-back-and-looking-forward/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-looking-back-and-looking-forward/</guid><description>Its been around six months and three releases since I took the reins of Selenium-IDE. The fundamental change in that time has been the adoption of a plugin model like the fine folks over that Firebug. (We’re also self-hosting it which is big from a project internals perspective.)
Right now, you can add custom user-extensions and formatters, but in the very near future you will be able to add location strategies as well.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Grid 1.0.8 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-8-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-8-released/</guid><description>We’re pleased to announce the release of Selenium Grid 1.0.8. This release fixes multithreaded issues with the Selenium Grid hub that appeared randomly under heavy load. If you’ve ever seen a log message about HttpClient being accessed by multiple threads, you definitely want to upgrade. Even if you haven’t, this release is highly recommended for all.
You can download it now or view the changelog. The list of changes is:</description></item><item><title>Selenium IDE 1.0.7 – Now with Drag-and-Drop!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-1-0-7-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-1-0-7-released/</guid><description>So its a month later than planned, but Selenium IDE 1.0.7 is now available. The delay was due to some internal build changes and not code, but one of the code changes that is there more than makes up for the delay.
That’s right, drag-and-drop has finally arrived to Se-IDE — though credit lies with Jérémy Hérault for implementing it.
Oh, and if you are Swedish, there is now a localization for you.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Grid 1.0.7 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-7-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-7-released/</guid><description>Following up on the Selenium Grid 1.0.6 release, which was mostly a bug fix release, we’re pleased to announce the release of Selenium Grid 1.0.7. This is another bug fix release that focuses primarily on how Selenium Grid handles browser sessions.
You can download it now or view the changelog. The list of changes are:
Hub now instructs remote controls to shutdown a session if the hub is going to remove it due to being idle for too long Added ability to specify timeout period when waiting for remote controls to become available.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0a3 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a3-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a3-released/</guid><description>Selenium 2.0a3 has been released and can be downloaded from the Selenium project site. This is a major update to 2.0 and all users are encouraged to update. The new features include:
An improved remote protocol. Updating the version of HtmlUnit used to 2.7. Improved support for simulating user interactions with the browser via native events on Linux. Better support for Firefox 3.6. Bug fixes The .Net, Python and Ruby bindings will be updated soon, as will the maven artefacts.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Grid 1.0.6 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-6-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-6-released/</guid><description>Following up on the Selenium Grid 1.0.5 release, which added self-healing features to ease grid management, we’re pleased to announce the release of Selenium Grid 1.0.6. This is a bug fix release for 1.0.5 with some minor new additions.
You can download it now or view the changelog. The summary of changes are:
Fixed some concurrent modification issues that may have resulted in NullPointerExceptions Fixed issue with shutting down workers with Rakefile Added PID file support for hub and worker started via Rakefile, making it easier to use a process monitor such as monit In case you missed the announcement, Philippe is no longer maintaining Selenium Grid.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 1.0.3 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-1-0-3-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-1-0-3-released/</guid><description>Hot off the heals of 1.0.2, we’re releasing Selenium Remote Control 1.0.3. You can download it now (http://selenium.googlecode.com/files/selenium-remote-control-1.0.3.zip).
There is no functional difference between this version and 1.0.2, other than it is packaged up a little nicer and we’ve clarified the relationship between selenium-server and the client drivers. That is: we are not releasing new client drivers with future 1.x releases. The reason is that we locked down the API in version 1.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 1.0.2 Released: Firefox 3.6 and Snow Leopard Support</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-1-0-2-release-firefox-3-6-and-snow-leopard-support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-1-0-2-release-firefox-3-6-and-snow-leopard-support/</guid><description>Today we’re happy to announce that Selenium Remote Control 1.0.2 has been released. While most of our efforts are on Selenium 2.0, we understand that there are millions of Selenium users that still need the 1.x line supported. That’s why we’ve said from the start that our goal is make 2.x 100% backwards compatible with 1.x. And that’s why we’re releasing a new version of Selenium RC today.
Download it here (http://selenium.</description></item></channel></rss>