<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>releases on SeleniumHQ Browser Automation</title>
    <link>https://selenium.dev/categories/releases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in releases on SeleniumHQ Browser Automation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://selenium.dev/categories/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 4.0 Alpha 6 is out!</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2020/selenium-4-alpha-6-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2020/selenium-4-alpha-6-is-out/</guid>
      <description>We are very pleased to announce the release of Selenium 4.0 Alpha 6.
All the information can be seen in different tweets from the project contributors, here they are all in one place:
Happy Friday! I&amp;#39;ve just pushed Selenium 4.0a6 for Java. There&amp;#39;s a lot of nice changes:
* Full remoting of the CDP protocol across the Grid
* The skeleton of our GraphQL support
* Better configuration options, especially for Nodes, via TOML</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium IDE Is Dead, Long Live Selenium IDE! </title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2018/long-live-selenium-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2018/long-live-selenium-ide/</guid>
      <description>In August of 2017 Simon shared the bleak, hard news that as of Firefox 55 Selenium IDE would no longer work. Selenium IDE (or as we’ll refer to it from here on out – the Legacy IDE) was, and is, dead.
Since then quite a lot has happened with the IDE. We have a new version of it which we are referring to as… Selenium IDE!
It is currently in “alpha” and available for use in both Chrome and Firefox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 3.0: Out Now!</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-0-out-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-0-out-now/</guid>
      <description>We are very pleased to announce the release of Selenium 3.0. If you’ve been waiting for a stable release since 2.53.1, now’s your chance to update. And if you do, here is what you’ll find:
As we’ve said before, for users of the WebDriver APIs this is a drop-in replacement. You’ll find that modern browsers, such as Chrome and Edge will continue to work just as before, and we’ve taken the opportunity to fix some bugs and improve stability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 3 is Coming</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>Selenium 3 is coming! As I write this, we think that &amp;#8220;beta 4&amp;#8221; will be the last beta before the official 3.0 release. I’m here to tell you about what’s changed, and what impact this will have on your testing.
TL;DR:  WebDriver users will just find bug fixes and a drop-in replacement for 2.x. Selenium Grid users will also find bug fixes and a simple update. The WebDriver APIs are now the only APIs actively supported by the Selenium project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Selenium 3.0-beta1</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2016/announcing-selenium-3-0-beta1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2016/announcing-selenium-3-0-beta1/</guid>
      <description>At SeleniumConf in 2013, we announced that a new major version of Selenium would be released &amp;#8220;by Christmas&amp;#8221;. Fortunately, we never said which Christmas, as it has taken us a while to make all the changes we wanted to make! We&amp;#8217;re excited to announce the release of the first beta &amp;#8212; Selenium 3.0.0-beta1.
We&amp;#8217;d love you to try it out on your projects, and provide us with feedback on where the rough edges are before we ship the 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Selenium 2.26: the “It’s Really Real” Release</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-26/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s been a long time since we announced a new Selenium release on this blog, as we moved to a model of quicker releases, but we&amp;#8217;ve been working on 2.26 for far longer than normal &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;s out! Download it now! &amp;#8212; so I thought it best to let you know. We&amp;#8217;re aiming to head back to faster releases, so hopefully you won&amp;#8217;t see another blog post about the release for a while (though I&amp;#8217;m sure they&amp;#8217;ll appear in the &amp;#8220;Smatterings of Selenium&amp;#8221; posts)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Selenium 2.22</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-22/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s been a while since the last Selenium release, but I&amp;#8217;m happy to announce that Selenium 2.22 is now available for download. This is a big release for us and features two major changes.
The first is that Selenium 2.22 is the first version that requires Java 6 in order to run. This has been the case for the Selenium Server for some time, but this is the first time the client code has required Java 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Selenium 2.19: the Prancing Unicorn release</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-19-the-prancing-unicorn-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2012/announcing-selenium-2-19-the-prancing-unicorn-release/</guid>
      <description>You might be pleased to hear that Selenium 2.19 has been released (download it from here!). There&amp;#8217;s one big user facing changing that we&amp;#8217;d like to tell you about: the webdriver-backed selenium can now be used in supported languages.
By providing this capability, it&amp;#8217;s possible to migrate from RC to the WebDriver APIs without rewriting all your tests in one fell swoop (which must be a Good Thing, right?) An example of how to use it in Python would be:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.16 Released: Welcome to 2012!</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-2-16-released-welcome-to-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-2-16-released-welcome-to-2012/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s been a while since we last blogged about a Selenium release. Since the release of 2.0, we&amp;#8217;ve been attempting to give you a fresh and shiny Selenium release every week (though, in reality, we&amp;#8217;re managing to get you one every 10 days on average). This allows you to pick the version that&amp;#8217;s most suitable for you and your teams, but provides a route for quick feedback on how we&amp;#8217;re doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.9 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-9-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-9-released/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;#8217;re pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.9. As well as improving the stability of Grid under high loads, we&amp;#8217;ve added an experimental (and temporary!) feature that allows the Firefox driver to use a different mechanism for determining when a page is loaded. This is designed to handle the case where the driver appears to hang, as it&amp;#8217;s waiting for all incoming requests to complete before continuing. How to enable this mode is listed in the changelog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.8 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-8-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-8-released/</guid>
      <description>In keeping with our (roughly) weekly releases, Selenium 2.8 was released today (and on Maven too), with a *huge* list of bug-fixes! As well as improved stability, if you&amp;#8217;re using the Java API, this release adds the ability to upload files to a RemoteWebDriver server (see RemoteWebDriver.setFileDetector).
Particular thanks have to go out to our two newest committers, Alexei Barancev and Ajay Kemparaj, for the copious bug-fixes they&amp;#8217;ve contributed!
We&amp;#8217;re already hard at work getting 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.6 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-6-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-6-released/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;#8217;ve been watching this blog carefully you&amp;#8217;ll have noticed that the last release announcement we made was for 2.3, so it may come as a surprise that we&amp;#8217;re announcing that 2.6 has been released (even on Maven!). Don&amp;#8217;t worry: 2.4 and 2.5 were released on time and without muss or fuss. 2.6, on the other hand has been almost three weeks brewing.
Selenium 2.6 introduces a raft of improvements and stability fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.3 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-3-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-3-released/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our new tradition of weekly releases, we&amp;#8217;re very pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.3. The release notes for this version are pretty slim:
 Better detection of clickable areas in Firefox. Merge of Google-contributed code into the underlying javascript libraries used by the drivers.  We&amp;#8217;ve also fixed bugs, one of which was being a nuisance for users of IBM&amp;#8217;s JRE. The complete changelog can be found in the zipped downloads or in our source tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.2 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-2-released/</guid>
      <description>The feedback from the last release was heard loud and clear: little and often it is!
We&amp;#8217;re proud to announce the release of Selenium 2.2. What&amp;#8217;s new this time? For many users, this is simply a bug fix release as there are no new major features. One thing you might appreciate is better exceptions being thrown when xpath searches return something other than a web element when using the WebDriver APIs, and we&amp;#8217;re continuing to tweak the emulation of user events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.1 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-1-released/</guid>
      <description>Now that Selenium 2 has been released, one of the goals of the project is to provide regular updates to our users and the community. The aim is for these updates to be small and manageable, incrementally addressing issues and problems raised by you. Selenium 2.1, which is launched today, marks the first of these regular, small releases.
Selenium 2.1 is largely focused on improving Grid with a host of minor improvements including better tracking of &amp;#8220;orphaned&amp;#8221; browser instances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.0: Out Now!</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0/</guid>
      <description>We are very, very pleased to announce therelease of Selenium 2.0. If you&amp;#8217;ve been waiting for a stable release since 1.0.3, now&amp;#8217;s the chance to update. And if you do, what will you find?
For users of Selenium 1, this is a drop-in replacement. You&amp;#8217;ll find support for modern browsers such as Firefox 5 and IE 9, as well as a wealth of bug fixes and stability improvements. That&amp;#8217;s one reason to update, but what other reasons are there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New ChromeDriver</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/new-chromedriver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/new-chromedriver/</guid>
      <description>The ChromeDriver is composed of two major pieces. There are the client APIs, which you use in your tests, and there&amp;#8217;s a server part, which the client APIs know how to start and run and which takes the form of an executable called &amp;#8220;chromedriver&amp;#8221;. The server piece is maintained by the Chromium team, and they&amp;#8217;ve just released a new version, with support for Chrome 14 and with bug fixes. If you&amp;#8217;re using Selenium 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium IDE 1.0.12 – now with Firefox 5 support</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-ide-1-0-12-firefox-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-ide-1-0-12-firefox-5/</guid>
      <description>Last week we quietly released Selenium IDE 1.0.12 on the website. It has Firefox 5 support along with other improvements. See the release notes and unofficial announcement. Download it here or ask Firefox to check for plugins updates.
And for those who did not download 1.0.11 (it was not pushed through the update system) you will want to read about the formatter change that landed. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.0rc3: The “Next One’s The Big One” Release</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc3-the-next-ones-the-big-one-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc3-the-next-ones-the-big-one-release/</guid>
      <description>When we pushed the 2.0rc1 live, we really hoped that the next release would be 2.0 final. We very quickly got some feedback that encouraged us to push a 2.0rc2. Now, after just under three weeks, we&amp;#8217;re launching a third and final release candidate. You can download it from the Selenium HQ site or directly from Google Code.
We think we&amp;#8217;ve addressed many of the common issues, added some polish and added a host of bug fixes and minor changes, and we hope to hear your feedback!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.0rc2: The Better Working Release</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc2-the-better-working-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc2-the-better-working-release/</guid>
      <description>You win some and you lose some. We&amp;#8217;d been really pleased to get Selenium 2.0rc1 out, so we were pretty disappointed to hear that some of you were running into problems with the Java version of the IE driver not launching IE sometimes. That&amp;#8217;s definitely not good, so we fixed the problems and havereleased Selenium 2.0rc2. It&amp;#8217;s the same as rc1, but with fewer problems 🙂
We&amp;#8217;re still very keen to hear your feedback!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.0rc1: The Grid Release</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc1-the-grid-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0rc1-the-grid-release/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;#8217;re very happy to announce the first Release Candidate for Selenium 2, available for Java, C#, Ruby and Python. The API has been stabilised and the functionality needed for the final 2.0 release is mostly in. We’re going to be working hard to get there as soon as possible, but now’s the perfect time to test the waters and provide us with any feedback you may have! Grab the downloads from the site!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium IDE 1.0.11 – Now with Firefox 4 Support!</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-ide-1-0-11-now-with-firefox-4-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-ide-1-0-11-now-with-firefox-4-support/</guid>
      <description>We know that you have been waiting eagerly for this release and you have to wait no more. Selenium IDE 1.0.11 is now here and you can get it from the seleniumhq download site. The update will also be pushed to you automatically over the next couple days.
Other things of note around this release
•Release Notes
•Where to log bugs
•Welcome Selenium IDE 1.0.11 (with Firefox 4 support)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.0b3: The Next Gen Browser Release</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0b3-the-next-gen-browser-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0b3-the-next-gen-browser-release/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s been about 5 weeks since the release of beta 2, so we&amp;#8217;re very pleased to announce that Selenium 2.0b3 has just been released simultaneously for Java, .Net, Ruby and Python. You can download it from Selenium HQ or from the Google Code site. This release focused on providing excellent support for the next generation of browsers, particularly IE 9 and Firefox 4, and we think you&amp;#8217;ll like what you&amp;#8217;ll find.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.0b2 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0b2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-2-0b2-released/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;#8217;ve just released Selenium 2.0b2. If you&amp;#8217;re the impatient sort who loves to have the latest and greatest, head over to thedownload site and get it while it&amp;#8217;s hot. If you&amp;#8217;re a Python user, then all you need to do is a simple &amp;#8220;pip install -U selenium&amp;#8221;. Ruby users can, as ever, simply run &amp;#8220;gem install selenium-webdriver&amp;#8221;. Maven users need to wait just a little bit longer: we&amp;#8217;re going to be checking the release in ASAP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OperaDriver Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/operadriver_released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2011/operadriver_released/</guid>
      <description>I think the word that I&amp;#8217;m looking for is &amp;#8220;wow&amp;#8221;. Perhaps &amp;#8220;Wow!&amp;#8221; would express the concept a little more clearly. Perhaps &amp;#8220;WOW!&amp;#8221; would be even clearer. Yes, definitely. &amp;#8220;WOW!&amp;#8221; is a good way of describing this.
Before Christmas, Opera Software announced a pre-release of OperaWatir, an implementation of the Watir 2 API. What you may not know is that Watir 2 rests on the same WebDriver core as Selenium 2. Today, Opera made the source of the OperaDriver available on github: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.0 beta 1 Release</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0-beta-1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0-beta-1-release/</guid>
      <description>We recently released the first of the betas for Selenium 2. It&amp;#8217;s available for Java, C# and Ruby. If you&amp;#8217;ve been holding off trying Selenium 2 because of the alpha label, then the biggest improvement you&amp;#8217;ll see is with the new WebDriver APIs, but there&amp;#8217;s a lot more!
 A promise of relatively stable APIs For Firefox only right now, an API for dealing with alerts, prompts and confirms. A brand new IE driver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.0a6 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a6-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a6-released/</guid>
      <description>We are extremely pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.0a6! Head over to the downloads page to get it while it&amp;#8217;s hot, or wait just a little bit longer for it to appear in a maven repo near you. The .Net version will also be updated soon too, and the python and ruby libraries have been having smaller, more frequent releases all this time.
You&amp;#8217;ll be pleased to hear that the Selenium 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.0a5 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a5-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a5-released/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m pleased to announce the release of Selenium 2.0a5, available for immediate download. This release brings a host of changes under the hood, and represents the efforts of many contributors. Highlights include:
 Newinterfaces for dealing with HTML 5 elements. An API for &amp;#8220;implicit waits&amp;#8220;: quietly waiting until an element is present before continuing with a test. You can use them like this: driver.manage().timeouts().implicitlyWait(15, TimeUnit.SECONDS) A revamped Firefox driver. More shared code between Selenium and WebDriver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium-IDE – Looking back and looking forward</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-looking-back-and-looking-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-looking-back-and-looking-forward/</guid>
      <description>Its been around six months and three releases since I took the reins of Selenium-IDE. The fundamental change in that time has been the adoption of a plugin model like the fine folks over that Firebug. (We&amp;#8217;re also self-hosting it which is big from a project internals perspective.)
Right now, you can add custom user-extensions and formatters, but in the very near future you will be able to add location strategies as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium Grid 1.0.8 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-8-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-8-released/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;#8217;re pleased to announce the release of Selenium Grid 1.0.8. This release fixes multithreaded issues with the Selenium Grid hub that appeared randomly under heavy load. If you&amp;#8217;ve ever seen a log message about HttpClient being accessed by multiple threads, you definitely want to upgrade. Even if you haven&amp;#8217;t, this release is highly recommended for all.
You can download it now or view the changelog. The list of changes is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium IDE 1.0.7 – Now with Drag-and-Drop!</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-1-0-7-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-ide-1-0-7-released/</guid>
      <description>So its a month later than planned, but Selenium IDE 1.0.7 is now available. The delay was due to some internal build changes and not code, but one of the code changes that is there more than makes up for the delay.
That&amp;#8217;s right, drag-and-drop has finally arrived to Se-IDE &amp;#8212; though credit lies with Jérémy Hérault for implementing it.
Oh, and if you are Swedish, there is now a localization for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium Grid 1.0.7 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-7-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-7-released/</guid>
      <description>Following up on the Selenium Grid 1.0.6 release, which was mostly a bug fix release, we&amp;#8217;re pleased to announce the release of Selenium Grid 1.0.7. This is another bug fix release that focuses primarily on how Selenium Grid handles browser sessions.
You can download it now or view the changelog. The list of changes are:
 Hub now instructs remote controls to shutdown a session if the hub is going to remove it due to being idle for too long Added ability to specify timeout period when waiting for remote controls to become available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 2.0a3 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a3-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0a3-released/</guid>
      <description>Selenium 2.0a3 has been released and can be downloaded from the Selenium project site. This is a major update to 2.0 and all users are encouraged to update. The new features include:
 An improved remote protocol. Updating the version of HtmlUnit used to 2.7. Improved support for simulating user interactions with the browser via native events on Linux. Better support for Firefox 3.6. Bug fixes  The .Net, Python and Ruby bindings will be updated soon, as will the maven artefacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium Grid 1.0.6 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-6-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-grid-1-0-6-released/</guid>
      <description>Following up on the Selenium Grid 1.0.5 release, which added self-healing features to ease grid management, we&amp;#8217;re pleased to announce the release of Selenium Grid 1.0.6. This is a bug fix release for 1.0.5 with some minor new additions.
You can download it now or view the changelog. The summary of changes are:
 Fixed some concurrent modification issues that may have resulted in NullPointerExceptions Fixed issue with shutting down workers with Rakefile Added PID file support for hub and worker started via Rakefile, making it easier to use a process monitor such as monit  In case you missed the announcement, Philippe is no longer maintaining Selenium Grid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 1.0.3 Released</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-1-0-3-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-1-0-3-released/</guid>
      <description>Hot off the heals of 1.0.2, we&amp;#8217;re releasing Selenium Remote Control 1.0.3. You can download it now.
There is no functional difference between this version and 1.0.2, other than it is packaged up a little nicer and we&amp;#8217;ve clarified the relationship between selenium-server and the client drivers. That is: we are not releasing new client drivers with future 1.x releases. The reason is that we locked down the API in version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium 1.0.2 Released: Firefox 3.6 and Snow Leopard Support</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-1-0-2-release-firefox-3-6-and-snow-leopard-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-1-0-2-release-firefox-3-6-and-snow-leopard-support/</guid>
      <description>Today we&amp;#8217;re happy to announce that Selenium Remote Control 1.0.2 has been released. While most of our efforts are on Selenium 2.0, we understand that there are millions of Selenium users that still need the 1.x line supported. That&amp;#8217;s why we&amp;#8217;ve said from the start that our goal is make 2.x 100% backwards compatible with 1.x. And that&amp;#8217;s why we&amp;#8217;re releasing a new version of Selenium RC today.
Download it here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>