<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Einführung on Dokumentation für Selenium</title>
    <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/de/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Einführung on Dokumentation für Selenium</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>2013-{year}</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://selenium.dev/documentation/de/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Das Seleniumprojekt und die Tools</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/de/introduction/the_selenium_project_and_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/de/introduction/the_selenium_project_and_tools/</guid>
      <description>Diese Seite wird von Englisch auf Deutsch übersetzt. Sprichst Du Deutsch? Hilf uns die Seite zu übersetzen indem Du uns einen Pull Reqeust schickst!
 Selenium controls web browsers Selenium is many things but at its core, it is a toolset for web browser automation that uses the best techniques available to remotely control browser instances and emulate a user&amp;rsquo;s interaction with the browser.
It allows users to simulate common activities performed by end-users; entering text into fields, selecting drop-down values and checking boxes, and clicking links in documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testautomatisierung</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/de/introduction/on_test_automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/de/introduction/on_test_automation/</guid>
      <description>Diese Seite wird von Englisch auf Deutsch übersetzt. Sprichst Du Deutsch? Hilf uns die Seite zu übersetzen indem Du uns einen Pull Reqeust schickst!
 First, start by asking yourself whether or not you really need to use a browser. Odds are that, at some point, if you are working on a complex web application, you will need to open a browser and actually test it.
Functional end-user tests such as Selenium tests are expensive to run, however.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testarten</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/de/introduction/types_of_testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/de/introduction/types_of_testing/</guid>
      <description>Diese Seite wird von Englisch auf Deutsch übersetzt. Sprichst Du Deutsch? Hilf uns die Seite zu übersetzen indem Du uns einen Pull Reqeust schickst!
 Acceptance testing This type of test is done to determine if a product&amp;rsquo;s feature matches its requirements. This generally involves the customer&amp;rsquo;s feedback or specification.
For web applications, the automation of this testing can be done directly with Selenium by simulating user expected behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Über diese Dokumentation</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/de/introduction/about_this_documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/de/introduction/about_this_documentation/</guid>
      <description>Diese Dokumentation wird so wie auch der Sourcecode von Selenium zu 100% von der Selenium Community gepflegt. Von Anfang an haben zahlreiche Benutzer diese Dokumentation verwendet. Viele haben Sie auch nur für einen sehr kurzen Zeitraum genutzt und haben Zeit investiert um für Neulinge den Einstieg in das Thema zu erleichtern.
Falls Du einen Fehler in der Dokumentation entdeckst, freuen wir uns wenn Du uns darauf aufmerksam machst. Der beste Weg uns das mitzuteilen ist es einen Issue (engl.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>