<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>General on Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/categories/general/</link><description>Recent content in General on Selenium</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 09:28:08 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sauce Labs: A New Milestone with Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/saucelabs-selenium-partnership/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/saucelabs-selenium-partnership/</guid><description>Selenium has witnessed an exceptional year filled with expansion and progress. The rising popularity of Selenium&amp;rsquo;s Python Bindings is prominently showcased through the engaging discussions at the Selenium Conference and on LinkedIn. Concurrently, the Java bindings have reached a significant landmark, surpassing 100 million downloads. In addition to this, the community has managed to garner over 2.5 million active Selenium users monthly.
We could not have achieved Selenium&amp;rsquo;s 20th anniversary without the collective efforts of numerous volunteers and the invaluable assistance of a company like Sauce Labs.</description></item><item><title>Celebrating a Milestone: BrowserStack Becomes Selenium's Development Partner</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/browserstack-selenium-partnership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/browserstack-selenium-partnership/</guid><description>It has been a great year for the Selenium community as it continues to grow. The popularity of Selenium’s Python Bindings is evident from the discussions at the Selenium Conference and on LinkedIn, while the Java bindings have impressively surpassed 100 million downloads.
This project, having reached 20 years old this year, would not be possible without the amazing contributions from our volunteer contributors and the Open Source Program Offices of companies like BrowserStack that allow us to work on this project as part of our day jobs.</description></item><item><title>Update imports to use BiDi Java</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/bidi-java-breaking-change/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/bidi-java-breaking-change/</guid><description>What part of the code base is impacted? Selenium WebDriver BiDi APIs in Java bindings are impacted.
What is impacted by the breaking change? The WebDriver BiDi APIs stay as they are, so you can continue to use them. However, the import statements need to be updated.
What is the breaking change? The import statements need to be updated when using the BiDi APIs.
Before Selenium 4.19: Java import org.openqa.selenium.bidi.LogInspector; import org.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Vs … blog posts</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-vs-blog-posts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2024/selenium-vs-blog-posts/</guid><description>The easiest way to clickbait a blog post about automated testing is to compare Selenium against another tool in the space with a catchy title especially when it talks down about the incumbent.
Unfortunately, this can lead to muddying the waters of which features are available in any of the products out there especially when we compare apples to apples.
Selenium has always been a great tool for browser automation. Fortunately for the project, it has become the tool of choice for testing web applications for nearly 2 decades.</description></item><item><title>Removal of AbstractEventListener + EventFiringWebDriver + WebDriverEventListener</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/java-removal-of-deprecated-events-classes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/java-removal-of-deprecated-events-classes/</guid><description>Upgrading to WebDriverListener and EventFiringDecorator Decorating the webdriver
new EventFiringWebDriver(driver); // Old approach new EventFiringDecorator().decorate(driver); // New approach Implementing method wrappers One may find the need to have their own custom implementations be used for underlying decorated method calls. An example may be wanting to use your own findElement implementation to store metadata from web elements. One can go down a deep rabbit hole of decorators ( extending WebDriverDecorator and such ), so to keep things simple we will extend EventFiringDecorator since we want a single decorator to handle all our listener events.</description></item><item><title>InvalidSelectorException has changed</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/invalid-selector-exception-has-changed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2023/invalid-selector-exception-has-changed/</guid><description>Before Selenium 4.8.2 in Java and C#, when an invalid locator was used to identify an element, the resulting behavior would be inconsistent in our bindings.
For example, let&amp;rsquo;s check the following code:
ArrayList&amp;lt;Class&amp;lt;? extends Exception&amp;gt;&amp;gt; expectedExceptions = new ArrayList&amp;lt;&amp;gt;(); expectedExceptions.add(org.openqa.selenium.NoSuchElementException.class); expectedExceptions.add(org.openqa.selenium.StaleElementReferenceException.class); expectedExceptions.add(org.openqa.selenium.ElementNotInteractableException.class); expectedExceptions.add(org.openqa.selenium.InvalidElementStateException.class); return new FluentWait&amp;lt;&amp;gt;(driver) .withTimeout(Duration.ofMillis(ELEMENT_IDENTIFICATION_TIMEOUT)) .pollingEvery(Duration.ofMillis(ELEMENT_IDENTIFICATION_POLLING_DELAY)) .ignoreAll(expectedExceptions) .until(nestedDriver -&amp;gt; { nestedDriver.findElement(By.xpath(&amp;#34;invalid-xpath&amp;#34;)).click; }); The expected result before this change would be that the driver waits until the timeout expires and then throw an InvalidSelectorException.</description></item><item><title>Year End Review 2022</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/end-of-year-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/end-of-year-review/</guid><description>It was an amazing year here at the Selenium project, and we wanted to remind you of some of the great things we accomplished.
In terms of releases, we continued to build on top of Selenium 4 which was launched in October 2021. This year we published v4.2, v4.3, v4.4, v4.5, v4.6, and v4.7. These releases included improvements, bug fixes, removal of deprecated functionality, improved error handling, updates of the underlying libraries, support for the latest Chrome DevTools versions to keep you in sync with new browser releases, but also new features.</description></item><item><title>BELLATRIX Test Automation Framework for C# and JAVA</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/bellatrix-test-automation-framework/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/bellatrix-test-automation-framework/</guid><description>Over the last decade, a large ecosystem of Open Source projects has sprouted up around Selenium. Selenium is often used for automating web applications for testing purposes, but it does not include a testing framework. Nowadays, Selenium Ecosystem initiatives try to give popularity to popular open-source test automation frameworks maintained by people outside of the core Selenium maintainers. One of these frameworks is BELLATRIX, invented by Anton Angelov. It has two versions - C# and Java.</description></item><item><title>Dev and Beta Channel Browsers via Docker Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/dev-and-beta-channel-browsers-via-docker-selenium/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/dev-and-beta-channel-browsers-via-docker-selenium/</guid><description>The Docker Selenium browser Beta and Dev channel releases are now regularly published to Docker Hub and updated every two days. This enables testers and developers to test their applications on pre-release versions of Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, and Microsoft Edge before their official releases, using container tools, such as Docker. This empowers teams to stay ahead of the curve and catch potential showstoppers in their CI environment before those issues have an impact on their users.</description></item><item><title>Scaling a Kubernetes Selenium Grid with KEDA</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/scaling-grid-with-keda/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/scaling-grid-with-keda/</guid><description>The Issue If you have any experience with Selenium Grid and Kubernetes you will probably run into an issue with scaling. Kubernetes (K8S) works wonders for scaling up and down applications based on their CPU and Memory usage, but it is not so straightforward when it comes down to applications like Selenium Grid.
The issue is described quite well in this blog post. But in short, the Horizontal Pod AutoScaler (HPA) that is built into Kubernetes checks (by default) for resource consumption to determine if a deployment needs to be scaled up or down.</description></item><item><title>Test Automation Summit Berlin</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/test-automation-summit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/test-automation-summit/</guid><description>Have you ever wanted to contribute to an open source testing project, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out where to start? If so, fill out this form to apply for an invitation to join the Open Source Test Automation Summit on August 26 in Berlin, sponsored by Selenium and hosted by Sauce Labs. You can review the list of available projects below and select the one that you&amp;rsquo;d like to contribute to. We&amp;rsquo;ll be in touch soon if you are selected to join us.</description></item><item><title>Removing Legacy Protocol Support</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/legacy-protocol-support/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/legacy-protocol-support/</guid><description>The Selenium team prides itself on how seriously it takes backwards compatibility. A lot of care has gone into the Java bindings, especially, to ensure very few breaking changes over the years. There is Selenium code written 15 years ago that can still run with Selenium 4 libraries! Providing this exceptional amount of support comes with a large maintenance burden, though, and we need to be able to properly meet the needs of the vast majority of our userbase.</description></item><item><title>Locate your locators - Python bindings changes upcoming</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/python-locators-se4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/python-locators-se4/</guid><description>In real estate, the mantra for finding a new house or office space is &amp;ldquo;location, location, location!&amp;rdquo;. It could be said that when working with Selenium, a critical aspect of writing tests is &amp;ldquo;locators, locators, locators!&amp;rdquo;. Having a robust locator strategy - in your app under test and in your test framework - is highly important for effective testing.
If you are a Pythonista like myself and using Selenium for your test automation, then there are some important changes coming to how locators are defined and used.</description></item><item><title>IE Mode in Edge supported by IEDriver</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/ie-edge-support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2022/ie-edge-support/</guid><description>With the retirement of Internet Explorer 11 (IE 11) later this year, the folks in Redmond have helped the Selenium project with getting IE Mode in Microsoft Edge working in IEDriver.
IE 11 is due to retire on 15 June 2022 for certain versions of Windows 10. After this date, the Selenium project recommends that you test your IE sites with IE Mode in Microsoft Edge. The Selenium Project will not remove support for IE 11 when it retires but we will not actively fix issues as we have done with previous versions of IE.</description></item><item><title>Improving &amp; refining our Docs translations</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/docs-translations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/docs-translations/</guid><description>A while ago, we started to make the Selenium documentation available in more languages. This, in an effort to offer a more inclusive environment for Selenium users who do not have English as their mother tongue.
This effort grew organically, and we got many pull requests adding content for different languages. Over time, some translations got to a very good state, and others didn&amp;rsquo;t get much attention. This brought the situation where 9 different languages are available in the documentation, but only a few add value to the readers.</description></item><item><title>Stepping Down, Stepping Up</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/stepping-down-stepping-up/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/stepping-down-stepping-up/</guid><description>The short version is that I&amp;rsquo;m stepping down as the Selenium project lead, and will concentrating on pushing WebDriver Bidi forwards. Fortunately, the Selenium TLC have already been steering the project for a while now, so it&amp;rsquo;s in excellent hands. With Selenium 4 now shipped, the project has a new energy and enthusiasm about it. The future is bright, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing what it holds.
The longer version?</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4 Release Candidate</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-rc-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-rc-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the first release candidate of Selenium 4. We&amp;rsquo;re shipping this for .Net, Java, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript, so if you&amp;rsquo;re using any of those languages, go and grab it from your package manager of choice!
This release is the result of a lot of work by the Selenium team project, but most importantly, all the Selenium community who tried our beta releases, and gave us great and valuable feedback.</description></item><item><title>All Selenium downloads are now available on GitHub releases</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/downloads-now-on-github-releases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/downloads-now-on-github-releases/</guid><description>We announced on a previous entry our decision to move all binaries from Google Storage to GitHub releases. Today, we would like to announce that this work has been completed and all binaries are also available to be downloaded in each one of the releases we have done in GitHub.
In addition to that, all links on our downloads page have been updated, as well as all references to Google Storage in the Selenium code base.</description></item><item><title>Selenium downloads will move to GitHub releases</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/downloads-moving-to-github-releases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/downloads-moving-to-github-releases/</guid><description>Thanks to Google, Google Storage has been the central place where we have been able to upload all binaries created for each Selenium release, and the place where the Selenium community can download them from. To do so, all people needed to do was visit our downloads page, find the release, and download from there!
The Selenium project hosts its source code on GitHub, and people who are familiar with GitHub know that they can go to the &amp;ldquo;release&amp;rdquo; page there to find any downloads for each release of a project.</description></item><item><title>The Selenium website has a new look!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/new-look-for-selenium-site/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/new-look-for-selenium-site/</guid><description>We have been working hard during the last few weeks redoing our website. Today, we are very happy to share it with the community and we are hoping to get as much feedback as possible!
We did a major revamp to our website two years ago. However, this revamp had some &amp;ldquo;technical debt&amp;rdquo; in it&amp;hellip;
We&amp;#39;re happy to announce that we have (finally!) refreshed our site. Head on over to https://t.</description></item><item><title>IRC channels are moving to Libera.chat</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/moving-to-libera-chat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/moving-to-libera-chat/</guid><description>Yesterday, 19 May 2021, all the staff of Freenode, the IRC network, collectively resigned as staff because of what they felt was a hostile takeover.
Freenode has always been seen as the home of Free and Open Software, so it was natural that you could find us on the #selenium channel there. To maintain this openness, and inclusivity, we are moving our IRC Channel over to Libera.chat. It is has been created by the team that previously maintained Freenode.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4 Beta 1 Released</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-beta-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-4-beta-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce the release of the first beta of Selenium 4. We&amp;rsquo;re shipping this for Java, .Net, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript, so if you&amp;rsquo;re using any of those languages, go and grab it from your package manager of choice!
This has been the culmination of a lot of work by so many people, not only the project TLC, but also of literally hundreds of people: 205 since we released Selenium 3.</description></item><item><title>New Tricks in Selenium 4</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-the-new-selenium-grid/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-the-new-selenium-grid/</guid><description>In the fourth and final post in his series, Simon Stewart continues talking about what&amp;rsquo;s coming in Selenium 4 and reviews what&amp;rsquo;s new in the Selenium Grid.
We’ve covered a lot of ground in the past few blog posts, including how to contribute to the project, and some details of what you can expect as a Selenium user. But there’s more to Selenium than just the APIs you use to write your tests, and one of the big features we’ve not covered yet is the refreshed Selenium Grid: a mechanism that allows you to distribute your tests across a fleet of machines.</description></item><item><title>Results of the first ever selenium survey</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-survey-results/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2021/selenium-survey-results/</guid><description>Below is a summary of the Selenium survey that was collected.
Batteries included Browser Management Unsurprisingly, people find having to manage browsers a task they wish they didn’t have to do and wish that Selenium did this. 59.5% of respondents want Selenium to manage the browsers for them. This, though the question didn’t ask this, is to include the browser drivers.
Frameworks The results show an interesting view into framework usage.</description></item><item><title>New Tricks in Selenium 4</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-new-tricks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-new-tricks/</guid><description>In the third post in his series, Simon Stewart continues talking about what&amp;rsquo;s coming in Selenium 4 and reviews some of the tricks in the new release.
In my last posts, we talked about how to contribute to Selenium, and why we’re bumping the version number to 4. That’s enough preamble! Today, we’ll cover some details about the new tricks and capabilities that Selenium 4 offers.
Finding Elements, and Relative Locators You know, finding elements on a page can be really difficult.</description></item><item><title>What’s Coming in Selenium 4: Why The Major Version Bump?</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-why-the-major-version-bump/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-why-the-major-version-bump/</guid><description>In the second post in this series, Simon Stewart continues talking about what&amp;rsquo;s coming in Selenium 4 and why this release has a major version bump.
In my last post, I shared a bit about how the Selenium project works overall. Now, let’s start talking about Selenium 4 and what’s coming. One thing I think I should clear up is &amp;ldquo;why the major version number bump?&amp;rdquo;
Sometimes I joke that the major reason for the version number bump is that while the digits of Pi are infinite, when we went from 3.</description></item><item><title>What’s Coming in Selenium 4: How Can I Contribute?</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-how-can-i-contribute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/what-is-coming-in-selenium-4-how-can-i-contribute/</guid><description>In this new blog series all about the upcoming release of Selenium 4, Simon Stewart will cover how the Selenium project works, who is involved, how you can get involved, and a sneak peek at what’s new in Selenium 4.
As the lead of the Selenium project, I wanted to kick off a new blog series leading up to the release of Selenium 4. During this series, I’ll talk all about how the Selenium project works, who is involved, how you—yes, you!</description></item><item><title>Browser Testing and Tools WG Meeting @ TPAC 2020</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/webdriver-tpac-meeting-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/webdriver-tpac-meeting-2020/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of the year where working groups from the W3C meet up to discuss the various standards that are being worked on.
Within the Browser Testing and Tools Working Group, there are 2 different standards.
We have:
WebDriver WebDriver-Bidi The first is what is commonly supported by the Selenium Project and has support from Apple, Mozilla, Microsoft, and Google in their browsers. It is also supported by various Selenium in the cloud providers like Sauce Labs and BrowserStack.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 4.0 Alpha 6 is out!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/selenium-4-alpha-6-is-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2020/selenium-4-alpha-6-is-out/</guid><description>We are very pleased to announce the release of Selenium 4.0 Alpha 6.
All the information can be seen in different tweets from the project contributors, here they are all in one place:
Happy Friday! I&amp;#39;ve just pushed Selenium 4.0a6 for Java. There&amp;#39;s a lot of nice changes:
* Full remoting of the CDP protocol across the Grid
* The skeleton of our GraphQL support
* Better configuration options, especially for Nodes, via TOML</description></item><item><title>Selenium IDE Is Dead, Long Live Selenium IDE!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2018/long-live-selenium-ide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2018/long-live-selenium-ide/</guid><description>In August of 2017 Simon shared the bleak, hard news that as of Firefox 55 Selenium IDE would no longer work. Selenium IDE (or as we’ll refer to it from here on out – the Legacy IDE) was, and is, dead.
Since then quite a lot has happened with the IDE. We have a new version of it which we are referring to as… Selenium IDE!
It is currently in “alpha” and available for use in both Chrome and Firefox.</description></item><item><title>Firefox 55 and Selenium IDE</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2017/firefox-55-and-selenium-ide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2017/firefox-55-and-selenium-ide/</guid><description>The bad news: from Firefox 55 onwards, Selenium IDE will no longer work.
The reasons for this are complex, but boil down to two main causes:
Browsers are complicated pieces of software that are constantly evolving. Mozilla has been working hard to make Firefox faster and more stable, while still retaining the flexibility and ease of extension that we’ve come to know and love. As part of that process, Firefox is switching extensions from the original “XPI” format, to a newer, more widely adopted “Web Extension” mechanism.</description></item><item><title>Hacking with IntelliJ</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2017/hacking-with-intellij/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2017/hacking-with-intellij/</guid><description>Jetbrains have a programme for Open Source projects which allows them to receive IntelliJ IDEA licenses. As part of that programme, which the Selenium project has participated in for many years, they’ve asked us to provide a fair and balanced review of IntelliJ. I’ll attempt to do that, and I’ll try and state my biases up-front so you’re aware of them.
I’ve been using Jetbrain’s IntelliJ to hack on the Selenium code since I started working on it slightly over ten years ago.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 3.0: Out Now!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-0-out-now/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-0-out-now/</guid><description>We are very pleased to announce the release of Selenium 3.0. If you’ve been waiting for a stable release since 2.53.1, now’s your chance to update. And if you do, here is what you’ll find:
As we’ve said before, for users of the WebDriver APIs this is a drop-in replacement. You’ll find that modern browsers, such as Chrome and Edge will continue to work just as before, and we’ve taken the opportunity to fix some bugs and improve stability.</description></item><item><title>Selenium 3 is Coming</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-is-coming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/selenium-3-is-coming/</guid><description>Selenium 3 is coming! As I write this, we think that “beta 4” will be the last beta before the official 3.0 release. I’m here to tell you about what’s changed, and what impact this will have on your testing.
TL;DR: WebDriver users will just find bug fixes and a drop-in replacement for 2.x. Selenium Grid users will also find bug fixes and a simple update. The WebDriver APIs are now the only APIs actively supported by the Selenium project.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium 3.0-beta1</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/announcing-selenium-3-0-beta1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2016/announcing-selenium-3-0-beta1/</guid><description>At SeleniumConf in 2013, we announced that a new major version of Selenium would be released “by Christmas”. Fortunately, we never said which Christmas, as it has taken us a while to make all the changes we wanted to make! We’re excited to announce the release of the first beta — Selenium 3.0.0-beta1.
We’d love you to try it out on your projects, and provide us with feedback on where the rough edges are before we ship the 3.</description></item><item><title>IntelliJ</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/intellij/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2015/intellij/</guid><description>Every year, Jetbrains are kind enough to donate an OSS license for IntelliJ to the Selenium project. As part of that process, they’ve asked that we review the product and (kudos to them!) have been clear that they hope we’re open and honest. So, I’ll be open and honest.
When I tell people that I’m a professional Java developer, people in some circles make sympathetic noises and (sometimes) jokingly refer to how painful my coding life must be.</description></item><item><title>Android and iOS Support</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/android-and-ios-support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/android-and-ios-support/</guid><description>TL;DR: We’re retiring Selenium’s own AndroidDriver and iPhoneDriver in favour of any of Selendroid, iosdriver and Appium. If you’re using one of Selenium’s own mobile drivers, please evaluate one of these alternatives.
The longer version:
In 2007, Steve Jobs announced the iPhone and changed the mobile Web from a curiosity to something the mainstream wanted and used. Current trends suggest that mobile Web usage will surpass desktop usage in the not too distant future.</description></item><item><title>Mobile WebDriver</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/mobile-webdriver/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/mobile-webdriver/</guid><description>Although the WebDriver APIs started life as just a mechanism for automating web browsers, over the past few years it has been extended to also work on mobile devices. Projects such as Appium, iosdriver, and Selendroid have all shown that this approach works, and works well. On the Web, if you start using Selenium WebDriver with one browser (Firefox, for example), it’s easy to switch out the browser for another one (such as Internet Explorer or Chrome).</description></item><item><title>The Road to Selenium 3</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/the-road-to-selenium-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/the-road-to-selenium-3/</guid><description>Selenium 2 was released in July 2011. It’s now two years old, and what a couple of years it’s been! The WebDriver APIs, which were the major addition in Selenium 2, are now the basis for a W3C standard, and there are implementations written and supported by Google, Mozilla and Opera. There have been 34 releases, with official support for Java, C#, Python, Ruby and Javascript, and the community has stepped in to provide bindings for Perl, PHP and others.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #157</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-157/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-157/</guid><description>Trying to find every excuse not to cut the grass … including apparently closing some browser tabs.
Interoperability – Standardized Test Information Interchange has me so full of ‘meh’ as to be hilarious. Commercially driven standards rarely are and/or I am just too much of an open source person to accept this model for standards development Licensing in a Post Copyright World – important How to Make Async Requests in PHP is php specific in its solution, but has some interesting bits about socket establishment that applies to other ones as well Adding Comments to JSON feels like a hack.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #156</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-156/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-156/</guid><description>Brain fried from PyCon Canada 2013 and ‘some’ browser tab is misbehaving which means its time to start closing some of these.
Patchwork seems like an awesome idea, but at the same time, I’ve had to work in heavily monkey-patched RoR apps before… Evolving syntax is PHP specific in its examples, but the ideas transfer Roslyn + Selenium: Scripty C# Powering Browser Automation – some C# voodoo? It’s like 10000 knives when all you need is a Spoon – or specifically, this particular spoon which is yet-another-android-automation-tool.</description></item><item><title>The World’s Best Selenium Meetup</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/the-worlds-best-selenium-meetup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/the-worlds-best-selenium-meetup/</guid><description>Note from Adam: This is a guest post from Dave Haeffner who, along with David Burns hatched this idea at SeConf2013.
Selenium Meetups are great, but… Have you ever wanted to attend a Selenium Meetup but there’s not one near you? Or maybe there is but something’s come up and you can’t make it out that night? Or maybe the meetup near you struggles to get good speakers and have a consistent schedule?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #155</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-155/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-155/</guid><description>A ‘should be scripting, but brain stuck in neutral so closing some tabs’ edition of the Smattering.
The slippery slope isn’t automation related, but if your employer does these things I’d suggest logging a bug and then finding an ethical job Why Package Signing is not the Holy Grail – crypto / security is hard. Also, I have a signed package for you to install… PHP and Async requests with file based sessions could be a way to speed up a PHP site.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #154</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-154/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-154/</guid><description>Apparently today’s ‘wait for an email’ task is to whittle down the smattering queue some more.
I won’t even pretend that FOAAS has to do with automation, but makes me laugh. Also, depending on how crappy your place of work is, it might not be SFW PHP RFC: Importing namespaced functions is interesting if you are writing your scripts in a Functional manner. In PHP. In a future where it gets accepted and implemented.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #153</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-153/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-153/</guid><description>A Sunday Smattering? Sure!
Solution to the Selenium with Firefox 22 Issues and How to Report Issues – Open Source is hard. Supporting Open Source’s infrastructure is harder — by a large margin frequests – asyncronous HTTP Requests; not sure where I would use this, but… why I don’t touch crypo – again, don’t. touch. crypto Five reasons why you should quote attribute values in HTML5 – for the record, you should do this in HTML 4 as well.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #152</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-152/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-152/</guid><description>40-ish minutes until midnight eastern so that counts as two days in a row, right? Right?
Improving jenkins execution times by common sense — common sense. sadly lacking most days. How to make test automation more effective? is useful up until the pitch at the end. So read until you get to that. Data Structures for PHP Devs: Trees – non-trivial data structures are non-trivial Writing clean WebDriver test suites for “duplicate” functionality by parameterizing on page objects – I especially like the usage of ‘might’ at the top dalek-internal-webdriver – what’s a day without a JS webdriver implementation?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #151</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-151/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-151/</guid><description>Almost a month after the last one. Though it did nice to have it at 150 when people go to the blog … but a greater number is nicer.
So I was trying to find Requests for PHP whilst talking to the grumpy programmer and he pointed me out to Guzzle which looks equally cool Can you optimize list(genexp) is one of those geeky language internals things that could be handy to have in your back pocket Slightly Snarky GWT Debug ID FAQ – c’mon, when have you seen a more blatantly ‘put this in the smattering’ title than this?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #150</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-150/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-150/</guid><description>Yup, this smattering has very little to do with Selenium, but… 150!
Referencing DOM from JS: there must be a DRYer, safer way is a nice ‘here is where I started, and here is how I ended up where I am’ post which can be stolen into other languages / frameworks other than in Backbone Hash lookup in Ruby, why is it so fast? is not something I was wondering, but now I know why.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #149</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-149/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-149/</guid><description>Too. Many. Tabs.
Internationalization and Localization Testing — yup, I agree. 5 HTML5 Features you need to know – ‘download attribute’ and ‘datalist element’ might be a pain for us automators. Or at least cause a couple hours annoyance until we figure out the pattern. Death to sleeps! Raise of Conditions! – expected conditions is likely the next thing to get more marketing this year line_profiler and kernprof – profiling is black magic voodoo Naught – ‘Naught is a toolkit for building Null Objects in Ruby.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #148</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-148/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-148/</guid><description>Gotta start this up again…
The Evil Tester Guide To HTTP Proxies appears to be more for using proxies for manual testing, but you should be running your automation through one as well so it helps to understand the magic that takes place. New BrowserMob Proxy release. Bindings should all be updated for the newly exposed methods in a couple days. 5 Things You Should Stop Doing With jQuery – Not sure whats better, the content, or the Saved By The Bell theme testtools is the latest hotness in the world of Python runners?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #147</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-147/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-147/</guid><description>My. Get. Productive. I know! I’ll push out a smattering. Oh. …
Python for Ruby Programmers is a pretty good deck, with the requisite snark at the end that you can safely ignore. Me @ Selenium Camp 2013 is Ivan’s mini-experience-report from SeCamp and has his slides on GhostDriver Using pip in production? pip install : Lightspeed and Bulletproof is a useful trick which I know I’ve done variants of with java and ruby in the past SeConf speakers are up — and the list looks really good Interfaces or Abstract Classes?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #146</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-146/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-146/</guid><description>Happy ‘productivity destructive week’ — otherwise known as March break.
How to Accept Self-Signed SSL Certificates in Selenium 2 — or you could use ‘real’ certificates that are trusted by the browser by default. If you are using self-signed certificates to ‘save money’ and you spend 3 hours making it work, you are not saving money anymore JockeyJS seems like it could be useful Dear every-js-widget-library-author, You can’t create a button If you are using PHP, then The Grumpy Programmer’s PHPUnit Cookbook should be added to your reading pile.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #145</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-145/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-145/</guid><description>Alice Finch builds massive LEGO Hogwarts from 400,000 bricks starts out at awesome and goes somewhere further down the scale when you get to the photo that shows scale.
Models of Automation — really, who reading this hasn’t had the conversation described in there in one of its variants Stop Moving So I Can Click You Dammit! – illustrates the only acceptable place for Thread.sleep() Using Realistic Data in Unit Testing and AngelaSmith: Creating Test Data is a two-for for the C# crowd — though the ideas resonate with everyone else How to handle common components with Page Object Model?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #144</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-144/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-144/</guid><description>Real Canadians watch curling instead of hockey.
jsPerf is a performance oriented sandbox The Myth Of Convention Over Configuration – hint: its curation over configuration. And since this is how frameworks work… sublimetext_indentxml is a sublime text plugin to indent xml — yes, originality counts with plugin naming Introducing Boxen – Boxen feels a lot like Vagrant, but for Macs? Maybe? Checking for Technical Requirements in a Sign-up Process — woah, this would be a pain to automate office_docs looks like it might help parse and inspect ms office docs your app generates.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #143</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-143/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-143/</guid><description>If you had anything interesting last week I should have seen, you’ll have to resend it to me or @seleniumhq — things were a bit crashy.
So … Opera switching to WebKit. That doesn’t mean you can write off automation with Opera though. Tragedy of the WebKit Commons Introducing ChemistryKit — a Ruby version of Saunter is another self-serving link. Automated local accessibility testing using WAVE and WebDriver is a post I had been waiting awhile for How Did the Duck Hunt Gun Work?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #142</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-142/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-142/</guid><description>Its a Wiggle your brain kind of morning…
Automated Web Testing Is Hard is the launch announcement of ChemistryKit Watir-WebDriver with GhostDriver on OSX: headless browser testing — the WebDriver version of this would be very, very similar to this. jQuery 1.9.1 Released isn’t interesting from a new jQuery perspective, but the migrate plugin is. Likely old news, but was new to me… GRASP (object-oriented design) ‘is really a mental toolset’ How Not to Design Pairwise Software Tests is even more useful when paired (pun intended) with… Using Data Driving Wisely The Importance of the DOM has a lot of stuff that my not-in-gear brain is capable of processing, but… Postel’s Principle is a Bad Idea.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #141</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-141/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-141/</guid><description>Its -12 Celsius plus windchill out. Why the heck is the office air conditioning on. Feel like I need a Mr. Rogers cardigan or something.
Caret Navigation in Web Applications starts slow and then hurts your brain while reminding you that this automation thing isn’t easy. I don’t know NUnit or TeamCity so don’t know if Using TeamCity and NUnit to Start WebServer, Run Selenium Tests and Stop WebServer is useful or just a rehash of common knowledge.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #140</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-140/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-140/</guid><description>Buckets!
I suspect that scanner-backed-by-selenium belongs in the ‘with great power comes great responsibility’ bucket
ios-driver is in the ‘wouldn’t it be nice if Apple provided this’ bucket
Selenium WebDriver utility for determining when page has finished rendering is in the ‘ADF specific’ bucket’
I suspect JSErrorCollector is in the ‘already indirectly linked to’ bucket. If not then its in the ‘FF only’ bucket
Using a business readable language for browser automation is in the ‘bdd/atdd hype’ bucket.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #139</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-139/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-139/</guid><description>Posting from the past into the future. Or something… (its a scheduled post).
webdriverjs-with-jasmine appears appropriately named since it claims to be A standalone (includes standalone Selenium server (30Mo) + includes Jasmine) working example of a test with WebDriverJS and Jasmine. Similar to the above, but with Drupal and Behat – Classic How I[he] send notifications to the build breakers. using twillio On Code Review comes from the Food For Thought department Orc is a model driven orchestration tool for the deployment of application clusters.</description></item><item><title>A Plan to Drop Firefox 3.x Support</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-plan-to-drop-firefox-3-x-support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-plan-to-drop-firefox-3-x-support/</guid><description>The support policy of the selenium project for Firefox browsers is to support the current and previous stables releases, as well as the current and previous ESR releases. At the time of writing, that means the supported versions are &amp;#8220;10&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;17&amp;#8221; (ESR) and &amp;#8220;17&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;18&amp;#8221; (stable channel). In addition to this, we are currently supporting Firefox 3.x too. This is an official announcement that we are planning to end support for Firefox 3.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #138</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-138/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-138/</guid><description>&amp;lt;insert snark here&amp;gt;
Debugging For Testers — they don’t teach this in testing school. Actually, there is a testing school… A million times this!! That’s not BDD, that’s just Cucumber Faster Websites: Crash Course on Web Performance — all three hours of video Continuous Integration of iOS Projects using Jenkins, CocoaPods, and Kiwi Clearing IE’s Caches – Not as simple as it appears is another one of those things that gives Jim headaches.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #137</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-137/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-137/</guid><description>Whoops, missed a couple days… ah well.
MOAR ELEMENTS!!! the element Dependency injection != Inversion of Control is useful reading. And the Waffle example is pretty funny. Not sure yet how I feel about this feature in the page-object gem.
Waiting for an application to be fully loaded has some more examples of using a ‘proper’ [not implicit] waiting strategy. Most of us are not using Se for HVAT, but knowing the terminology, etc.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #136</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-136/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-136/</guid><description>Someone go back to my past self and punch him for thinking that starting to get in shape was a good idea. OMGCANTMOVE.
.NET Goes Immutable seems interesting. But I don’t really speak C# so it could very well be boring and uninteresting. Shadow DOM 101 is another part of HTML5 that makes me think this web automation stuff has a very limited life span. Between this and Canvas… ugh. Using WebDriver to automatically check for JavaScript errors on every page is something I have been considering adding to my frameworks… Have I mentioned how much Canvas worries me?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #135</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-135/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-135/</guid><description>Three in a row … of course, these are the easy three.
Build, test and deploy Firefox OS apps for $0 (or any other currency that I don’t know how to emit) Ruby on Rails … in Bash. Because they can. Bash on Balls All you need to know about CSS Transitions except how the hell we are going to synchronize on them. Well, kinda does, but this is going to hurt.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #134</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-134/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-134/</guid><description>Hrm. Office is closed until Monday, but everyone is in. Very confusing…
One reason I have heard people say they don’t use cloud instances is they are afraid they will just sit around idle when not needed. Behind the clouds: how RelEng do Firefox builds on AWS has some useful scripts to find and teardown machines. Page Weight Matters is a fun little insight into how/why YouTube shed some of its heft.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #133</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-133/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2013/a-smattering-of-selenium-133/</guid><description>Since today is the start of ‘find a new contract’ I guess I don’t have an excuse to miss these for the next week or so.
(Oh, and Happy New Year, etc.)
This is snark, but just makes me laugh given the hype machine around ATDD/BDD;
AS an angry userI WANT TO punch the developer in the faceSO THAT I CAN punch the developer in the face.
— Kristopher Johnson (@OldManKris) December 4, 2012</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #132</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-132/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-132/</guid><description>2.27.0 is now out which means you can close the browser tab that points to the old Firefox installers.
Not Providing an HTML Page? Think of the Kittens! is important to remember. We want to fix your bugs. Help us help you! The HTML5 download attribute is another bit I am not looking forward to have to automate Refactoring to Improve Testability – what can I say? I like experiential posts Oh how it pains me to suggest that SikuliWebDriver looks mighty cool Page Visibility API Support in Opera 12.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #131</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-131/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-131/</guid><description>Not sure how widely broadcast this has been (cus, you know, we’re good at communicating and stuff), but if you are using 2.26.0 and Firefox 17 you will get a nasty bug. 2.27.0 is in the works to address this (and a couple other things…) so if you need FF right now, keep your install at the latest 16 release.
This is pretty decent. Except the usual “Feh! We don’t need humans to test!</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #130</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-130/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-130/</guid><description>Can’t get enough Se bloggage? Have a look at Overview of Selenium Blogs — though I must say there has to be something wrong with the Alexa algorithm if I am that far down the list. And behind both David and Alister. 🙂
Must Have Git Aliases: Advanced Examples reminds me of someone I used to work with who likely couldn’t function on a clean unix system, but with all his aliases was mind blowing to watch Writing a Selenium Test Framework for a Django Site (Part 3) has the usual myths and FUD around XPath and embeds locators in the script method but is the first thing I’ve seen that uses the Color class in Python so I’ll overlook those things.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #129</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-129/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-129/</guid><description>A hardy welcome back to work to our American friends who spent Thursday being thankful for what they had, then getting into fist fights at stores for things they thought they didn’t need the next day.
You know what would be grand? If various widget makers would provide automation hooks for their stuff so we, as automators, don’t have to write them ourselves. Like for High Charts (in Java) Why you should never use a boolean field (use an Enum instead) is food for thought when designing your page objects Do you work for Google?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #128</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-128/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-128/</guid><description>…as I avoid writing code that deals with dynamically constructed tables. Without any sort of unique locator. Of course.
I would contend that the ‘right’ solution to this problem is to use a CI container and have it email you, but if you are using Java and not using CI, then Automatically Email the Reports After Selenium Test Execution could be valuable. I feel like I have already linked to Webdriver StaleElementReferenceException but the archive search is, erm, not great, so here it is again.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #127</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-127/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-127/</guid><description>Within an hour I had some more things to add to the last Smattering. Oh well, I’ll just save them up…
Har-assert looks like something useful to include in your project if you are using Java. And the browsermob-proxy (which of course, you all are) Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.0 seems like something more people should care about. Right. Here is another cool part of the nebulous, meaningless thing called HTML5.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #126</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-126/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-126/</guid><description>I’ve been threatening that I was going to do this for awhile…
What it feels like when you are running a long running batch of scripts…
Remember kids, your script cannot adapt to the unexpected…
But on occasion they can do something that…
Oh! Here’s a useful metric of productivity!
And just when you thought you were doing something without anyone paying attention…
Unfortunately what a lot of automation is like…</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #125</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-125/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-125/</guid><description>Right…
Scripting batch 1: waiting for an email Scripting batch 2: waiting for an email Scripting batch 3: waiting for an email Scripting batch 4: waiting for an email Perhaps I’ll do something else right now…
Alright kids, its not the Olympics, but Curvy would be a fun app for someone to automate. Wow that was fast. Øredev has started to publish the videos from this year’s conference. Lots of good things in there.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #124</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-124/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-124/</guid><description>Too. Many. Links. Not. Enough. Posts.
The important word is strive in 100% Automation Pass Rates. PHP Error could be interesting to turn on in your automation environment. Well, if it is a PHP app at any rate… Testing mobile? Tap Into Mobile Application Testing by Jonathan Kohl Behavioural testing in .Net with SpecFlow and Selenium – Part 1, Part 2 cocoa-rest-client could be a useful tool for the toolbox if you are on mac and are testing rest apps.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #123</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-123/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-123/</guid><description>If you are not using something like Chef or Puppet to keep your grid nodes behaving then you are absolutely doing it wrong. Here are all the PuppetConf 2012 Videos to help you get started. See also this Apple’s Lightning port dynamically assigns pins to allow for reversible use is just too geeky not to include. Hurray for hardware lock-in? Websockets 101 — again, if your app uses a technology, you better be damned clueful about it if you are going to automate it Child Elements seems to address the ‘is my element where I expect it’ problem though I’m still not convinced that is a problem that needed solving HTML for Icon Font Usage could be interesting.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #122</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-122/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-122/</guid><description>Let’s try the ‘all video’ edition this time.
Solving Common Problems with Web UI Automation Hrm. That didn’t work … let’s add some slide decks.
Mobile Test Automation at eBay from Dominik Dary PHPUnit Best Practices A Whirlwind Tour of Test::Class from Curtis Poe Simple Log Analysis and Trending from Mike Brittain</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #121</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-121/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-121/</guid><description>Its the ‘all github’ edition today!
Dave goes a little strange on us with his diy_framework as an emoting robot. Here is the deck that went along with it. Can’t get enough of the food-based frameworks from the kids at Sauce. If you are using the PHPUnit included WebDriver bindings [and Sauce OnDemand] then Sausage could be of interest. Of course, if you are just using PHPUnit, then paraunit could of interest.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #120</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-120/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-120/</guid><description>Here we grow again. Telerik acquires Fiddler. What’s next?. So. When can we look for nice Se integration with Fiddler then? Third-Party Issues and the Performance Ripple Effect is interesting, and something I’ve harped on consistently. Automated Web Testing with Selenium is 3.5 hours of videos on Se. That has my usual complaints; shouldn’t have Se-IDE, there is no such thing as ‘basic’ and ‘advanced’, etc. But its there. The Oracle Problem and the Teaching of Software Testing is long, but important to understand when doing automation.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #119</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-119/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-119/</guid><description>Its that time again, 4th Annual Automation Honors Voting is now open. Vanity contests FTW!
Introducing the Sauce Plugin for Selenium Grid from a product perspective is huge. And in a roundabout way proves I am not completely crazy…
Benchmark of Python WSGI Servers has lots of numbers, and graphs and charts.
Seleno makes some bold marketing statements (‘the RIGHT way!’). Looks like a framework in C# that forces people to use Page Objects</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #118</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-118/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-118/</guid><description>&amp;lt;Insert witty/snarky commentary on something here&amp;gt;
Apparently the TestWatchman thing I linked to is deprecated now in favour of TestWatcher (shows how much I pay attention to JUnit stuff…). Here is an example of TestWatchers and RuleChains. No, I don’t know what the blurb at the top says. Sure, we’ve all see lorum ipsum text, but do you know what it (ish) says? now you do From the ‘MEASURE ALL THINGS!</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #117</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-117/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-117/</guid><description>Evolutionary Project Structure talks about a particular project structure, but this is one of those fun developer opinionated things to geek out on Testers Caught Sleeping on the Job is not browser-based, but you cannot bash sleeps enough. Also has a pretty amusing photo with it PHP: The Right Way is of course one person’s understanding of the ‘right way’ but still not bad. Automation is Code. But are your code conventions hurting you?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #116</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-116/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-116/</guid><description>So do people celebrate the day after Labor day as the beginning of summer?
Web Performance Power Tool: HTTP Archive (HAR) is worrisome that HARs are being billed as a power tool, but full of good stuff How do you pick responsive images breakpoints? is another one of those problems I think we’re going to have to worry about TestWatchman seems like an interesting bit of JUnit4. (At what point do we have to stop saying 3 or 4 when referring to JUnit?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #115</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-115/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-115/</guid><description>The big news in the twitter-verse yesterday was the announcement of Apple Sauce and Android Sauce from Sauce Labs. I of course jumped all over that bandwagon with Apple Sauce and Android Sauce .. Yummy! (And Fully Supported) * Accessing priviledged Javascript APIs from your web page in Firefox with Selenium lets to pull even more strings of the browser than you were supposed to be able to. Something I suspect Marionette will make redundant, but until then…</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #114</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-114/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-114/</guid><description>Hurray for having fillings done on both sides of my face. Don’t expect me to speak without drolling for rest of the day.
I’ll admit to not knowing what the difference is/was between FluentWait and WebDriverWait, but FluentWait with WebElement explains it well. With sample code!
PHPUnit + Selenium + php-webdriver = hours of entertainment (Part 1) shows a nice extension to PHPUnit_Framework_TestCase. Now if only he was using my active fork of the php-webdriver bindings rather than the original project Facebook seems to have abandoned.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #113</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-113/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-113/</guid><description>/me is not looking forward to when the jet lag whallops him
Thorough look at PHP’s pcntl_fork() is how we have to do parallel tests with phpunit until it grows it proper Catch Javascript Errors on the Page with Watir or Selenium – This! Categorising WebDriver–Navigation, Interrogation, Manipulation walks through the WebDriver API bit by bit. Of course, now the trick is to keep it up to date. 🙂 Screening uses Se deep in its guts to script up Montage apps Millions of web pages use the -moz-opacity:0.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #112</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-112/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-112/</guid><description>Eyes are gross.
Thucydides has a spiffy new website How Eventbrite uses Jenkins and Selenium which I think I’ve linked to before, but can’t seem to find reference to. What’s my UDID? is now the new bar for online tutorials Creating Maintainable Automated Acceptance Tests from Jez Humble Selenium Users Anonymous from Dave Haeffner Capture/Playback: The Vampire that Will Not Die has perhaps the most unfriendly url in the history of the internets, but is a nice little rant anyways.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #111</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-111/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-111/</guid><description>When this gets published, I’ll be sitting around the Barcelona airport waiting for my connection home. Unless I screwed up the time math. 🙂
The dangers of uniformity pours cold water on something that I know I used to preach for automation environments. How to crawl a quarter billion webpages in 40 hours doesn’t have code listed (he explains why) but it explains how you could write it yourself if you wanted.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #110</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-110/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-110/</guid><description>Dear body; what time zone are you in?
Ah well, until that battle resolves itself, here are some links.
Firefox the Clear Winner for Automated Testing has a wonderfully SEO friendly title, but really is just some cool usage graphs for their system. Extrapolate beyond that at your own risk. Task Automation FTW! — make your application installable! I did something like this a decade ago (also using python) but finding something in my own blog seems a harder challenge than it should be.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #109</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-109/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-109/</guid><description>Going to be on an airplane for the better part of the next day, so will likely miss some links … unless I am tagged on twitter with it.
Introducing The Driver Binary Downloader Maven Plugin For Selenium solves a problem that has been solved a couple times but this seems the slickest. Normally I would suggest just using Chef/Puppet for this but it makes sense in the Maven context. I think.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #108</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-108/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-108/</guid><description>Apparently the links are slowing down for the summer?
Ralph Bodenner talks about New Relic’s experiences at the SF Continuous Delivery meetup Xelenium: Security Testing with Selenium! is kinda an interesting use case Introducing mobile browser automation from/with Opera A minimal WebDriver based DSL is a bit of an experiment Testing Chef Cookbooks is something you didn’t think you needed to think about NASA’s github is not Se focused, but could help you build your own Mars rover WordPress Performance is a nice deck with lots of graphs and pictures Principles of Agile Test Automation outlines 4 principles and how they can often compete with each other Cucumber.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #107</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-107/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-107/</guid><description>Back on the train again. Wow, the highway is screwed today.
The Automation Litmus Test is one that most companies face, but now it has a name
Okay, who has more info on the bots mentioned in Meet the ‘bots’ that edit Wikipedia? Highly doubt that they are Se powered, but it is a fun mental image
Custom PHPUnit Annotations is useful magic if you are building out a framework</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #106</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-106/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-106/</guid><description>In case you are curious, the train just went past my old neighbourhood.
Marionette – The Future of FirefoxDriver in Selenium is a project that has been hinted at here before I think, but this is its coming out party. Oh. And its the future of the Firefox driver. Now, what I need is an A-Team t-shirt… FlynnID 0.2 changes its config format. I don’t play around with Grid much (at all) but I’ve been told that you need this if you are going to have Android devicii attached to the grid.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #105</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-105/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-105/</guid><description>This was supposed to go out Friday, but the flu bug I picked up decided to move the schedule about somewhat.
As Se marches towards being a W3C standard, the sort of thing in OAuth and API Providers: Come on guys. scares me more and more. Why WP_Error Sucks. Intelligent error handling is hard. Especially when you have a legacy install base to deal with. A nice little rant. Normally you see lists from people about books individuals want to see written, but Heroku has gone one step further and has released Contribute a Dev Center Article of articles they want to see written about how to use their stuff.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #104</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-104/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-104/</guid><description>I think everyone is on holidays right now…
Firefox 15 plugs the add-on leaks — Hey look! Openness from Mozilla! I’m not kidding when I say I want to see more of these; from all browser vendors. JUnit Oath — when geeks collide! Integration Tests With Cucumber-Jvm, Selenium and Maven is nice in that is shows the use of profiles (which is pretty much maven’s killer feature) but it uses Se-RC.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #103</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-103/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-103/</guid><description>Seems I had this all ready to go yesterday… oh, and Happy Birthday Jim Evans — maintainer of IE and C# driver. If also a day late.
Migrating Unit Tests from Selenium to Watir Webdriver is less about migrating rather than a quick overview of Watir HttpWatch 8.4: Supports Firefox 14 and Selenium appears to be http traffic monitor — minus a proxy sms is a quick script which will send an sms from the commandline — using Se as the means of doing it Buster.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #102</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-102/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-102/</guid><description>Apparently my body isn’t quite on left coast time…
Butter Performance is a nice experience report on making a [big] html table behave. All sorts of headaches this would cause for automation. I’m now starting to think more about caching since some of that information is included in HAR files. So if you are automating against a Rails site, Advanced Caching in Rails: Revised could be of values Scaling lessons learned at Dropbox, part 1 is another fun experience report including a bit of hints at Dropbox’s own version of Netflix’s Chaos Monkey Finding the broken links in a webpage using Selenium is Se-RC, but the idea is sound.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #101</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-101/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-101/</guid><description>Really? A drought for most of the week and now I’ve got a queue again in the span of 3 hours?
Developing RESTful Web APIs with Python, Flask and MongoDB is toolchain dependent, but likely enough cross-tool-ism to be worth a quick click through The cool part of Jasmine Testing With Sauce Labs isn’t necessarily the Jasmine part, but the Sauce Connect Puppet part. Though Jasmine is high on my cool list.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #100</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-100/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-100/</guid><description>Century!
Event 1028 – Automatic Download Blocking looks like something that could be useful to have tucked away in your head somewhere I think I said I wasn’t going to link to headless gem posts, but I don’t think I’ve linked to one about Cucumber. Cucumber running headless Selenium with Jenkins (the easy way); fixed Errorception, and things like it, are the next wave of infrastructure to come I think now that things like BrowserMob Proxy are becoming mainstream-ish-er I’m not really sure of the difference between NPageObject.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #99</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-99/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-99/</guid><description>With the queue flushed we’ll go back to our regular random posting schedule
Etsy Code as Craft: The Other Part of Software Architecture with Coda Hale – Code as Craft talks are generally good All the Atlassian Summit 2012 talks. I love this trend. Perception Of Performance discusses the whole ‘OMG CHOME IS HELLA FAST ON IOS!!!!!!’ madness. As the last line of the article says, I present to you, the power of marketing!</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #98</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-98/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-98/</guid><description>Happy day off Canuckistan! I’ll be in California in two weeks; here is my schedule — come by and chat
Selenium Rc to Webdriver Migration – Part2 is included mainly for the IE bit. Busted SSL certificate? Don’t work around the problem — fix it! Can’t find an element? Synchronize properly — don’t just bap it in the face with the magic implicit wait wand… Google I/O 2012 Videos won’t give you the loot attendees got, just the content.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #97</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-97/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-97/</guid><description>Yes. I know. I missed a day. But 13 in a row was a good run!
Free Automated Cross-Browser JavaScript Testing is a pretty standard ‘here is how you do it’ article — until you get to the IE section. It has a trick I don’t think I’ve seen yet. If you don’t want to use a Proxy to generate HAR files, you can use NetExport in your Firefox profile to save things locally, or sent them to a remote server as explained in Automate Page Load Performance Testing with Firebug and Selenium.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #96</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-96/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-96/</guid><description>Blech. Supposed to go car shopping today. Any car brands want to sponsor my wife with a car so I can do something productive? Worth a shot…
jbehave-selenium is a sample project that uses, unsurprisingly, jbehave and selenium. Sample projects are outstanding. Just as samples are good, so are playgrounds. It’s playtime – Light Table Playground released And try jasmine! Announcing Joyride is another ‘browser automation without programming as a service’ site Announcing pytest-mozwebqa 1.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #95</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-95/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-95/</guid><description>Ok twitterverse. After 2 weeks of very few links a day you explode.
Testing JSF with Arquillian and Selenium apparently will save the world. GhostDriver: almost 50% is an update on something that got a bit of momentum at SeConf2012 Building and profiling high performance systems with Iago is getting a bump by being released at/during Velocity. Not browser based, but what its being used for doesn’t need browsers. Testing geolocation with capybara + selenium + firefox is an interesting trick to address something I haven’t thought of needing yet.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #94</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-94/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-94/</guid><description># sudo wget coffee &amp;gt; adam
Selenium-RC Commands is a mindmap of all the commands in Se-RC. (Unsurprising really.) I keep meaning to do this for WebDriver.
quacken is a script for grabbing OFX files from Quicken it seems
What’s that? You weren’t happy with one of the six PHP WebDriver clients that were out there already? Have another one — Nearsoft/PHP-SeleniumClient. It’d be spooky what would happen if we all got together on this.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #93</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-93/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-93/</guid><description>Did I say 8 days in a row yesterday? I meant 9. Good thing programming doesn’t require counting…
Passing ruby instance variables from Rspec to mix ins is the sort of nonsense you need to do when framework writing. Scared yet? (But it is fun…) Rspec, page objects and user flows is the experiment that likely led to the link above puppet-sauceconnect is a puppet module for moving Sauce’s Sauce Connect daemon onto remote nodes.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #92</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-92/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-92/</guid><description>What’s that? Eight days in a row? That’s right…
lolcommits seems almost funny enough to be a good idea A vision for Cucumber 2.0 is rather interesting Install Firefox on Amazon Linux X86_64 Compiling GTK+ is not something I have had to do. But then again, I haven’t tried. Nerrvana is yet another Selenium-As-A-Service provider. Looks like they are taking the ‘upload to our servers and run as a scheduled job’ approach rather than real-time.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #91</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-91/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-91/</guid><description>As you’ll start to see by the timestamps of things towards the end, I’m running out of ‘new’ stuff and am pulling from the queue now.
Fairly certain I’ve linked to this before, but seleniumwrapper adds some syntacitcal sugar around the Python bindings. Though not sure that it makes it clearer to me. What the heck is an xrange? is today’s Python internal geekiness post Functional Automated Testing Best Practices with Selenium WebDriver is the video version of these slides (wow I dislike this html slide deck trend…) All the WWDC 2012 Session Videos are now up.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #90</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-90/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-90/</guid><description>Eventually I’ll get back on the once-a-week schedule. But not today!
Falsehoods Programmers believe about Time. Time is hard; let’s go shopping! Speaking of hard. Concurrency is not Parallelism (it’s better) (http://concur.rspace.googlecode.com/hg/talk/concur.html) — also has gophers Did Netflix actually Open Source Army of Cloud Monkeys? I don’t see anything on their github account (and that is the trendy place to release stuff these days) Need I say more? I’ve used this trick a couple times Python introspection – how to check current module / line of call from within function Ah-ha!</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #89</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-89/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-89/</guid><description>Figured I would get this out before the computer goes in for surgery.
Automate Page Load Performance Testing with Firebug and Selenium is not a new topic, but a timely one for me Speed up your features with a backdoor login route is not a recent post, but something I’ve had to explain to people at least once a week for the past month, so… RSpec’s New Expectation Syntax explains not only the ‘what’ of the new syntax but the ‘why’ Slides &amp;amp; Videos from LDNSE #6 does not falsely advertise itself Python Timer Class – Context Manager for Timing Code Blocks reminds me that I need to use Context Managers more often Overloading Python list comprehension is an interesting little experiment.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #88</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-88/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-88/</guid><description>Five days and fifty links later…
I’m working on a larger-ish rant on headless browsers, but until then there is Jasmine Headless WebKit Not 2. Not 4. But Three ways to generate test data for your ruby automated tests Downloading things is a pain, but Waiting for watir-webdriver downloads (and determining the file name) has a solution Use classes in Python? Of course you do! Under the hood of Python class definitions — but as the warning states, If the prospect of pondering the metaclass of the metaclass of your class makes you feel nauseated, you better stop now.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #87</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-87/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-87/</guid><description>Avoiding punching things about software packaging by doing the 4th!!!! smattering in row.
Python Decorators is an attempt at picking up a stick the right way A lawnchair is sorta like a couch except smaller and outside. And a persistence solution for HTML5 apps. If your apps persist data, checking them in the browser is. Not. Enough. Atlassian is building a performance tool off of WebDriver including Page Objects called soke I wonder if we should fail scripts that use vendor prefixes…How to Unprefix -Webkit-Device-Pixel-Ratio The last paragraph in Android unittests now have LOLcat is the sort of thing that more projects should do tl;dw: Speedily practical large-scale tests — of course, browsers are going to slow things in any event, but things to think about… Continuous Deployment as a Remedy for Burnout — hadn’t thought about it this way, but yup.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #86</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-86/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-86/</guid><description>Look at that! 3 days in a row, and the boy isn’t even gone to school yet and I’ve hit ‘publish’
Most people know about this already, but SeleniumConf has its own YouTube channel — which has all of the 2012 videos on it now. How to Dynamically Add Android Support to Selenium Server at Runtime Python Iteration is a beginner talk about, well, iterating in Python. In ways that you would expect (for) and ways that you wouldn’t (generators) Sleepy Automated Tests talks about polling loops.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #85</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-85/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-85/</guid><description>Two days in a row! Take that doubters!
Automated Software Testing: An Example of a Working Solution is an interesting take on designing an automation system for the US DoD. It sure as heck isn’t how I would do it, but I can understand how this context might lead to this solution. And it seems like it is Eclipse based which is even worse a decision. 🙂 5 Tips on Finding a Mobile Job in Toronto is pretty focused, but also applies to non-mobile jobs outside of Toronto.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #84</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-84/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-84/</guid><description>What? Its only been 3 months since the last one. Sheesh.
Sorry about being a G+ article, but DOM Ready discusses briefly about how to build your page in terms of order of events. Of course, if you read the comments it is very much buyer beware, but…
I’ve been fixating a bit on operational dashboards the last little while and Enterprise Operational Intelligence has a couple good ones
Looking to use BrowserID?</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf: Community</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-community/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-community/</guid><description>In this series of blog posts we’ve introduced one of the keynotes and talked about some of the great presentations you’ll see at Selenium Conf ’12, but so far we’ve missed the most important aspect of the entire event: you.
For me, one of the highlights of any conference is the chance to meet other members of the community, make new friends and talk about all things interesting (and perhaps even tangentially related to the conference!</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf: Speakers</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-speakers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-speakers/</guid><description>I may be biased, but I think Selenium Conf ’12 is going to be great. There are talks aimed at every level of Selenium user. We’ve got experience reports, so you can learn from the trials and tribulations of others. There are talks about using Selenium in unusual ways, such as performance testing, or automated security testing, so you can see new ideas and approaches.
There are technical talks, such as the one Jim Evans is giving on lessons learned from developing the IE driver, so you can learn a little bit more about how Selenium works and Luke Daley’s talk about Geb is bound to be fun.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conf Keynotes: Liz Keogh</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-keynotes-liz-keogh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conf-keynotes-liz-keogh/</guid><description>The tickets for Selenium Conf ’12 are still on sale for about another week, so there’s still time for you to buy your tickets. In case you’ve not already gone to the conference site to see the great line up, this week we’ll be letting you know what to expect!
I’m really pleased to announce that Liz Keogh, who is a core member of the Behaviour Driven Development (BDD) community and is one of the stalwarts of the London Agile community, as well as a haiku poet, is going to be one of our keynotes!</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #83</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-83/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-83/</guid><description>Well, might not be in Florida, but how about them juggernaut Blue Jays?
WebDriver: capture JS errors while running tests is a JS way of capturing JS errors on a page Selenium reports – our take is a pretty detailed report on one company’s drive for prettier report output Hmmm. How do we get a Selenium coderwall achievement? page-objects is A basic framework for running automated tests using WebDriver, TestNG &amp;amp; Gradle selenese-runner is a js runner of Selenese scripts including a JUnit style reporter.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #82</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-82/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-82/</guid><description>Someone explain to me why I’m in Toronto and not Florida?
Couldn’t make it to Pycon last week? There are videos of the session! Release Histories for all Major Browsers is just interesting from a historical perspective Interacting with web pages using Selenium WebDriver for C# is pretty basic but does include the all-important security settings to make IE behave-ish page-object 0.6.2 released is not just a release announcement but has some nice examples of page objects in ruby autoenv is a magic hack for having auto-firing scripts at a directory level.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #81</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-81/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-81/</guid><description>Its March Break (at least here) which means its also Catch Up Week. An extra long Smattering every day!
Generally I reccomend to people not to automate file uploads, but sometimes they are unavoidable. Selenium Tips: Uploading Files in Remote WebDriver explains how one might go about things in WebDriver HTTP Status Cats isn’t new, but is still funny. httpstatus.es has the same information, but organized slightly differently. Now for someone to make a mashup of the two Coypu appears to be a .</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conference 2012</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conference-2012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/selenium-conference-2012/</guid><description>Good news, everybody! Selenium Conf ’12 is getting closer! We recently selected the speakers for the conference, and it’s going to be a great mix of talks, spanning the full range of subjects from the very practical to the deeply technical. I’m promised that there will be robots.
Selenium Conf isn’t just about the planned talks, it’s also about the community. On the final day, there will be an unconference, so if there’s something you feel passionately about and feel the world should know, now’s your chance.</description></item><item><title>Support for Ancient Browsers</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/support-for-ancient-browsers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/support-for-ancient-browsers/</guid><description>The first code checked into the Selenium project’s public repository was in November, 2004. We’re now in 2012. In the intervening years there have been many browsers released. The last browser we officially stopped supporting was Firefox 2.0, and it’s time to review the list of browsers again.
We periodically review the list of supported browsers as the more changes there are between the oldest version of a browser that we support and the most recent, the harder it is for us to add new features and maintain those that already exist.</description></item><item><title>A Note About the Cybervillains SSL Certificate</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-note-about-the-cybervillains-ssl-certificate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-note-about-the-cybervillains-ssl-certificate/</guid><description>If you&amp;#8217;re using Selenium RC to test websites hosted on a secure site (accessed using a URL starting with HTTPS), we strongly recommend that you upgrade to Selenium 2.19. This is because the Cybervillains certificate in previous versions will expire soon, and has been replaced in 2.19 with an updated one.
Our thanks to Patrick Lightbody, Ivan De Marino and Mark Watson and Neustar for taking providing the new certificate and the patch!</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #80</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-80/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-80/</guid><description>I should have learned not to boast about getting caught up with links.
Automating BrowserID with Selenium is pretty awesome. (As is BrowserID.) Now if this was only installable via pip or easy_install… Ruby Trick Shots – heed the disclaimer; not an exercise in Ruby best practices Keep It Functional – iPhone Test Automation talks about another automation framework for mobile. At some point Selenium is going to grow Objective-C bindings I fear.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #79</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-79/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-79/</guid><description>The only links left now are ones currently open in tabs right now. Hurray!
November’s SFSE was Continuous Deployment At Mozilla: slides, video Practical Web Test Automation is a book available in both a free and paid editions. I haven’t looked at it so can’t comment how good or bad it is. The Why, What and How of Software Test Automation isn’t too horrible, though I don’t like the word ‘guideline’ and of course the measurement section at the bottom is complete hokum.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #78</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-78/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-78/</guid><description>Look! A light at the end of the tunnel!
ASP.NET MVC + Selenium + IISExpress – You don’t see too many Windows how-to’s. Not sure if they just don’t get tweeted about or is more a sign of that community. Write Logs for Machines, use JSON is a nice idea. I wonder if (when) the major CI containers will land on a pseudo-standard for consuming JSON Remote File Upload using Selenium 2’s FileDetectors shows yet another area I need to figure out in WebDriver (not Selenium 2 as Santi so stubbornly referred to it as 🙂 Janky is GitHub’s CI server.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #77</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-77/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-77/</guid><description>No. Really. A Smattering every day this week and I’ll have the link queue cleared.
Go!
Mentioned in #74, Automating Web Performance data collection with BrowserMob Proxy and Selenium is more than just a link to GitHub Of course you are using the excellent Requests module rather than urllib2 which ships with Python; but are you using envoy instead of subprocess? Grabbing Screenshots of Failed Selenium Tests uses some JUnit magic.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #76</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-76/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-76/</guid><description>Post ten links, find seven more to add to the queue.
Selenium Page Objects and Abstraction is one person’s attempt at writing down how they describe POs Running Geb specs using a separate driver profile to test mobile views in Grails shows how to create a custom Firefox profile in WebDriver Django and Selenium on Jenkins/Hudson (Headless) is yet another tutorial around xvfb but has a trick at the end I don’t think I’ve seen Python’s concurrent.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #75</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-75/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-75/</guid><description>And home. Which mean 100% more internets! Or at least 98% more.
As things like native-driver become more prevalent, knowing how to do Continuous Integration for iOS projects with Jenkins CI will become more important Chocolatey seems like a nice and big step towards managing Windows build slaves SST (Selenium Simple Test) comes out of Ubuntu and has a quick introductory screencast.
Automate Salesforce Config Changes with Selenium is a contest.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #74</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-74/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-74/</guid><description>It is kinda hard to do these without reliable internet… dear hotels, fix. your. internet.
Testing Facebook Login with Selenium has some nice Python helpers to dealing with Facebook auth VBS WebDriver – ummm, wtf?! Python Browsermob Proxy Library – the best code is code you don’t have to write yourself. (Thanks David!) I saw A Few of My Favorite (Python) Things at CodeMash last week and learned a few things def test = new BDDMadeEasy(Selenium,EasyB,Groovy) is a writeup from a recent presenter at the Greater Boston Selenium User Group Receive SMS alerts when a Selenium test fails seems like both a good idea and a bad one at the same time Have you always wanted to automate minesweeper?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #73</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-73/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-73/</guid><description>Two Ruby gems
rwebspec-webdriver – Executable functional specification for web applications in RSpec syntax and Selenium-WebDriver loadable_component – Ruby implementation of LoadableComponent A three-parter on building a framework showing there is more than one way to skin the framework cat.
Testing Concepts Base Classes Putting it all together Another three-parter on Is the Cost of Continuous Integration Worth the Value on Your Program? – part 1, part 2, part 3</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #72</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-72/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2012/a-smattering-of-selenium-72/</guid><description>January means its time to escape from under the deadlines I found myself under during December so some of this stuff is a month old (or older!). Hopefully it is still interesting though.
Localizing automation well is something I’ve seen people struggle with. Creating Multi-Language Web Applications with Zend_Translate is a possible solution for PHP folks. Using Spinach with Selenium and of course Spinach seems to be a different implementation of Cucumber.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Selenium Conf ’12</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/announcing-selenium-conf-12/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/announcing-selenium-conf-12/</guid><description>The community around Selenium is the thing that really makes the Selenium project special. Last year, we held the first official Selenium Conference in San Francisco, and it was both great fun and a huge success. It is therefore with great pleasure that we are announcing Selenium Conf ’12! It’ll be taking place in London from the 16th to the 18th April, and we’re really looking forward to seeing you all there!</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #71</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-71/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-71/</guid><description>Looking like there might also be one later in the week too…
As we start to transistion the web over the HTML5, I keep thinking about incorporating some ‘static’ checks into Se scripts. HTML5 Accessibility Chops: using nested figure elements explains some good (and bad) ways to use Jim took my nudging the organizing tests post I linked to last time and expanded on Organize Your Tests, Part II: Use Metadata!</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #70</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-70/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-70/</guid><description>That’s it for this week. 🙂
For TestMate / Java folks, TextMate-Bundle-Selenium-Java could be interesting. We’ve all made Oopses when writing / interpreting Se scripts, so it is important to remember that Mistakes: Transparency is Best Organizing scripts is one of those topics that gets both too much and not enough attention. Organizing Your Tests adds to the discussion — though completely omits using ‘tags’ (which his product supports…) Not sure how this will affect automation of Android or not, but still pretty cool.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #69</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-69/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-69/</guid><description>In honor of this edition I provide…
…in which I also date myself.
CITCon is another one of those conferences I should go to but haven’t. Yet! 7 continuous integration ideas from CITCon is a quick list from the most recent iteration. Testing Facebook authentication with Rails 3 Cucumber, Capybara, Selenium has a nice little trick to get Facebook to authenticate back to your Rails stack. pennyworth is a ‘continuous packaging system’ which seems like an interesting description.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #68</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-68/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-68/</guid><description>Its been almost a month, so time for a flurry of Smatterings.
Maven has a bad reputation in some circles (ignoring for a second that you are using Java…), but should you be using it the QuickStart Archetype looks interesting. Why Your Monitoring Is Lying To You talks about types of logging which are valuable both from a Continuous Delivery perspective and for checking the health of your application during long script runs.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #67</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-67/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-67/</guid><description>Spinach is a Cucumber-esque BDD framework that was advertised on twitter as having ‘less regex magic’. Not sure if it has grown Se support yet, but I have no doubt that it will soon. Coping With Big C.I. is full of stuff that is useful for even Small C.I. Sane AJAX Testing in Selenium uses ‘reintroduced page loading’ for what I would call a ‘latch’ but describes it better I think.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #66</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-66/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-66/</guid><description>Aside from one of the dog’s tummy making noises that imply a big mess to clean up later, this scheduling thing seems to be working out.
Heard someone talk about doing bitmap comparisons last week somewhere. Adaptive Images tricks I suspect are going to become more commonplace. Good luck with that. Se is best at interaction, structure and content checks; not does-it-look-the-way-some-human-intended. Robots where robots should be used. Humans where humans should be used.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #65</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-65/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-65/</guid><description>Trying something new; queuing up the catch-up post while I have time to catch-up.
I’ve been lead to believe that Functional Testing with Arquillian is a Big Deal&amp;amp;tm;. Of course, I just see a lot of Java… If one thread raises an exception, why aren’t other threads’ finally blocks called? is an interesting question with a nice answer. If you start running scripts in parallel, this, and the GIL is something to keep in mind.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #64</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-64/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-64/</guid><description>How did I fall behind again already?!?!
This is a pretty good deck. Automation Isn’t All Shiny Toys If your work is divided in time-based goals then providing videos of the end result is a fantastic idea. See Dave’s Q3/2011 in review. The last two screencasts directly relate to Se The training wheels came off is outstanding! I’ve been saying this around Se-IDE for years. If you have tried automation-in-anger with Python, then you have likely spent some time swearing at the GIL.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #63</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-63/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-63/</guid><description>Watir to WebDriver: Unit Test Frameworks – Well, its ‘big’ news. Of course, Watir can use WebDriver so they didn’t have to port their scripts to a different API (I sure hope they have the API well abstracted away from their scripts). And of course the title of the post implies that Facebook thinks that Watir/Selenium scripts are ‘Unit’ tests which is suspect at best… Selenium tests for Jenkins — Yup; Jenkins now has a set of Se scripts for it.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #62</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-62/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-62/</guid><description>All opinions, all the time…
It all began with Test Design for Automation which lead to Automated Test Design (riffing/ripping off Alan Page) And then through some weird Jedi mind control there was Design for *GUI* Automation which in turn led to more UI test design (once more from Alan Page) And heck, why have two articles from the same author when you can have three?! It’s (probably) a Design Problem — though I don’t think Chris has riffed off this one yet… Remember, Not Every Test Should be Automated!</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #61</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-61/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-61/</guid><description>‘These are the people in your neighbourhood…’
Like the power of WebDriver, but not the API? Watir WebDriver will get you going with the Watir API. Lots of useful stuff there. So does Alister Scott’s WatirMelon blog Sikuli Plays Angry Birds on Google Games — just because scripts that play games are fun. cukeforker is for ‘Forking cukes and VNC displays.’ First time I’ve seen a group of machines referred to as a ‘fleet’, but its appropriate.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #60</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-60/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-60/</guid><description>This instalment of catch-up week is brought to you by the letters C and I.
The pre-scm-buildstep plugin for jenkins adds a useful step into the job workflow. Understanding your tools is important. Here is an explanation of Jenkings Action and its subtypes You think your CI setup is impressive? Check out the Apache Foundation’s Jenkins server The easiest way to get CI going is with the ubiquitious but completely unoffically Ant JUnit XML format.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #59</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-59/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-59/</guid><description>Its been a month and a half since the last one of these, and the volume of links I have collected illustrates that. So this week is now a cleanup week.
How Browsers Work: Behind the Scenes of Modern Web Browsers seems to be one of those articles that people who automate browsers for a living should be familiar with.
100% Test Coverage is always the goal.
Continuous Deployment and Data Visualization reminds us that if some data is good, more is often better.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #58</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-58/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-58/</guid><description>And here we go again with more links than I thought I had collected…
There are a metric tonne of site on the internets which are on how to scam your way through a Se interview. Hiring Selenium QA people provides some fodder on how one could look for and hire Se folk.
Why I don’t use spork reminds us that pain is [sometimes] a good thing.
The Jenkins project is having a conference on October 2 in the same hotel that SeConf was held.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #57</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-57/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-57/</guid><description>Phew. The links made it through the Lion installation.
Distributing the Same Test to Multiple Processes shows a technique for debugging flaky scripts Repeat after me: I will not automate GMail unless I am Google. Or if you will, you will do something like what is described in Verify email confirmation using Selenium. Notice that they are not using Se for it. Selenium and Nagios is something more teams should do I think.</description></item><item><title>A Quick Survey on Features</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-quick-survey-on-features/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-quick-survey-on-features/</guid><description>Rather than surprising the general community in ways that we have become somewhat known for, I figured I would try something new. Actually asking about usage of things before changing them in fundamental ways.
To this end, I have created a quick(!) survey about changes that are under consideration regarding UI-Maps and how Se-IDE is opened.
The survey is only two questions, so I’m hoping for a large response. I’ll post the results next Monday (August 8, 2011).</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #56</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-56/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-56/</guid><description>Safari is starting to whinge about how many tabs I have open which means it is time for another post.
Ripple-UI is a cross-platform, mobile web application emulation environment. From RIM. Could be something interesting.
Tips From Our Codebase To Help You Write Reliable Selenium Tests has nothing I don’t violently disagree with. And makes me think we should just add Implicit Waits to the Se Server and be done with it.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #55</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-55/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-55/</guid><description>Last week we released Se-IDE 1.1.0 which now features WebDriver formats and Se 2.1.0 was released about an hour ago. Simon will post something shortly-ish on what’s changed.
I haven’t messed around with HTML5 goodies yes, but fake-html5 seems like it could be interesting.
The Yii framework has grown WebDriver support. Now if only there were not two competing PHP implementations for them to have to choose from…
If you are using Python’s native packaging system to share your framework, then Lies, More Lies and Python Packaging Documentation on `package_data` could spare you some headache</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #54</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-54/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-54/</guid><description>Two Smatterings in two days?!!? That never happens. Well, except when I get behind and have a metric tonne of links queued up.
Next week appears to be Meetup week with ones in London on Tuesday, Toronto on Wednesday and San Francisco on Thursday. It’s like we coordinated or something. (But didn’t.) Last month’s SFSE meetup was on framework design. Here is the slides and the video.
Selenium Smells goes on a bit of a rant (and provides solutions) to people putting sleeps in their code instead of proper synchronization.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #53</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-53/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-53/</guid><description>Well, since the last Smattering there hasn’t been much in the community. Oh. Well, except for hitting the 2.0.0 milestone. Which seems like a good time to remind people that:
Selenium is the project name Selenium 1 is a project version Selenium 2 is a project version Selenium Remote Control (RC) is an API name Selenium WebDriver is an API name A person upgrades from Selenium 1 to Selenium 2 A person migrates from RC to WebDriver And with that soap boxing, here are some links for your consumption.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #52</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-52/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-52/</guid><description>Welcome to the Canada Day edition of the less-than-weekly-now collection of Selenium / Automation links that is the Smattering of Selenium.
Selenium Advanced User Interactions illustrates how this new API (which is part of WebDriver) can use used to do things like drag-and-drop on Canvas elements. Things you (probably) didn’t know about xargs is one of those things to keep tucked away in your toolbox. Especially if you find yourself having to shell out in your scripts.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #51</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-51/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-51/</guid><description>Two big releases last week&amp;hellip;
Selenium IDE 1.0.11 was released — with Firefox 4 support. Finally. And just in time for people to start agitating for Firefox 5 support. official announcement, unofficial announcement Selenium 2 RC1 (and RC2) were released which marks the first official release of the new in-server grid behaviour. Even if you are not using the WebDriver API or grid functionality, you should be updating your environment to this.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #50</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-50/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-50/</guid><description>Half a century!
And because I am late doing this, the Selenium Test Day for Addons.Mozilla.org — which is today! gets top billing. Its actually going on Right Now. Looking to practice script writing and/or up your profile? This is a great way.
And now for the usual stuff.
.NET Headless browser options looks at various options that might be available to you if you want something like HTMLUnit but for .</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #49</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-49/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-49/</guid><description>Here is the next 10 links as I play catch-up.
First up is the Selenium Conf videos. There are only seven up currently, but as they are processed they will be posted Silicon Valley Continuous Integration Summit, April 7, 2011 Virtual Hudson Build Environments – Part One, Part Two The second last paragraph of So you think you know automation? Part One is extremely important if you re doing automation. Which you likely are if you are reading this.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #48</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-48/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-48/</guid><description>It’s catch-up time again! Here is the first 10.
Automated tests for HTML5 offline web applications with Capybara and Selenium shows how a custom Firefox profile lets you automate Offline capabilities of HTML5 apps Robot Framework’s SeleniumLibrary 2.7 has been released primarily to pick up 2.0b3 of the Selenium Server. There was a series of posts about using Selenium with Drupal recently. Selenium testing in Drupal Run Selenium tests in Drupal on Debian headless Drupal Selenium tests API Using XPath Axes for locating elements in Selenium discusses some of the more advanced ways of finding elements via XPath I’ll follow that up with a link to the cssify project which will attempt to automatically convert XPath locators to CSS And since we’re now onto CSS… CSS Stress Testing and Performance Profiling discusses the stress-css bookmarklet.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #47</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-47/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-47/</guid><description>Nothing says ‘Hello Monday!’ like a batch of links and a wife with a kidney stone.
Eradicating Non-Determinism in Tests is a nice essay by Martin Fowler and applies to Se as Left uncontrolled, non-deterministic tests can completely destroy the value of an automated regression suite. Reminds us to disable automated updates on your remote machines. Selenium Simple Automation Infrastructure is a framework built on top of Selenium using Python to make writing scalable, data driven, functional web tests easier with code.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #46</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-46/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-46/</guid><description>Let’s put Selenium IDE on Firefox 4 is Available for Testing! Now! outside of the normal list. We have a ‘working’ version of Se-IDE for FF4, but don’t really have too too much faith in it (or at least I don’t). Please help test it.
Eight Techniques to Improve Your Tests is focused on unit tests, but I’m sure something can be gained from them Runners are great fun. How the play framework test runner works is therefor also great fun.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #45</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-45/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-45/</guid><description>A Smattering of Selenium #45
So of course by now everyone has seen Selenium 2.0b3: The Next Gen Browser Release and upgraded their rigs. Expect Selenium IDE at some point in the next week with support for FF4 — if you just. can’t. wait. then you could try the bleeding edge for yourself. Logging any bugs you find; of course.
Oh, and there is the whole Selenium Conference next week.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #44</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-44/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-44/</guid><description>What started out as the week of Capybara rounded itself out fairly nicely
I’m not a fan of using 3rd party abstraction layers (1st party are full win though) but Capybara has a large marketshare so Capybara (and Selenium) with RSpec &amp;amp; Rails 3: quick tutorial is likely going to be of interest to people.
And while on the subject of Capybara, here is a post on Checking Invisible Elements in it.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #43</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-43/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-43/</guid><description>The big thing in the new last week was ColdFusion. Yes, ColdFusion. I was amazed how much mention it got on Twitter. Introducing CFSelenium – A Native ColdFusion Client Library for Selenium-RC Export Selenium-IDE Scripts in CFSelenium (ColdFusion) Format GitHub repo CFSelenium and VirtualBox SeleniumCamp happened over the weekend and from the looks of things was a success. And had almost an even number of women as men — which is almost unheard of at these sorts of things.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #42</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-42/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-42/</guid><description>Is this week’s post the Answer to the Ultimate Question of Life, the Universe, and Everything Selenium?
Selenium 2 – Get Number of Rows in a Table illustrates what is advertised, though it feels like there has to be a shorter way to do this along the lines of getXpathCount() or getCssCount() Atlassian Plugin SDK – how to provide optional selenium tests explains how to wire up Se with the Atlassian toolkit and has a couple task specific tips as well.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #41</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-41/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-41/</guid><description>There isn’t an official announcement anywhere (yet) but Selenium 2.0b2 was released a couple hours ago. Time to upgrade all your servers. Beta 3 is going to focus on IE9 and FF4 support.
Meanwhile…
A Webinar on Automated Selenium Testing with Maestro 3 could be interesting if you are considering the Maestro platform. And sticking with the webinar idea, Sauce Labs is hosting Selenium 2 Webinar: The Next Generation of Web and Mobile Application Testing After a bit of stagnation, the official Python drivers are starting to get updated again.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #40</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-40/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-40/</guid><description>You would think by now that I wouldn’t be surprised by the number of links I collect in a week.
The big news last week is that we (Selenium) have successfully avoided the whole Hudson/Jenkins drama by joining the Software Freedom Conservancy. Se Announcement Conservancy Announcement Speaking of Hudson/Jenkins, here is how to upgrade a Hudson install to Jenkinss I don’t like a lot of the messaging of the whole ‘Lean Startup’ scene, but they have some things to steal though.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Joins the Software Freedom Conservancy</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-joins-the-software-freedom-conservancy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/selenium-joins-the-software-freedom-conservancy/</guid><description>It doesn’t seem that long ago that we announced on the mailing list that the Selenium project planned to join the Software Freedom Conservancy. I’m very pleased to announce that as of Friday, 21st January, our application was approved. We’re now under the aegis of the SFC.
From most people’s perspective, this won’t make much difference: you’ll still be able to view the documentation and download the latest versions of Selenium from Selenium HQ.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #39</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-39/</guid><description>Hey look! All caught up — only took a month…
My opinions on Continuous Deployment are pretty widely known, but the IMVU folks certainly have a lot of neat tricks to ‘borrow’. Such as Buildbot and Intermittent Tests Dealing with an API that returns XML? Your scripts don’t care about the readibility, but it helps you as the human if it is formatted pretty. xml formatter is a glorious time save in that case.</description></item><item><title>Bug Bash Aftermath</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/bug-bash-aftermath/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/bug-bash-aftermath/</guid><description>What a week! I’m almost (almost!) sorry that the Bug Bash is over. I’d like to say thank you to everyone involved in the Bug Bash, from those reporting issues, through those brave souls (Dharani, Anthony, Jari!) who went through the issue tracker, applied labels and made sure the issues were still fresh, all the way to those contributing fixes. And the top five bug fixers were?
Jari Bakken (24 issues) Simon Stewart (21 issues) David Burns, aka: AutomatedTester (11 issues) Jim Evans (10 issues) Michael Tamm (6 issues) Some interesting nuggets of information:</description></item><item><title>2.0b1 and Maven</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/2-0b1-and-maven/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/2-0b1-and-maven/</guid><description>If you’re using Maven and the 2.0b1 release of Selenium, you may be running into some problems getting maven to pick up your tests. The underlying problem is that selenium contains support classes for both JUnit and TestNG. The solution is to add this to your pom.xml
&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.seleniumhq.selenium&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;selenium&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;2.0b1&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;exclusions&amp;gt; &amp;lt;exclusion&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.testng&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;testng&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/exclusion&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/exclusions&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #38B</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-38b/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-38b/</guid><description>Will today be the day I finish three weeks of catch-up? Well, no..
UI Tests – putting it all together summarizes the series of posts using Watir and Cucumber, but the ideas could be converted to Se pretty easily.
I haven’t read it, but Essential Software Testdesign is now available for free [legitimately] as a pdf. Test Design is something I expect to see more discussion around in 2011 when it comes to Se automation.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #38A</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-38a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-38a/</guid><description>No. Really. I’m almost caught up.
Want input in a non-english language but don’t want to convert your whole machine? InputKing might be able to help. And the fact it is in a browser means we can use it via Se. HAR (HTTP Archive) is the format the cool kids are talking about, and now there is a har gem so you can make use of HAR files in you [Ruby] scripts.</description></item><item><title>Bug Bash: 24-30 January</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/bug-bash/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/bug-bash/</guid><description>When the Selenium (http://selenium.googlecode.com/) and WebDriver projects merged, all those moons ago, we moved the infrastructure from something we hosted to Google Code. One reason for doing this was to make it easier for people to file bugs and feature requests. And it looks like people have been filing a lot of bugs and feature requests.
In the run up for the 2.0b2 release, we’ll be running a Bug Bash. This will run from the 24th January all the way to the end of the 30th January.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #37B</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-37b/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-37b/</guid><description>Let’s see how many announcements there were that didn’t get pushed out in a timely manner today shall we?
Well, there is of course Selenium Conf is coming and you have until Friday to get your proposals in. Last I heard we had 37 which is impressive, but I think 50 should be doable. On the meetup side of things there is Boston on January 25 NYC on January 26 (its not on the site yet, but I’m speaking, so trust me, it exists) London on March 23 SeleniumCamp (English) is coming to Kiev at the end of February.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #37A</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-37a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-37a/</guid><description>My scheme for catching up with links last week ran afoul of 900 geeks and their families melting the internets at CodeMash 2.0.1.1. So let’s try it again this week.
Capturing screenshots on script failure is a common trick and Capturing Web Page Screenshots with Selenium 2 is the first post I have seen that explains how to do with with Selenium WebDriver XPath marks the spot uses a treasure map analogy around how to create good XPath — but at the same time propagates the ‘XPath is Inherently Evil’ myth.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #36B</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-36b/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-36b/</guid><description>Second in a week-long series of catch-up posts. But before I get to the next batch of links, don’t forget to submit your proposals to speak at the first Selenium Conference. I’m pretty sure we’re going to be trying to pick out the talks next week.
Can we please adopt this as the official poster for Selenium? Please? If you are a C# developer looking to get started with Selenium WebDriver, Automated Testing with Selenium 2 and NUnit seems like a good place to start Per the who ‘bringing order to the universe’, Watir-WebDriver: A detailed introduction shows how to drive Watir using Selenium WebDriver UI Automation: Tricks and Traps has, well, umm, tricks to try and traps to avoid.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #36A</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-36a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2011/a-smattering-of-selenium-36a/</guid><description>I have drastically fallen behind on the link reporting, but not the collecting, so this week’s Smattering will be multi-part.
The ‘big’ news falls for this edition is two fold –
We’re having a conference! Selenium Conference 2011 is April 4 – 6, 2011 in San Francisco. See the site for more information. (And I think our friends at Watir are going to be in the same space the day before.</description></item><item><title>Atoms have come to Selenium IDE</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/atoms-have-come-to-selenium-ide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/atoms-have-come-to-selenium-ide/</guid><description>As mentioned in Simon’s Going Atomic: Why? and Going Atomic: How, part of the merging of Selenium and WebDriver is to share common code between the two. And as of the 1.0.10 release of Selenium IDE, this merged code, ‘atoms’ is now included.
Some early users of this release are noticing that this the atom that drives assertAttribute and verifyAttribute is causing their scripts to break. This post explains the ‘why’ and suggests how to fix them as well.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #35</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-35/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-35/</guid><description>(If I wasn’t still recovering from a cold there would be something witty here.)
We’ll start this week with a cartoon So I know I have linked to playing pacman with se 2, but here is a site that explains the ghost behavior. If Google implemented the algorithms properly-ish, then this should be the ticket to crazy high scores. There should be a contest for this… Cucumber + Cuke4Duke + Selenium (WebDriver) = Enlightenment is step-by-step instructions for using maven to wire all these things together.</description></item><item><title>Selenium Conference Survey</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-conference-survey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-conference-survey/</guid><description>Great news! Thanks to the initiative of our friends at Sauce Labs, we’re finally ready to host the first-ever Selenium Conference. We’re still working out a lot of the details, but so far we’ve decided this first conference will be sometime in April and hosted in San Francisco.
In order to figure out the rest of the details, we’re looking for feedback from the Selenium user community. Please take a moment to fill out the following survey.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #34</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-34/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-34/</guid><description>We’ll start this week with the official announcement of ‘Selenium 1.0 Testing Tools: Beginner’s Guide’ being available. Congrats David! (Still waiting for my copy…)
There is now a DZone ‘refcard’ for Selenium 2. Of course, the reason Se2 is alpha is the API isn’t done with at least one major addition still left so it will be out of date in a month, but still… Here is another example of how to do Page Objects in Python Client-Side Profiling with Selenium 2 is David’s post about his recent London Selenium User Group talk Someone took the time to make a Selenium lens on Squidoo; which is going to get kinda circular once this post shows up on it.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #33</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-33/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-33/</guid><description>…and here’s the links!
Henrik Skupin was one of the speakers at the London Selenium Meetup and has written about the night and his talk Speaking of which, videos of the talks are now up Part of good automation is knowing how to code. So here are some sites that crossed my path this week for that Rails for Zombies Dive into HTML 5 HTML5 Rocks Cheezy continues his UI series which takes a detour over to WATIR land, but things are transferable.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #32</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-32/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-32/</guid><description>For those people paying attention to the goings-on in the Selenium world, yes, I am skipping something major until some of the details are worked out and announced. Until then, here are the links I accrued over the week.
Selenium uses Bamboo for its CI infrastructure. This week saw an upgrade to the latest version so if you want bleeding-edge code, get it here The only browser Se has no real traction on right now is the BlackBerry one.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #31</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-31/</guid><description>The big news for last week was that I released Se-IDE 1.0.8 to very little fanfare. 1.0.9 should be a week or two and much more important a release.
Cheesecake! is isn’t nearly as impractical as Pacman, but still adds to the Se2 example bucket. The London Se Meetup stuff from last week are starting to appear… Client-side profiling with Se2 a summary How Mozilla uses Se Crowd-sourced Automated Firefox UI Testing Some notes from CITCON last week as well.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #30</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-30/</guid><description>I’ve missed a couple weeks due to travel and a complete system lock which meant I lost all the links I had open but not saved. So these are the ones I have recovered.
I have written a series of posts on how to do parallel execution of tests in JUnit 4 up on the Sauce Labs blog. Part One, Part 2 and Part Three Quick start with FitNesse and Selenium is a beginners guide to wiring Selenium and FitNesse together.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #29</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-29/</guid><description>A fair number of links this week. The vast majority of which were buried in annoying airport internet advertising frames…
This looks like it is Spanish which would normally mean it doesn’t get included but it Integração Selenium e Testlink explains how to integrate Se with TestLink. We, as a community, need to document this sort of thing more. JUnit 4 Vs TestNG is a somewhat biased comparison between JUnit 4 and TestNG; but useful none the less.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #28</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-28/</guid><description>So we go from not-enough-stuff-to-do-one to wow-this-will-take-awhile. And we’re off..
Tellurium is one of the many frameworks that absorb Se and has an article on InfoQ called Introducing the Tellurium Automated Testing Framework which, well, introduces the framework. In the first of many Cucumber related posts this week is Sean Grove’s Cucumber Sauce for doing parallel Cucumber runs on the Sauce infrastructure. Might be general enough to use outside of it as well.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #27</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-27/</guid><description>Seems I skipped a week, but that’s okay since there hasn’t been much in terms of volume (or maybe my clever search filter is a bit overly clever…).
The big news I think is that there is now a Se driver for Node.js called Soda. I’m not sure I like the syntax, but I also don’t claim to know Node so it could be idiomatically correct which is more important than my blessing.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #26</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-26/</guid><description>It’s Labour Day here, so this post was written to backdrop of Sponge Bob. In case you were wondering.
selenium-java-evidence appears to be another logging framework, this time with an emphasis on auditability. Personally, the reports from a CI server should be all that are required, but to each their own… taza is an opinionated browser-based test framework webdry is a Python (jquery-inspired) wrapper for DRY:er access to the Selenium WebDriver Self-testing AppEngine apps with Saucelabs seems like a cool little (if very low level) trick to using Se inside AppEngine Sauce Labs released their Getting Started With Selenium guide and is looking for feedback on it Need to interact with a web service during a BrowserMob run?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #25</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-25/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-25/</guid><description>A day late, but that sort of thing happens when you have family.
I keep telling myself I will document how to incorporate Se launching and result recording in QC, but never seem to find the excuse. Looks like Aaron found the excuse: Finding the API for a DLL, Connecting to HP/Mercury Quality Center from a client side script Also from Aaron is a cool Credit Card Generator which has nice id tags which makes for easy Se parsing.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #24</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-24/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-24/</guid><description>A bit late, but I’m in California for a Selenium Developers Meetup and my body doesn’t quite know where it is temporally.
Don’t forget that tomorrow is the next meeting of the San Francisco Selenium folks which seems to be running a crowd sourced “Let’s stump Jason with our problems” session. Most of the ‘main’ Se folk will be there. Test design theory is something that I have yet to really see covered much, so here are three articles on the similar idea of what to test and what to skip.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #23</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-23/</guid><description>I was at Agile 2010 in Orlando last week so missed doing the Smattering, so here is two weeks worth of links.
There is crazy amounts of power hiding in that there JUnit 4 library – such as @Rule. One usage of them is described here. A useful pattern indeed when doing something like BDD or ATDD The next SFSE has been announced; August 24 at LinkedIn. Se creator Jason Huggins will be fielding questions in a Q&amp;amp;A session on steroids.</description></item><item><title>Selenium at Agile 2010</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-at-agile-2010/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-at-agile-2010/</guid><description>The Selenium project does not have an ‘official’ presence here at Agile as it is seen as a ‘test after’ tool rather than ‘test first’ — even though it provides the magic of the ‘test first’ frameworks… But there is a small, unofficial contingent of recognizable faces around that can help people out and some sessions on it.
Sessions
Why your selenium tests are so dang brittle, and what to do about it – Wednesday, August 11 – 3:30 – 5:00</description></item><item><title>Selenium 2.0 backend for running IDE test suite via the Se2 Firefox</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0-backend-for-running-ide-test-suite-via-the-se2-firefox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/selenium-2-0-backend-for-running-ide-test-suite-via-the-se2-firefox/</guid><description>The GSoC 2010, it’s a great adventure.
I’m Raynatou, I come from Burkina and do my internship at SERLI. Like all interns in this company the topic of my internship focuses on advanced topics like the integration of WebDriver as backend for Selenium IDE. Selenium IDE is currently built upon Selenium Core for interacting with web pages. Selenium Core has several major limitations, including the inability to fire native events. To avoid these limitations and produce more robust tests, I am investigating Selenium IDE to using WebDriver in place of Selenium Core.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #22</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-22/</guid><description>Happy Simcoe Day. Only a handful of links this week to mention.
Kevin relaunched Mogotest – see your website the way your users do. In a much earlier Smattering I think I linked to an announcement about a Se talk at Boston.rb. Well, here are the slides While not directly related to Se, the W3C has released their Unified Validator called, wait for it, Unicorn. So who is going to create the integration that magically sends pages to be validated there?</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #21</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-21/</guid><description>I thought it had been a slow week — until I looked at how many browser windows I had open. I wonder if that was why things were feeling a bit sluggish…
Some bits of history from Simon Stewart
First announcement of Selenium (outside of Thoughtworks) First announcement of WebDriver (again, outside of Thoughtworks) The ‘merger’ announcement (aka Selenium 2) More history lessons on Cloud Computing Show #35 where Jason recounts the origin of Se (and other stuff)</description></item><item><title>The Current Status of Selenium 1 and Selenium 2</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/the-current-status-of-selenium-1-and-selenium-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/the-current-status-of-selenium-1-and-selenium-2/</guid><description>In the beginning there was Se1, and it was good. But it could have been better — in ways that WebDriver was starting to be good at. Thus the brilliant idea was hatched to merge the two projects.
And then the confusion began. Let’s see if I can start to address some of it via a ficticious conversation that consolidates the Se-user list and #selenium irc channel.
There are a couple annoying bugs in Se-RC 1.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #20</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-20/</guid><description>12 hours late, but I was driving draft horses all day so that’s my excuse and I’m sticking with it. Enjoy. I’m going for a nap.
The big news this week was the next alpha of Se 2 came out. Time to update those automation machines. Like TestNG’s @BeforeClass and @AfterClass but using JUnit4? Using JUnit Nested Suites with Selenium RC to simulate TestNG suite and grouping annotations is a long titled post, but describes how to fake one out to act like the other.</description></item><item><title>GSoC 2010 – Remote Storage</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/gsoc-2010-remote-storage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/gsoc-2010-remote-storage/</guid><description>What’s new for Selenium this summer ? The GSoC of course !!!!
I’m Jérémy, a french engineer and I work at SERLI, a services company based in France.
I’m working on Selenium since a year and this summer I’m mentoring Aleksejs for the GSoC 2010. I’m helped by David Burns when I’m on vacation or offline. His experience is really useful to me, and David is involved on student supervising regularly.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #19</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-19/</guid><description>I’ve got a full day of driving ahead of me to go to a client so this is the early-morning (for me) edition of the Smattering post. That of course means there will be an absolute link explosion in about 20 minutes.
Dave talks about some of the stuff he is doing with Se-IDE in the post Improving Selenium IDE Another post on how to deal with file downloads in Se.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #18</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-18/</guid><description>Not too much this week with various holidays around the world, but still managed to dig some things up.
Sauce Labs has started a webinar series and recently had one on using Cucumber and OnDemand. Cucumber and Robot Framework like tools are the coming wave of testing tools. Another bit of Sauce-ish news is the folks at Rally put up a post on how to get Se 2 scripts in their OnDemand cloud If writing Se scripts is ‘programming’, then writing the controlling frameworks is real programming.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #17</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-17/</guid><description>Here are the posts dealing with Se, and/or automation in general that caught my eye and interest.
Selenium Unit Test Reuse illustrates one way of iterating through environments and browsers in a script without using Se-Grid. I’ve done similar tricks to this to some success — the problem is usually reporting though, but you are all clever folks so I’m sure you could add it in. Adding a custom header is sometimes required when writing a script, but its not really that documented so Kevin wrote How to Perform Basic Authentication in Selenium which combines how to do basic auth and header injection.</description></item><item><title>A Smattering of Selenium #16</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/a-smattering-of-selenium-16/</guid><description>I’m going to start posting the Smattering posts here on the main Selenium blog, hopefully each Monday. For past ones see my personal blog’s archive
Style Tests using Selenium and Robotframework – With those simple steps we are able to do regression testing on our user interfaces that have strict standards Export Selenium IDE scripts for Grails – A plugin which does exactly what the announcement says. Selenium XML Formatter – Hurray for plugins!</description></item><item><title>The Future of Selenium Grid</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/the-future-of-selenium-grid/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/the-future-of-selenium-grid/</guid><description>As you likely know by now, after years of stewardship Philippe has stepped down as maintainer of Selenium Grid and has named me the new maintainer. In this post, I hope to address the most immediate questions about what this means for the future of Selenium Grid.
Background I realize many of you may not know who I am. I’ve been using Selenium in some capacity for close to five years now.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the official Selenium blog!</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/welcome-to-the-official-selenium-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/blog/2010/welcome-to-the-official-selenium-blog/</guid><description>Since we moved away from Clearspace for our forums, it’s time we also did the same for our blogging platform. As such, the new location for the official Selenium blog will now be:
http://seleniumhq.wordpress.com
We hope to be much better about posting news, tips, and tricks here going forward.</description></item></channel></rss>