<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WebDriver on Documentação do Selenium</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/</link><description>Recent content in WebDriver on Documentação do Selenium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>2013-{year}</copyright><atom:link href="https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Entendendo os componentes</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/understanding_the_components/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/understanding_the_components/</guid><description>Page being translated from English to Brazilian Portuguese. Do you speak Brazilian Portuguese? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
Building a test suite using WebDriver will require you to understand and effectively use a number of different components. As with everything in software, different people use different terms for the same idea. Below is a breakdown of how terms are used in this description.</description></item><item><title>Requerimentos do driver</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/driver_requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/driver_requirements/</guid><description>Page being translated from English to Brazilian Portuguese. Do you speak Brazilian Portuguese? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
Through WebDriver, Selenium supports all major browsers on the market such as Chrom(ium), Firefox, Internet Explorer, Opera, and Safari. Where possible, WebDriver drives the browser using the browser&amp;rsquo;s built-in support for automation, although not all browsers have official support for remote control.
WebDriver&amp;rsquo;s aim is to emulate a real user&amp;rsquo;s interaction with the browser as closely as possible.</description></item><item><title>Manipulação do Browser</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/browser_manipulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/browser_manipulation/</guid><description>Page being translated from English to Brazilian Portuguese. Do you speak Brazilian Portuguese? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
Ruby Ruby is not installed by default on Windows. Download the latest version and run the installer. You can leave all settings at default values, except at the Installation Destination and Optional Tasks screen check where you need to check the Add Ruby executables to your PATH checkbox.</description></item><item><title>Esperas</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/waits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/waits/</guid><description>Page being translated from English to Brazilian Portuguese. Do you speak Brazilian Portuguese? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
WebDriver can generally be said to have a blocking API. Because it is an out-of-process library that instructs the browser what to do, and because the web platform has an intrinsically asynchronous nature, WebDriver does not track the active, real-time state of the DOM. This comes with some challenges that we will discuss here.</description></item><item><title>Classes de suporte</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/support_classes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/support_classes/</guid><description>As classes de suporte do WebDriver são fornecidas para simplificar a manutenção do seu código. Eles fornecem uma boa abstração para fazer a modelagem de elemento(s) HTML como objetos de domínio mais fáceis, também fornecendo métodos auxiliares para tornar o uso de tais objetos fácil de se pensar. Vamos aprender sobre:
Estratégias de localizador Eventos LoadableComponent ThreadGuard etc. Vamos começar:
ThreadGuard Esta classe está disponível apenas no Java Binding</description></item><item><title>Alertas, prompts e confirmações JavaScript</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/js_alerts_prompts_and_confirmations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/js_alerts_prompts_and_confirmations/</guid><description>Page being translated from English to Brazilian Portuguese. Do you speak Brazilian Portuguese? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
WebDriver provides an API for working with the three types of native popup messages offered by JavaScript. These popups are styled by the browser and offer limited customisation.
Alerts The simplest of these is referred to as an alert, which shows a custom message, and a single button which dismisses the alert, labelled in most browsers as OK.</description></item><item><title>Proxies Http</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/http_proxies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/http_proxies/</guid><description>Um servidor proxy atua como intermediário para solicitações entre um cliente e um servidor. De forma simples, o tráfego flui através do servidor proxy a caminho do endereço que você solicitou e de volta.
Um servidor proxy para scripts de automação com Selenium pode ser útil para:
Capturar o tráfego da rede Simular chamadas de back-end feitas pelo site Acessar o site necessário em uma rede complexa topologias ou restrições / políticas corporativas estritas.</description></item><item><title>Estratégia de carregamento de página</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/page_loading_strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/page_loading_strategy/</guid><description>Define a estratégia de carregamento de página da sessão atual. Por padrão, quando o Selenium WebDriver carrega uma página, segue a normal pageLoadStrategy. É sempre recomendado parar de baixar outros recursos (como imagens, css, js) quando o carregamento da página leva muito tempo.
A propriedade document.readyState de um documento descreve o estado de carregamento do documento atual. Por padrão, o WebDriver vai adiar a resposta a uma chamada para driver.get() (ou) driver.</description></item><item><title>Elemento Web</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/web_element/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/web_element/</guid><description>Page being translated from English to Brazilian Portuguese. Do you speak Brazilian Portuguese? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
WebElement represents a DOM element. WebElements can be found by searching from the document root using a WebDriver instance, or by searching under another WebElement.
WebDriver API provides built-in methods to find the WebElements which are based on different properties like ID, Name, Class, XPath, CSS Selectors, link Text, etc.</description></item><item><title>Teclado</title><link>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/keyboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/pt-br/webdriver/keyboard/</guid><description>Page being translated from English to Brazilian Portuguese. Do you speak Brazilian Portuguese? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
Keyboard represents a KeyBoard event. KeyBoard actions are performed by using low-level interface which allows us to provide virtualized device input to the web browser.
sendKeys The sendKeys types a key sequence in DOM element even if modifier key sequence is encountered. Here are the list of possible keystrokes that WebDriver Supports.</description></item></channel></rss>