<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paquetes de soporte on Documentación de Selenium</title>
    <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/support_packages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paquetes de soporte on Documentación de Selenium</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>2013-{year}</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/support_packages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trabajando con colores</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/support_packages/working_with_colours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/support_packages/working_with_colours/</guid>
      <description>En algunas ocasiones es posible que sea necesario querer validar el color de algo como parte de tus tests; el problema es que las definiciones de color en la web no son constantes. ¿No estaría bien que existiese una forma sencilla de comparar una representación de color HEX con una representación de color RGB, o una representación de color RGBA con una representación de color HSLA?
No te preocupes. Hay una solución para esto, la clase Color</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trabajando con elementos select</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/support_packages/working_with_select_elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/support_packages/working_with_select_elements/</guid>
      <description>Page being translated from English to Spanish. Do you speak Spanish? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
 Select elements can require quite a bit of boiler plate code to automate. To reduce this and make your tests cleaner, there is a Select class in the Selenium support package. To use it, you will need the following import statement:
Java Python C# Ruby JavaScript Kotlin import org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acciones del mouse en detalle</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/support_packages/mouse_and_keyboard_actions_in_detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/support_packages/mouse_and_keyboard_actions_in_detail/</guid>
      <description>Page being translated from English to Spanish. Do you speak Spanish? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
 Mouse represents a mouse event. Mouse actions are performed by using low-level interface which allows us to provide virtualized device input action to the web browser.
clickAndHold It will move to the element and clicks (without releasing) in the middle of the given element.
Java Python C# Ruby JavaScript Kotlin import org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with cookies</title>
      <link>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/support_packages/working_with_cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selenium.dev/documentation/es/support_packages/working_with_cookies/</guid>
      <description>Page being translated from English to Spanish. Do you speak Spanish? Help us to translate it by sending us pull requests!
 A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent from a website and stored in your computer. Cookies are mostly used to recognise the user and load the stored information.
WebDriver API provides a way to interact with cookies with built-in methods:
Add Cookie It is used to add a cookie to the current browsing context.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>